<Reports xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="NEH_Reports.xsd">
	<Report ID="44">
		<ApplicationNumber>PF-50028-10</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Resulting from an NEH funded review of art storage spaces in Old College and Mechanical Hall, this report provides recommendations for the most efficient use of spaces, and the best possible conditions for collections preservation.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Watson and Henry and Associates; Wendy Jessup and Associats</Author>
		<Date>08/26/2011</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Space Improvements Plan Report for University Museums at Old College and Mechanical Hall</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="78">
		<ApplicationNumber>PA-51545-06</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>On October 25 - 26, 2006, Walter Newman, Director of Paper Conservation at the Northeast Document Conservation Center and the author of this report, visited the New Hampshire State Library to examine the collection of maps and atlases. Janet Eklund, Administrator of Library Operations, guided the visit.&amp;#x0D; &amp;#x0D; The maps and atlases were identified as a priority during the preservation survey performed by Millie O'Connell in 2002–3. The purpose of the present survey was two-fold: 1) to examine all the maps and atlases and incorporate their condition into the database, assigning them a priority for conservation treatment, and 2) to make recommendations for measures that can be taken in-house to improve the preservation of the map and atlas collection as a whole. The data pertaining to the first goal were turned in at the conclusion of the visit. The latter goal depends heavily on improving storage conditions for these materials.  &amp;#x0D;  &amp;#x0D; </Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Walter Newman</Author>
		<Date>10/25/2006, 11/30/2008</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Historic Maps &amp;amp; Atlases Collection Assessment report, Collection Survey</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="79">
		<ApplicationNumber>PA-24333-02</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The building and collections of the State Library of New Hampshire (NHSL) in Concord, NH, were surveyed for preservation planning purposes by the writer of this report, Millie O'Connell, Preservation Consultant to Northeast Document Conservation Center (NEDCC) in Andover, MA.  Conducted on December 16 &amp;amp; 17, 2002, the survey was carried out with support from the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH).  While the primary focus of the survey was the special collections, much information in this report can also be applied to the remainder of the Library's research collections. &amp;#x0D; &amp;#x0D; The special collections of the NHSL contain a wealth of materials that document important people, places, and events in New Hampshire history, some of them unique, rare, or otherwise valuable.  They include historical State documents, NH imprints, archives and manuscripts, musical scores, medical and scientific studies, NH town and family histories, maps, photographs, and artwork.&amp;#x0D; </Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Millie O'Connell</Author>
		<Date>12/17/2002</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Preservation Survey Report for NH State Library</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="80">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-50766-10</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Ms. Wender spent four days in November 2010 examining approximately 550 monographs, pamphlets, and serials.  The goal of the survey was to assess the physical and chemical stability of bound materials in the collections and to make recommendations for the preservation and conservation of individual objects as well as for the bound collection as a whole.The volumes examined were selected from two discreet collections and included early New Hampshire imprints and volumes in the Library's Rare Book Collection.  Materials in the two collections were transferred to the Library from other collections, acquired by gift, or purchased.  The majority of volumes examined are monographs or pamphlets, but a few serials, government documents, a record book and several documents were examined as well.&amp;#x0D; &amp;#x0D; </Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Debra Wender</Author>
		<Date>02/04/2011</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Survey Report on pre-1830 bound imprints at the NH State Library</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="316">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-50928-10</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>On March 22-23, 2010, Lance Mayer and Gay Myers conducted a survey of the collection of paintings at the New London County Historical Society. They examined and wrote a separate report for every oil painting, including recommendations for conservation treatment and a prioritization of the conservation needs of each painting. Also included were estimates of the costs of treatments, valid for the year of the examinations. The principal work of the project has been providing the individual examination reports for each painting. However, the report also included brief generalizations about the condition of the collection as a whole and recommendations for storage and display.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Gay Myers, Lance Mayer, Lance Mayer and Gay Myers</Author>
		<Date>2010/04/30</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Report of Examination of Paintings at New London County Historical Society</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="445">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-50886-10</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This plan covers emergency and disaster preparedness situations and what library staff should do in the event of the varying types of situations.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Thomas F.R. Clareson </Author>
		<Date>11/07/2011</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Emergency and Disaster Preparedness Plan: Schmidt Library, York College of PA</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="561">
		<ApplicationNumber>GE-50288-10</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The Museum coordinated a stimulating, multi-perspective conversation among the national and regional scholars and staff to present the developing exhibition framework and facilitate discussions exploring the violations of civil liberties and injustices imposed upon Japanese Americans during World War II.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Patricia Wakida</Author>
		<Date>04/09/11</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Notes from the Regional and National Scholars Meeting</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="929">
		<ApplicationNumber>HD-50776-09</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Wrote about challenges faced during the period of NEH ODH grant.  More specifically, focused on the digital divide that makes it difficult for Native American communities to obtain grants in digital humanities and problems with broad band access in Indian Country.  Also wrote about need to raise consciousness concerning the lack of cultural diversity in digital humanities</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Timothy B. Powell</Author>
		<Date>4/1/2010</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>"The Digital Humanities Viewed From Indian Country" (White Paper for NEH ODH)</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="930">
		<ApplicationNumber>HD-50776-09</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A white paper for the NEH ODH recounting the activities during the grant period-- a conference at Minnesota Historical Society, dissemination of information, building partnerships between Penn Museum, American Philosophical Society, Minnesota Historical Society, White Earth Tribal and Community College, Leech Lake Tribal and Community College, Fond du Lac Tribal and Community College.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Timothy B. Powell</Author>
		<Date>4/1/2010</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://ojibwearchive.sas.upenn.edu/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Gibagadinamaagoom: An Ojibwe Digital Archive is a website edited by Timothy B. Powell that contains materials related to Ojibwe culture from Penn Museum, Minnesota Historical Society, American Philosophical Society, National Archives, videos of Ojibwe wisdom keepers, etc.  The site also has been developed with the assistance of 2 NEH HITCU grants awarded to White Earth Tribal and Community College and Leech Lake Tribal College.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>"Gibagadinamaagoom: An Ojibwe Digital Archive"</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="1560">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-50815-10</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report is a comprehensive assessment of the audio-visual collections currently held in Carnegie Hall's Archives.  The assessment isthe first step toward developing a plan for preserving this vital collection, which includes audio and video recordings of thousands of concerts that have taken place at Carnegie Hall, television broadcasts of performances, and master tapes of Carnegie Hall's music education programs.  Much of this collection is in danger of becoming unusable because of obsolete formats and unusable media.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>AudioVisual Preservation Solutions (AVPS)</Author>
		<Date>7/1/2010</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.avpreserve.com</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Website of AVPS, a consulting firm that provides resources needed by content caretakers to preserve, access, and distribute their audiovisual assets. </PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Carnegie Hall Audiovisual Collection Assessment and Recommendations</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19276">
		<ApplicationNumber>RZ-230579-15</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Preliminary report on the results of research conducted during the 2018 field season.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>B. D. Wescoat</Author>
		<Date>08/15/2018</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://samothrace.emory.edu/field-seasons/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>2018 Field Season</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19277">
		<ApplicationNumber>RZ-230579-15</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Preliminary report on research conducted during the 2017 field season.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>B. D. Wescoat</Author>
		<Date>08/15/2017</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://samothrace.emory.edu/field-seasons/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>2017 Field Season</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="1603">
		<ApplicationNumber>HD-51348-11</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>cited by the Horizon Project Navigator (in beta). It appears in the 2012 Horizon Report. It links to our project development blog. </Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Michelle Aubrecht</Author>
		<Date>2/26/2012</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://navigator.nmc.org/projects</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>This section of Navigator is the entryway to the extensive listings of vetted projects exploring uses of emerging technologies contained in the Horizon Project data set — easily the largest database of its kind in the world. Multiple avenues and tools are provided for searching — a sophisticated map interface, keywords, regions, technology, and much more. Multiple search terms are permitted, but keep in mind that the more search criteria used, the smaller the resultant set will be. To submit a new project to the data set, click on the Contribute Content link below.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>http://navigator.nmc.org/projects?filters=0%20+%20im cck field nav primary focus:494&amp;amp;search=</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Meet the Earthworks Builders, tagged with game-based learning, higher education sector</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Meet the Earthworks Builders</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="1689">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-51564-12</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This is a preservation assessment conducted of the building, storage room, and historical materials at Weber State University Stewart Library Special Collections and University Archives.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Randy Silverman</Author>
		<Date>02/01/2012</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://http://library.weber.edu/asc/speccoll/PreservationAssessment.cfm</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>This is the link to the preservation assessment.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Preservation Planning Study Weber State University</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="2075">
		<ApplicationNumber>HD-51128-10</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This thesis develops a framework for observing the evolution of various aspects of&amp;#x0D; human knowledge over time. The framework uses several editions of Encyclopedia Bri-&amp;#x0D; tannica, as well as Wikipedia, to build a database for human knowledge corresponding&amp;#x0D; to several time periods. The framework matches the same articles and topics across&amp;#x0D; the different time periods and ranks them using various NLP and network analysis&amp;#x0D; techniques. The data from Encyclopedia Britannica has been merged with Wikipedia&amp;#x0D; to form a Gravebook - a website allowing scholars to query certain topics or articles&amp;#x0D; and observe how the importance of the queried item evolved over time in terms of&amp;#x0D; importance and content.&amp;#x0D; </Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>A. Gabrovski</Author>
		<Date>05/23/2012</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Knowevo and Gravebook: Tracking the History of Knowledge</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="2160">
		<ApplicationNumber>LT-50065-09</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Pride and Passion Exhibit Report</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Janet Johnson, Chad Kahl</Author>
		<Date>05/12/2012</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://library.illinoisstate.edu/pride-passion/PridePassionFinalReport.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Pride and Passion Exhibit Report</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="2162">
		<ApplicationNumber>RZ-51147-10</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This is the first report about the rescue work at the small step pyramid south of Edfu.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Gregory Marouard, Hratch Papazian</Author>
		<Date>12/01/2011</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://oi.uchicago.edu/pdf/nn213.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>The Edfu Pyramid Project</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="2163">
		<ApplicationNumber>RZ-51147-10</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This is a preliminary report about the results of the 2010 season at Tell Edfu.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Nadine Moeller</Author>
		<Date>09/01/2011</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://oi.uchicago.edu/pdf/ar/11-20/10-11/10 11 Tell Edfu.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Tell Edfu 2010 Season</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="2316">
		<ApplicationNumber>RQ-50471-10</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>g</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Senior Essay, History Department, Yale University (unpublished)</AccessModel>
		<Author>Tatiana Schlossberg</Author>
		<Date>4/2/2012</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Escaping History: The Story of a Fugitive Slave, the Wampanoag Tribe of Gay Head (Aquinnah), and Becoming Free in Antebellum Massachusetts</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="2615">
		<ApplicationNumber>GI-50074-09</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report presents the findings from formative evaluation implemented in conjunction with an NEH-funded initiative at Historic Hudson Valley. This April-July 2011 evaluation project focused on two American Arcadia web program prototypes (while the additional eight were in development): Violetta Delafield and Sawkill Creek. With a fundamental desire to garner feedback from the intended audience, on topics ranging from navigability to content, the following goals were used:&amp;#x0D; &amp;#x0D; - Inform the preliminary design process through the participation of intended users&amp;#x0D; - Test program effectiveness in terms of navigability and ease of use&amp;#x0D; - Determine comprehension (not content, but level of repetition and connections)&amp;#x0D; - Assess the viability of the text and images&amp;#x0D; - Open a dialogue about user assumptions (that may guide this project, or future&amp;#x0D; implementation)&amp;#x0D; - Provide insight on overall satisfaction</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Catherine H. Harris</Author>
		<Date>08/01/2011</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>HHV - Montgomery Place American Arcadia - Formative Evaluation of Web Programs</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="2666">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-51767-12</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The report consists of four parts: Executive Summary, Institutional Profile, Observations List, and photograph pages.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Elisa L. Redman</Author>
		<Date>3/15/2012</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>General Preservation Needs Assessment Survey</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="2803">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-51585-12</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report is the result of an assessment of the storage needs at the Woodstock Artists Association &amp;amp; Museum (WAAM), one of the five museums in the Hudson Valley Visual Art Collections Consortium (Collections Consortium) by two conservators from the Natural Heritage Trust/New York State Office of Parks, Recreation and Historic Preservation's Bureau of Historic Sites/Peebles Island Resource Center (OPRHP) in July 2012. The goal of this assessment was to help WAAM improve current storage and further plans for its participation in a shared, regional collections storage facility and study center proposed by the Hudson Valley Visual Art Collections Consortium. This report gives recommendations for WAAM to help plan collections storage space in the proposed facility.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Conservators of the New York State Office of Parks, Recreation and Historic Preserv</Author>
		<Date>07/01/2013</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://origin.library.constantcontact.com/download/get/file/1101793785598-400/WAAM+Storage+Assessment+Report.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>AN ASSESSMENT OF COLLECTIONS STORAGE NEEDS FOR THE WOODSTOCK ARTISTS ASSOCIATION &amp;amp; MUSEUM</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="2833">
		<ApplicationNumber>RZ-51468-12</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Report about the conference to be published in the 'Bulletin de philosophie médiévale' of the SIEPM (http://www.siepm.uni-freiburg.de/index.php/about-siepm9/publications.html)</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>subscription only</AccessModel>
		<Author>Jack Zupko, Gyula Klima</Author>
		<Date>09/30/2013</Date>
		<ISBN>ISSN	0068-4023</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.siepm.uni-freiburg.de/index.php/about-siepm9/publications.html</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>SIEPM web site publications page</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>http://www.brepols.net/Pages/BrowseBySeries.aspx?TreeSeries=BPM</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Brepols Publishers' web site</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Conference Report</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="3045">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-51235-11</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The report provides the following: 1. a description of the size, location of Caramoor's &amp;#x0D; archival holdings and proposed Series  and Record Group Structure for the collection  &amp;#x0D; 2. a description of the current intellectual control of the Archives' collection and extant  &amp;#x0D; finding aids  3. information regarding the physical condition of the overall collection, &amp;#x0D; including storage of  material, environmental controls, and prospective shelving options &amp;#x0D; for the Theremin Collection  4. suggested policies regarding management of the collection  &amp;#x0D; 5. suggested budget for archival supplies  6. recommended funding sources for future management &amp;#x0D; of the collection</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>by request only</AccessModel>
		<Author>Winthrop + Germain</Author>
		<Date>09/01/2011</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Findings Report: Rosen House Archives</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19278">
		<ApplicationNumber>RZ-230579-15</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Preliminary report on research conducted during the 2016 field season.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>B. D. Wescoat</Author>
		<Date>08/15/2016</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://samothrace.emory.edu/field-seasons/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>2016 Field Season</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19311">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-266704-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report serves 3 purposes: 1) to document environmental conditions in archives and special collections storage spaces; 2) to analyze the data and determine the impact the conditions will have on the collections; 3) to provide recommendations for ongoing environmental monitoring and recommendations for improving the management of the spaces to promote better environmental conditions in the future.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Northeast Document Conservation Center</Author>
		<Date>12/10/2020</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Report of an Environmental Monitoring Consultation: Oakland University</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="3249">
		<ApplicationNumber>HK-50022-12</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>As more and more scholars experiment with building digital humanities (DH) resources, how are their host institutions approaching the challenge of supporting these diverse projects over time?&amp;#x0D; In this study, Ithaka S+R explores the different models colleges and universities have adopted to support DH outputs on their campuses.  This final report, Sustaining the Digital Humanities: Host-Institution Support beyond the Start-Up Phase, and the accompanying Sustainability Implementation Toolkit, are intended to guide faculty, campus administrators, librarians, and directors of support units as they seek solutions for their institutions.&amp;#x0D; </Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Both the report and toolkit are freely available on the Ithaka S+R website</AccessModel>
		<Author>Sarah Pickle, Nancy L. Maron</Author>
		<Date>06/18/2014</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.sr.ithaka.org/research-publications/sustaining-digital-humanities</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Landing page for Sustaining the Digital Humanities (final report and toolkit)</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>http://www.sr.ithaka.org/sites/default/files/SR Supporting Digital Humanities 20140618f.pdf</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>FINAL REPORT: Sustaining the Digital Humanities</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Sustaining the Digital Humanities: Host Institution Support beyond the Start-up Phase</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="3281">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-51478-13</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Interim and final reports on the work of the archivist during her four months of work, July-August 2013 and November-December 2013.  The reports describe the tools developed and form the basis for planning future projects.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>internal report</AccessModel>
		<Author>Diane Ryan, ARIT-American Board Project Archivist</Author>
		<Date>12/31/2013</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Archivist's Report</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="3587">
		<ApplicationNumber>GE-50679-12</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A primary purpose of the NEH planning grant was to evaluate the potential appeal of an exhibition exploring Chinese jade. We therefore engaged consultant Marcella Wells to organize focus groups in three cities, Kansas City, Salem, Mass, and San Francisco. This is the full report of her findings.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Marcella Hughes</Author>
		<Date>9/30/2013</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>GE-50679-12 Front End Evaluation Report for Chinese Jade Exhibition</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="3701">
		<ApplicationNumber>PF-50265-12</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Installation of new web-based HVAC management, monitoring and control system to improve collection environment and save energy received an award from the Greater Philadelphia Chapter of the Association of Energy Engineers .</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Lois Olcott Price</Author>
		<Date>3/19/2015</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Award to Winterthur's Sustainable Preservation Environment project</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="3708">
		<ApplicationNumber>HC-50011-12</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Envisioning the Future of Computational Media begins by describing a rapidly-growing interdisciplinary research field: computational media. This field brings together people knowledgeable about the arts, the humanities, and the sciences -- particularly computer science, but also the social sciences -- to pursue questions that could only arise, and only be answered, through interdisciplinary research.&amp;#x0D; &amp;#x0D; Envisioning the Future of Computational Media then goes on to describe some of the remarkable opportunities and persistent challenges that face the field. The opportunities include ongoing growth of economic and cultural impact, powerful approaches for addressing national priorities, and the potential for establishing new centers for education and research. The challenges include the need for basic and applied interdisciplinary research, the need for more interdisciplinary practitioners and greater diversity, the need for deeper, more accessible collections of computational media artifacts, and others.&amp;#x0D; &amp;#x0D; In order to seize the opportunities, and address the accompanying challenges, Envisioning the Future of Computational Media describes 12 field-shaping recommendations, with concrete examples of potential interventions. These recommendations -- along with the field description, opportunities, and challenges -- are synthesized from a national convening of diverse field experts, along with more than a year of follow-up conversation and research (made possible by the National Science Foundation, the National Endowment for the Humanities, the National Endowment for the Arts, Microsoft Studios, and Microsoft Research).&amp;#x0D; </Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Noah Wardrip-Fruin, Michael Mateas</Author>
		<Date>3/21/2014</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://mediasystems.soe.ucsc.edu/report</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Media Systems project site</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>http://www.escholarship.org/uc/item/9z95w96h</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>University of California digital repository</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Envisioning the Future of Computational Media: The Final Report of the Media Systems Project</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="4243">
		<ApplicationNumber>ED-50387-13</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The language interests of students in US colleges and universities are continuing&amp;#x0D; to diversify, according to a comprehensive new report, Enrollments in Languages Other Than English in United States Institutions of Higher Education, Fall 2013, released by the Modern Language Association of America (MLA). While total enrollments in languages other than English decreased since the MLA's last survey in 2009, several languages saw increasing enrollments, and particularly growth in enrollments in advanced language classes.&amp;#x0D; The MLA report is the longest-running comprehensive analysis of the study of languages other than English at US colleges and universities; this is the twenty-third survey in the series. The report includes undergraduate and graduate course enrollments in languages other than English in fall 2013 for 2,616 AA-, BA-, MA-, and PhD-granting colleges and universities in the United States. Partial funding for the report came from the National Endowment for the Humanities and the National Security Educational Program.&amp;#x0D; Total language enrollments on US college campuses decreased by 6.7% between 2009 and 2013. But some languages—Korean, American Sign Language (ASL), Portuguese, and Chinese—showed higher enrollments. The sharpest percentage increase was in Korean enrollments, which rose at every institutional level between 2009 and 2013: 27.6% in two-year institutions, 45.3% in four-year institutions, and 86.6% in graduate programs. This growth in 2013 follows increases of 18.2% between 2006 and 2009 and 37.1% between 2002 and 2006. American Sign Language continued to experience strong growth, showing an increase of 19.0% in total enrollments, and was the language with the third most enrollments, displacing German, now fourth. Also up were enrollments in Portuguese (10.1%) and Chinese (2.0%).</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>David Goldberg, Dennis Looney, and Natalia Lusin</Author>
		<Date>02/28/2015</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.mla.org/enrollments surveys</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>2013 Survey of Enrollments in Languages Other Than English</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="4298">
		<ApplicationNumber>HT-50067-12</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A participant's final presentation given July 26, 2013 at Early Modern Digital Agendas, a summer research institute funded by NEH at the Folger Institute in Washington, D.C. These final reports were given after three weeks of high-level discussion centering on digital aspects of early modern scholarship. There was also a steady stream of tweets throughout the institute; reading through these gives a good sense of the depth of discussion and sense of community (as evidenced by the continued use of the hashtag!).</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Robin Camille Davis</Author>
		<Date>7/26/2013</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.robincamille.com/presentations/emda/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Seeing: final report for EMDA </Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19934">
		<ApplicationNumber>ZR-256732-17</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A Beyond the Beat project where Musicology students participating in Spy Hop's year long music program examined their lyrics through a humanities lens.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open</AccessModel>
		<Author>Carey Campbell</Author>
		<Date>07/24/19</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://weberstate.app.box.com/s/ej10ypp1631xkwu0sv48na0p674nuf45/file/496403775999</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Sincerely, the Universe - Liner Notes</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="4413">
		<ApplicationNumber>HD-50995-10</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>In spring 2010, the Philadelphia Department of Records (DOR), an Azavea client, was awarded an NEH Digital Humanities Start-Up Grant to research the use of mobile augmented reality technology in displaying a large database of historic photographs.  They partnered with Azavea to conduct the research and create a prototype smartphone application (iPhone and Android) that enables users to view historic images as overlays on the current landscape.  In creating the application, we drew from the huge collection of nearly 93,000 images available on PhillyHistory.org, a previous project we created with DOR.  But how to actually make it happen? We approached application development with many questions. Is augmented reality (AR) a useful method for showing the history of Philadelphia and helping users to see the connections between the past and the present? Is AR technology advanced enough to make this type of application possible? Are smartphone networks fast enough?  Is the phone able to pinpoint a user's location accurately enough to load images of that location even in a crowded urban setting? For the answers to these questions and many more, check out our research results in our "Implementing Mobile Augmented reality Technology for Viewing Historic Images" white paper.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Deborah Boyer and Andrew Thompson</Author>
		<Date>04/01/10</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.azavea.com/research/company-research/augmented-reality/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Augmented Reality for Cultural Institutions (whitepaper) - </Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="4419">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-52257-14</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Through a Preservation Assistance for Smaller Institutions grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities, conservator Linda Nieuwenhuizen conducted several site visits and performed extensive research. Her resulting 52-page report identifies outstanding conservation issues in the collection and the current collection storage/display and provides the basis for a long-term plan for collection care.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>upon request</AccessModel>
		<Author>Linda Nieuwenhuizen</Author>
		<Date>11/10/14</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>William Paterson University Galleries Conservation Condition Assessment</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="4545">
		<ApplicationNumber>RQ-50470-10</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>In September 2014, we asked four users (one Dartmouth undergraduate student, one recent Dartmouth graduate, and two researchers working in the field and in digital humanities) to evaluate the website. Peter Carini (co-PI) and John Cocklin of the Library Assessment Committee developed the assessment questions after polling the Occom Project Team Membership for ideas. The assessment focused heavily on the database side of the site since the text side of the site had not been developed out sufficiently to assess at the time the questions were devised. The full report is in the Appendix, with my comments.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>included in appendix</AccessModel>
		<Author>Peter Carini</Author>
		<Date>9/29/14</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Occom Circle Assessment Report</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="5004">
		<ApplicationNumber>RZ-51154-10</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Excavations at Wingo's began as part of a larger study of slavery at Poplar Forest, a late 18th-century piedmont Virginia plantation. Archaeological excavations at Poplar Forest preceded the Wingo's project includes work at the Quarter and North Hill quarters; within and around a standing brick house that served as a late antebellum slave quarter; and within a group of dependencies associated with the early 19th-century mansion built for Thomas Jefferson's retirement. Additional excavations southeast of the mansion in areas known as Sites A and B have subsequently provided additional information about slavery on the property.   Work at Wingo's began with small-scale testing in 2000 and 2001. From 2007 to 2012, more intensive research was undertaken at the site, with funding from the National Foundation for the Humanities from 2010 to 2012. Research focused on the creation and maintenance of domestic spaces by the enslaved; practices relating to foodways; and the ways in which enslaved people engaged with the informal and formal consumer economies. In order to address the materiality of slavery, the research team adopted a multi-scalar approach that captured information useful for reconstructing macro-features such as yards, more limited features such as subfloor pits, and the micro-scale evidence of burned seeds, wood charcoal, small faunal remains, and artifacts vital for addressing foodways and economic practices. This report presents a detailed summary and interpretations of research findings. </Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Barbara J. Heath, Eleanor E. Breen, Andrew Wilkins, Crystal Ptacek</Author>
		<Date>12/30/2015</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://web.utk.edu/~bheath2/#</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Archaeological Excavations at Wingos Quarter (44BE0298) Forest, Virginia. Results from the 2000-2012 Seasons</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="5290">
		<ApplicationNumber>RA-228502-15</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The first report's objective is to&amp;#x0D; monitor the presence of social&amp;#x0D; sciences in the different academic&amp;#x0D; and public spheres in the Arab world.&amp;#x0D; This includes universities, research&amp;#x0D; centers, scholarly and cultural&amp;#x0D; periodicals, civil society, and public&amp;#x0D; media. Therefore, the report presents&amp;#x0D; a general survey of the presence of&amp;#x0D; social sciences and evaluates the&amp;#x0D; abilities and characteristics of their&amp;#x0D; disciplines in the region, with an eye&amp;#x0D; to the significant transformations Arab societies have lately witnessed.&amp;#x0D; &amp;#x0D; The report aims to serve as both&amp;#x0D; a practical and theoretical tool for&amp;#x0D; parties interested in the support of&amp;#x0D; social sciences and their development&amp;#x0D; in the Arab world, including social&amp;#x0D; science scholars, officials from&amp;#x0D; research centers, universities, nongovernmental&amp;#x0D; organizations (NGOs),&amp;#x0D; sponsors of social research and&amp;#x0D; development, and all intellectual and&amp;#x0D; cultural actors interested in the role&amp;#x0D; of the social sciences in the public&amp;#x0D; domain.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Mohammed Bamyeh</Author>
		<Date>01/01/2015</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.theacss.org/uploads/English-ASSR-2016.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>The Arab Social Science Monitor</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Social Sciences in the Arab World  Forms of Presence 2015</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="9937">
		<ApplicationNumber>ED-50367-11</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The "Humanities at the Crossroads" project, funded in part by the National Endowment for the Humanities, has attracted national attention, although not in the conventional ways, such as articles, books, interviews, and the like.  The core of the project focused on a detailed mapping of the "ecology" of the humanities in the state of Indiana.  This work was carried out by Indiana Humanities, the state humanities council in that state.  The report and the brochure on this project have been widely disseminated to the state and territorial humanities councils, all of which receive significant funding from NEH.  The Indiana Humanities initiative has also been discussed at the National Humanities Conference, an annual event organized and sponsored by the Federation of State Humanities Councils.  Presently, explorations are under way, with encouragement from the Kettering Foundation, to extend the life of "Humanities at the Crossroads" through support of humanities mapping, similar to what was done in Indiana, in a variety of states and under the auspices of state councils.  The payoff from "Humanities at the Crossroads" is turning out to be a clearer picture of how and where the humanities are actually practiced in the states.  Among other things, these studies explore how work done in college and university humanities programs can be linked to the "public humanities" in mutually advantageous ways.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>John K. Roth, Elizabeth Lynn, Keira Amstutz</Author>
		<Date>5/5/2015</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://indianahumanities.org/programs/humanities-at-the-crossroads</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Indiana Humanities</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Humanities at the Crossroads Update and Indiana Case Study Executive Summary Brochure</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="10558">
		<ApplicationNumber>RZ-51674-14</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Unpublished report submitted to the Montserrat National Trust</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>C. Lorin Brace VI, John F. Cherry, Krysta Ryzewski</Author>
		<Date>06/18/2015</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Report on the Excavations of Potato Hill, May-June 2015</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="11909">
		<ApplicationNumber>CH-50656-09</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>University Library Self Study and Plans for the Future</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>web</AccessModel>
		<Author>Ruth Kifer</Author>
		<Date>12/1/2013</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://library.sjsu.edu/files/documents/ULB-sjsu 5y review-2008-2013.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>University Library Self-Study, 2008-2013</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="12026">
		<ApplicationNumber>PJ-50116-13</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A professor from the Central Connecticut State University math department, with a special data mining project, used newspapers digitized by us to demonstrate methods, alerting other researchers to the rich data trove available in Chronicling America.  He recently provided a summary of his results to CDNP.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Roger Bilisoly</Author>
		<Date>03/22/2017</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://ctdigitalnewspaperproject.org/2017/03/ccsu-professor-uses-digitized-newspapers-for-data-mining-research/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Connecticut Digital Newspaper Project website</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>"Text Mining WWI-era Connecticut Newspaper Stories with Graph Theory and Beyond"</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="13408">
		<ApplicationNumber>HAA-256368-17</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>With the increase in the dynamic nature of the web, often the content of a web page grows, changes, and might be shrunk. And with these pages being archived numerous times, they serve as the digital history for those changes that are long gone from the live page. But visualizing over these numerous different archived copies, or mementos, with the intention of perceiving the major changes over time is nearly impossible, as the memento count can be very high. In case of cnn.com, the web page has been archived 188,966? ?times?. This TimeMap summarization tool referenced throughout this paper as ‘tmvis', facilitates visualization of these changes by analyzing all mementos in a TimeMap and picking the most unique mementos, which best describe the major changes in a webpage. A web service with a user friendly interface and command line tools are also provided for this tool.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Maheedhar Gunnam</Author>
		<Date>05/04/2018</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.cs.odu.edu/~mweigle/papers/gunnam-ms-proj-18.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Masters' Project report, Old Dominion University, May 2018</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>How I Changed Over Time: A webservice to summarize TimeMaps based on SimHashed HTML content</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="13676">
		<ApplicationNumber>ZZ-253123-16</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Written to help guide applicants to NEH Next Generation Humanities PhD grants, as well as any campus team interested in pursuing the goals of the Next Gen program. Part I, Lessons Learned, summarizes the common features of Next Gen projects and outlines some of the challenges and promising solutions employed by grantee universities in pursuit of the larger goals of the grant program. Part II, Emerging Strategies, offers suggestions for additional considerations that might be included in the design of Next Gen programs. Please note that Promising Practices does not constitute evaluation criteria for the selection of 2018 grantees; rather, this document is intended to help institutions understand what practices have been most successful for past grantees, and identify ideas and approaches that are appropriate to their campuses.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Maureen Terese McCarthy</Author>
		<Date>09/01/2017</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://cgsnet.org/publication-pdf/5049/NEH NextGen LessonsLearned.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>PDF of the report</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>https://cgsnet.org/promising-practices-humanities-phd-professional-development-lessons-learned-2016-2017-next</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Page on the CGS website linking to the report PDF.</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Promising Practices in Humanities PhD Professional Development: Lessons Learned from the 2016-2017 Next Generation Humanities PhD Consortium</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="13677">
		<ApplicationNumber>ZZ-253123-16</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A review of the reform efforts and scholarship relevant to humanities professional development. This report will be useful to any campus team interested in pursuing the goals of the Next Gen program and any researcher interested in the history of this work.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Maureen Terese McCarthy</Author>
		<Date>09/01/2017</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://cgsnet.org/ckfinder/userfiles/files/NEH NextGen PriorWork.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>PDF of report</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Review of Prior Work in Humanities PhD Professional Development</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="13678">
		<ApplicationNumber>ZZ-253123-16</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Written to help guide applicants to NEH Next Generation Humanities PhD grants to clarify NEH's Third Party Match guidelines.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Council of Graduate Schools</Author>
		<Date>09/01/2017</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://cgsnet.org/ckfinder/userfiles/files/NEH NextGen ThirdPartyMatch.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>PDF of report</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Clarifying NEH guidelines for Third-Party Match of grant funds</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="13736">
		<ApplicationNumber>RZ-51748-14</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>n/a</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>n/a</AccessModel>
		<Author>VanValkenburgh, Parker, Torres Mora, Rocio</Author>
		<Date>3/1/2015</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Excavaciones en el Sitio de Carrizales (LA-057), Temporada 2014 (Informe Técnico)</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="13737">
		<ApplicationNumber>RZ-51748-14</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>n/a</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>n/a</AccessModel>
		<Author>VanValkenburgh, Parker, Zevallos Castañeda, Daniela</Author>
		<Date>3/1/2016</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Excavaciones en el Sitio de Carrizales (LA-057), Temporada 2015 (Informe Técnico). Ministerio Nacional de Cultura (Peru).</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="13738">
		<ApplicationNumber>RZ-51748-14</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>n/a</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>n/a</AccessModel>
		<Author>VanValkenburgh, Parker, Zevallos Castañeda, Daniela</Author>
		<Date>3/1/2017</Date>
		<ISBN>2017</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Proyecto Arqueológico Zaña Colonial, Trabajos de Laboratorio 2016 (Informe Técnico). Ministerio Nacional de Cultura (Peru).</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="14694">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-258298-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Final performance report for the NEH Preservation Assistance Grant.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>PDF File (Upon request)</AccessModel>
		<Author>Shikoh Shiraiwa, Nicole Willard</Author>
		<Date>04/01/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>UCO Melton Legacy Collection: Assessment of Conservation Treatment Needs</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="14727">
		<ApplicationNumber>HAA-256218-17</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report in both English and Turkish summarizes work at Kerkenes in 2016 and 2017.  It includes on pages 13-15 a brief summary of the initial vision for the collaborative DATCH Project.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Available for free download and limited print copies</AccessModel>
		<Author>Scott Branting, Joseph W. Lehner, Sevil Baltali-Tirpan, Dominique Langis-Barsetti, Tuna Kalayci, Yasemin Özarslan, Nilüfer Yöney, Burak Asiliskender, John M. Marston, Sarah R. Graff, Lucas Proctor, Noël Siver, Soran Avcil, Tomasz Wazny, Canan Çakirlar Oddens</Author>
		<Date>7/15/2018</Date>
		<ISBN>ISSN:1302-0749</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://sciences.ucf.edu/anthropology/kerkenes/wp-content/uploads/sites/20/2018/11/KerkNews2016-2017.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Kerkenes News 2016-2017 – Kerkenes Haberler 2016-2017</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="14964">
		<ApplicationNumber>GW-259383-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report delivered to Citizen Film from WTTW Chicago contains American Creed's PBS broadcast information including an executive summary, station relations, audience research, presenting station services, notable press coverage, ratings, and carriage data.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Available between project partners</AccessModel>
		<Author>WTTW Chicago</Author>
		<Date>01/24/19</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.dropbox.com/s/yj8bzd7vjykaht9/American%20Creed%20Wrap%20Up%20Report.pdf?dl=0</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>This URL is a dropbox download link to a .pdf file of the report.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>American Creed Community Conversation Wrap Up Report</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="15131">
		<ApplicationNumber>AKB-260426-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This PittWire article published by University of Pittsburgh Communications publicizes the "Water in Central Eurasia" project among Pitt faculty and students.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open Access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Katie Fike</Author>
		<Date>08/31/2018</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://https://www.pittwire.pitt.edu/news/new-academic-programs-take-worldly-view</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>New Academic Programs Take a Worldly View</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="15201">
		<ApplicationNumber>RZ-255635-17</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>From June 9-July 12 2018, the Epipalaeolithic Foragers of Azraq Project (EFAP), University of California, Berkeley and University of Tulsa, conducted excavations at the Epipalaeolithic site of Kharaneh IV. The 2018 excavation at Kharaneh IV is the seventh field season at the site, focused on exploring the nature of prehistoric (Late Pleistocene) occupation of Kharaneh IV. During this season we completed excavation on an Early Epipalaeolithic hut structure (Structure 2) discovered in the 2010 season. The goal of the 2018 excavation season was to fully excavate Structure 2 to understand the distribution of artifacts with the structure and the relationship between the structure and the surrounding deposits. This year's excavations have prepared us for targeting specific new areas for work, namely continuing to excavate several hut features during future field seasons.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Subscription Only</AccessModel>
		<Author>Danielle A. Macdonald, Lisa A. Maher</Author>
		<Date>7/30/2018</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>2018 Excavations at the Epipalaeolithic Site of Kharaneh IV</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="15267">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-263521-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Detailed documentation of conservation of Ned Kahn's Wind House project.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Rowan Geiger</Author>
		<Date>6.11.2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Preservation Arts - Treatment Report</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="15290">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-258399-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The report is a general preservation assessment of the object collection at the Medford Historical Society and Museum. It includes analysis and recommendations regarding inventory, security, and the care and condition of artifacts. Recommendations include environmental (temperature and humidity), pest identification and control, housekeeping, proper storage, control of dust and dirt pollution, preparation for a major building renovation project, mold remediation, control of light levels, and cost-conscious rehousing of artifacts.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>This document is for internal use only.</AccessModel>
		<Author>Helene Gillette-Woodard</Author>
		<Date>12/4/2018</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Preservation Assesement of the Object Collection at the Medford Historical Society and Museum LAB #OB-2659</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="15329">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-258399-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report addressed Organizational Issues, Collection Management and Preservation Planning, the Building and Environment, Collection Storage and Handling, Conservation, Digitization, Exhibition Practices, and Preparation for Building Renovation. The report also provided a summary of recommendations, a methodology ("Implementation Matrix") for prioritizing activities, and a comprehensive list of additional resources.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>This document is for internal use only.</AccessModel>
		<Author>Sean Ferguson</Author>
		<Date>12/14/18</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Report of a Preservation Needs Assessment</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="15462">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-263563-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report presents observations of the present environmental conditions of the collections at the Sargent House Museum and provides recommendations for climate control improvements for these collections housed within the building.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>The report is on a Google Team drive and individuals can ask for access to it.  The report is also attached in this Progress Report.</AccessModel>
		<Author>Ernest Conrad</Author>
		<Date>6/3/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://drive.google.com/open?id=1HMzCha4fStBfHzhvamvN7iFnBtbFtubyXaH0wmLJFRA</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>A Google doc file.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>ENVIRONMENTAL ASSESSMENT of THE SARGENT HOUSE MUSEUM GLOUCESTER, MA</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="15515">
		<ApplicationNumber>MD-263786-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The Appalachian Trail is the United States' most iconic long-distance hiking trail, but its history is not widely known by the people who use it. All the Appalachian Trails is an interactive website that explicates the Appalachian Trail's nearly 100-year history through an investigation of the changes in the trail's route over time. Using historical maps and primary sources, users will be able to see different trail routes and discover a more complex understanding of the history of the trail and the ways in which the trail informs the larger history of the 20th-century United States. Users will be able to follow links from a large interactive map to primary sources, to digital exhibits about topics of interest to hikers and trail workers, to scholarly essays about the AT's place in the history of the United States. The website is intended for a broad public audience, especially people with a personal connection to the trail, either through hiking or maintaining the trail.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Submitted to NEH</AccessModel>
		<Author>Mills Kelly, Abigail Mullen</Author>
		<Date>05/31/19</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>All the Appalachian Trails Design Document</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="15613">
		<ApplicationNumber>FA-252317-17</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Since 2011 I have been documenting and researching rural singing in oral trad ition in the bi-national island of Timor.1  I have worked mainly with two ethnolinguistic groups:  the Southern Tetun,2 who live (a) in the southern mountains (foho) and south coastal plain (fehan) in Kabupaten Malaka on the Indonesian side of the international border, and (b) and in the adjacent Munisipiu Covalima on the Timor-Leste side;  and the Fataluku, who live at the far eastern tip of the island, in Munisipiu Lautem.   In their singing, both groups use complex, unwritten systems for incorporating pre-existing poems into a repertoire of melodies that are independent of the poems.  (That is, the poems are not fixed to specific melodies.)  The Fataluku poems are called vaihoho, while a common term for the Tetun poems is kananuk (also knananuk and aiknanuk).  Vaihoho and kananuk have different metrical structures, and the systems for setting them to melodies are different in detail, though similar in principle. These singing traditions are practiced now only by the elderly, and they are likely to die out in the next decades.  My ethnomusicological aim is first of all to document them in recordings while documentation is still possible.  But beyond that it is to comprehend the traditions as formal structures and as systems of knowledge and practice.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Philip Yampolsky</Author>
		<Date>03/20/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Vaihoho and kananuk: the metrical structure of two forms of sung poetry from the island of Timor [unpublished report submitted to the PARADISEC Archive of the Sydney Conservatorium of Music</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="15736">
		<ApplicationNumber>AV-260657-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This is the final project report for War and Healing: A Century of Veterans' Reintegration, a National Endowment for the Humanities-funded reading and discussion program for veterans, which took place in Miami, Florida in 2018-2019. It provides information about how the program was executed, as well as a summary of "lessons learned." It is intended to be of use to humanists aiming to oversee partnerships with veterans' organizations and local arts/cultural organizations. We provide an overview of War and Healing, including its structure and goals, as well as a description of the organizations and individuals who oversaw and supported it. We also provide information about program "outcomes" based on surveys with facilitators and participants. The Conclusion offers takeaway points regarding the implementation of humanities-focused and collaborative educational programs.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Jessica L. Adler, Brahim Almarales</Author>
		<Date>09/15/19</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://historyofhealth.fiu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/WarHealingFinalRptFINAL3.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Humanities-Based Programming for Veterans:  Report on a University-Community Partnership</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="15932">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-258335-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Final report of Preservation Needs Assessment undertaken by the Northeast Document Conservation Center for University Archives &amp;amp; Special Collections, Joseph P. Healey Library, University of Massachusetts Boston.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Sean Ferguson</Author>
		<Date>01/09/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://blogs.umb.edu/archives/files/2019/09/uasc-preservation-assessment-final-20190110.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Report of a Preservation Needs Assessment: University Archives &amp;amp; Special Collections, Joseph P. Healey Library, University of Massachusetts Boston</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="15987">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-258370-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The report is based on the assessment of paper-based, audiovisual, and photographic materials housed at South Dakota State University Hilton M. Briggs Library Archives &amp;amp; Special Collections were for preservation planning purposes by Becky Geller and Frances Harrell, Preservation Specialists for the Northeast Document Conservation Center (NEDCC) in Andover, MA on June 27th, 2018. The assessment evaluated the buildings and environments as they relate to the preservation needs of the materials; examined current policies, storage, and handling procedures; and assessed the general condition of materials. Observations and recommendations are based on a pre-site visit questionnaire, a full-day site visit, and discussions with Michele Christian, Archivist and Special Collections Librarian.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>The report is available for viewing in the South Dakota State University Archives and Special Collections reading room in the Hilton M. Briggs Library.</AccessModel>
		<Author>Geller, Becky, Harrell, Fraces</Author>
		<Date>12/10/2018</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Report of a Preservation Needs Assessment.</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="15988">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-258370-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The Preservation Plan is based upon implementation of recommendations from the Report of a Preservation Needs Assessment done by Becky Geller and Frances Harrell, Preservation Specialists for the Northeast Document Conservation Center (NEDCC) in Andover, MA on June 27th, 2018. The plan includes that outlines steps and timelines for implementing the recommendations from the assessment. The plan addresses the pressing matters of controlling temperature and humidity, preserving audiovisual materials and digital files, and creation of policies and procedures that are in line with standard preservation practices. The plan also focuses on storage needs of fragile materials, such as large buffalo robes, rare books, and oversized documents. The plan will direct the preservation activities of the A&amp;amp;SC for the next five years and will result improved care of South Dakota State University's historical materials.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>The plan is available for viewing in the South Dakota State University Archives and Special Collections reading room in the Hilton M. Briggs Library.</AccessModel>
		<Author>Christian, Michele</Author>
		<Date>6/25/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>South Dakota State University Archives and Special Collections Preservation Plan.</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="16002">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-263555-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report confirmed the medium and technique of each print in the Fairfield University Art Museum's James Reed Print Collection.The report stated the condition of each print, advised on how each work should be stored, recommended conservation treatment if necessary, and identified a few works whose condition is so poor, that conservation is contraindicated, and deaccessioning is the most prudent course.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>for internal use only</AccessModel>
		<Author>Sarah Dove</Author>
		<Date>3/18/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>NEH Condition Survey Report: James Reed Print Collection, Fairfield University Art Museum.</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="16115">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-263487-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This is a 25 page report from the NEDCC that discusses the current state as well as future steps to take with OSV's collections regarding mold.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Internal only (currently)</AccessModel>
		<Author>Ann Marie Willer</Author>
		<Date>3/25/19</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>NEDCC Consultation Report</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="16118">
		<ApplicationNumber>ZZ-258560-17</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Report on Years One and Two Outcomes of the Native Language Immersion Initiative project.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open Access</AccessModel>
		<Author>First Nations Development Institute</Author>
		<Date>10/01/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.firstnations.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/NLII-report-Oct-2019-for-web.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>PDF Version of "Native Language Immersion Initiative: These are our Stories".</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Native Language Immersion Initiative: These are our Stories</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="16120">
		<ApplicationNumber>AV-260657-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This is the final project report for War and Healing: A Century of Veterans' Reintegration, a National Endowment for the Humanities-funded reading and discussion program for veterans, which took place in Miami, Florida in 2018-2019. It provides information about how the program was executed, as well as a summary of "lessons learned." It is intended to be of use to humanists aiming to oversee partnerships with veterans' organizations and local arts/cultural organizations. We provide an overview of War and Healing, including its structure and goals, as well as a description of the organizations and individuals who oversaw and supported it. We also provide information about program "outcomes" based on surveys with facilitators and participants. The Conclusion offers takeaway points regarding the implementation of humanities- focused and collaborative educational programs.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Jessica L. Adler, Brahim Almarales</Author>
		<Date>10/30/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://historyofhealth.fiu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/WarHealingFinalRptFINAL3.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Humanities-Based Programming for Veterans: Report on a University-Community Partnership</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="16487">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-263398-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The NEH PAG project goals were to hire a consultant to conduct a preservation needs assessment of the local history and archives collection to: 1. Assess existing ESPL archival collections 2. Create a preservation plan that includes planning priorities and access to the collection, and 3. Trains ESPL and members of the Eastern Shore of Virginia (ESVA) Museum Network to learn best practices for care and handling of materials.  A report was generated as a result of a one-day workshop and study by the consultant resulting in many near-term recommendations to move forward with collections care at the current library. However, from the consultant's perspective, the move to a new facility in Parksley will be absolutely critical for the long-term care and preservation and access of the collections.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Leigh A. Grinstead, LYRASIS, 1438 W. Peachtree Street NW, Atlantic GA 30309</Author>
		<Date>06/27/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Eastern Shore Public Library Preservation Site Reort</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="16526">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-258343-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Northeast Document Conservation Center (NEDCC) provided a detailed preservation needs assessment for the Knoxville Jewish Archives, based on a site visit, outlining strengths and weaknesses in areas of a) collection management and preservation planning, b) building and environment, c) collections storage and handling, and d) conservation, reformatting, and exhibition of the Archives' holdings.  The report provided information on best practices in these areas, and recommended actions to be taken to preserve this cultural heritage, broken into short-, medium- and long-term priorities.  Appendices included an implementation matrix, resources for additional information and contact information for vendors, and a sample five-year preservation plan.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>N/A</AccessModel>
		<Author>Danielle Spalenka, Preservation Specialist for the Northeast Document Conservation Center</Author>
		<Date>10/10/2018</Date>
		<ISBN>N/A</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>N/A</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>N/A</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>N/A</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>N/A</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Report of a Preservation Needs Assessment</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="16544">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-258550-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The Jewish Historical Society of North Jersey received a grant from the National Endowment of the Humanities for a Preservation Grant for Smaller Institutions. The society commissioned Dyani Feige of the Conservation Center for Arts and Artifacts. Ms. Feige traveled from the Philadelphia headquarters to our location to examine the collection in May 2018. She submitted a report several months later. The 59 page report offers a thorough evaluation of our collection and housing and also made recommendations for necessary projects in the future.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Dyani Feige of the Conservation Center for Arts and Artifacts</Author>
		<Date>05/19/2018</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Jewish Historical Society of North Jersey Needs Assessment Report</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="16592">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-259060-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The Treasury of Lives revised Guidelines &amp;amp; Style Sheet describes the standards required for biographical essays that are published on the resource. Intended primarily for contributing authors, these expanded guidelines provide detail on formatting, style, content, sources, licensing, workflow and change management.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open Access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Alexander Gardner, Tenzin Dickyi, Catherine Tsuji</Author>
		<Date>10/31/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://treasuryoflives.org/uploads/standards documents/226e0-Treasury-of-Lives-Guidelines-&amp;amp;-Style-Sheet.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Active link to PDF file of Guidelines &amp;amp; Style Sheet is accessible from the RESOURCES page (easy navigation from RESOURCES on main menu).</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Treasury of Lives Guidelines &amp;amp; Style Sheet</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="16593">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-259060-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The expanded and revised Treasury of Lives Phonetic Principles and Transliteration document provides information on the system used to transliterate Tibetan words. A chard of equivalents and examples and exceptions are provided, along with explanatory text.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open Access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Alexander Gardner</Author>
		<Date>10/31/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://treasuryoflives.org/uploads/standards documents/4abb8-Treasury-of-Lives-Phonetics.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>The Treasury of Live Phonetic Principles document is accessible from the RESOURCES page (easy navigation from RESOURCE menu item on all site pages.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>The Treasury of Lives Phonetic Principles</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="16611">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-253708-17</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Additional documents related to the final financial report.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Tax forms/financial summary</AccessModel>
		<Author>Price, Rachel</Author>
		<Date>01/31/2020</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B xJ6wFnokiYMlBNT1NmMUV4ZExZcTZqcDBrX20yWFBXNFI0</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Link to document in MIPoPS Google Drive.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B xJ6wFnokiYTWRXSnFoUlNRVS1PQmtjMnVVVXVrMy1KVXdr</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Link to document in MIPoPS Google Drive.</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Final Financial Report (appendices)</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="16644">
		<ApplicationNumber>PR-253384-17</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The PBCore Handbook compiles most of the documentation about PBCore available on this website into a downloadable PDF format. Because the documentation covers many topics, we've provided separate downloadable files for each section, as well as a fully compiled version.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open Access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Rebecca Fraimow</Author>
		<Date>10/30/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://pbcore.org/handbook</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>PBCore Handbook</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="16972">
		<ApplicationNumber>PY-263763-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report documents the original workflow process developed by the Lakeland Digital Archive Team to organize and staff public community digitization events. It describes the five work stations for the event--intake station, imaging stations, accession interview and metadata intake station, post-processing station, and exit and rehousing station. The document also includes scripts for intake and accession interviews and diagrams to capture the workflow processes.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Subscription only at present</AccessModel>
		<Author>Katrina Fenlon, Trevor Munoz, Stephanie Sapienza, Mary Corbin Sies</Author>
		<Date>10/20/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Lakeland Common Heritage Digitization Event Workflow</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="17053">
		<ApplicationNumber>RA-50103-11</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Review appeared in ASAP J, the open-access platform of ASAP Journal, on January 8, 2019.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Jennifer M.S. Stager</Author>
		<Date>01/08/19</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://asapjournal.com/asli-cavusoglu-the-place-of-stone-jennifer-stager/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>This URL leads directly to the review on the ASAP J website.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Review of Asli Çavusoglu: The Place of Stone exhibition, New Museum, New York</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="17115">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-259002-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This thesis analyzes the formation of early English colonial trade networks through an examination of three Plymouth Colony sites. Although Plymouth Colony has been studied extensively by both historians and archaeologists, materials from the original settlement have only recently been identified by University of Massachusetts, Boston archaeologists at Burial Hill in downtown Plymouth, Massachusetts. This thesis compares the 17th-century ceramics from Burial Hill (1620-c. 1660) to two homesteads established later by Plymouth colonists, the Alden First Home Site and the Allerton/Prence/Cushman Site. A minimum number of vessels (MNV) was established for each site and the country of origin was established for each vessel to determine the origin of consumer goods, specifically ceramics, in Plymouth Colony. These vessels were then divided up into "English" and "foreign" categories, and a chi-square analysis was conducted to determine whether the composition of ceramics was significantly different at Burial Hill than at the later two sites.   By comparing a site that likely pre-dates the implementation of most of the Navigation Acts (1651, 1660) to two sites that continue decades after their passage, it is possible to determine whether there was a significant effect on Plymouth's trade. The results of this analysis demonstrate that the difference between Burial Hill, the Alden First Home Site, and the Allerton/Prence/Cushman Site with respect to proportions of English to Foreign vessels is not statistically significant. This suggests that the percentage of foreign vessels did not significantly change over time. In addition, there were more English and foreign ware types found at the later sites than at Burial Hill. Combined with documentary evidence, this indicates that the Plymouth colonists were skirting regulations and establishing their own personal and intercolonial trade networks, even as the English government tried to limit them.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open Access MA thesis</AccessModel>
		<Author>Elizabeth G. Tarulis</Author>
		<Date>4/30/2020</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.umb.edu/library</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>UMass Boston library</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>“WE MAY HAVE PROFITABLE COMMERCE AND TRADE TOGETHER”: AN ANALYSIS OF 17TH-CENTURY CERAMICS IN PLYMOUTH COLONY</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="17140">
		<ApplicationNumber>HAA-256368-17</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>We report on the development of TMVis, a web service to provide visualizations of how individual webpages have changed over time. We leverage past research on summarizing collections of webpages with thumbnail-sized screenshots and on choosing a small number of representative past archived webpages from a large collection. We offer four visualizations: image grid, image slider, timeline, and animated GIF. Embed codes for the image grid and image slider can be produced to include these on separate webpages. The animated GIF can be downloaded as an image file for the same purpose. This tool can be used to allow scholars from various disciplines, as well as the general public, to explore the temporal nature of web archives. We hope that these visualizations will just be the beginning and will provide a starting point for others to expand these types of offerings for users of web archives.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Michele C. Weigle, Abigail Mabe, Dhruv Patel, Maheedhar Gunnam, Surbhi Shankar, Mat Kelly, Sawood Alam, Michael L. Nelson</Author>
		<Date>06/02/2020</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://arxiv.org/abs/2006.02487</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>ArXiv tech report</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Visualizing Webpage Changes Over Time</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="17147">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-263532-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The Preservation Assessment of Ninepipes Museum of Early Montana intended to build the museum's capacity to care for its collections, thereby preserving history the local Confederated Salish, Kootenai and Pend d'Orielle Tribal Nations and many other Native Nations and peoples represented in the collection. This illuminates relationships among all cultures in the region and a chapter in United States and Tribal Nation history. This also solidifies the museum's mission to conserve the history and cultures of what is now the State of Montana. The recommendations from this report stem directly from site visits conducted in the spring of 2019. The report outlines a long-range prevention conservation plan.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Organization's Website, public access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Pat Roath</Author>
		<Date>10/17/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.ninepipesmuseum.org/news/neh-collections-needs-assessment/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Link to final report document on Ninepipes Museum of Early Montana website. Collection Needs Assessment.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Collections Needs Assessment for the Ninepipes Museum of Early Montana</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="17257">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-266645-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This Museum Storage Assessment (MSA) was developed by museum consultant Donald Cumberland under Purchase Order 47694 issued by the Fauquier County Parks and Recreation Department (FCPRD). Funding for the assessment was provided by a Preservation Assistance Grant for Smaller Institutions by The National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH). Museum consultant Donald Cumberland visited two collection storage sites in Fauquier County, Virginia on January 21, 2020 in coordination with Park Manager/Curator Todd Bonshire of the Gold Mining Camp Museum at Monroe Park. The site visits were for the purpose of discussing with staff (Todd Bonshire and Artifact Inventory Project Manager Jeanne Brunk) collection storage objectives, examining department collections, and evaluating current collection storage spaces and conditions.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Print and By Request</AccessModel>
		<Author>Donald Cumberland</Author>
		<Date>06/30/2020</Date>
		<ISBN>N/A</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Fauquier County Parks and Recreation Department Museum Storage Assessment</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="17318">
		<ApplicationNumber>RA-264490-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Forest degradation contributes to ecological and climate instability, foreclosing all possibilities for mitigation. At the same time, forest resources such as timber, metal, and land for agricultural production are vital for economic development. In Cambodia, economic development stalled while the country and region suffered war for over thirty years from the late 1960s through the late 1990s. Instituting democracy in Cambodia restarted the wheels of economic development as sanctions lifted, making space for national and international investments to exploit Cambodia's resources(World Bank 1993; World Bank 1992; World Bank, UNDP, and FAO 1996). Since that time, the impact on resources in Cambodia has been profound and forest loss is among the most visible. In Cambodia's Ministry of Environment(MoE) captured nearly one million hectares of  viable forest land in an effort to slow forest loss and improve forest governance. The Prey Lang  Wildlife Sanctuary (PLWS) is the largest of these and involved a jurisdictional shift of forest management authority from Cambodia's Forest Administration.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>S. Sien, Courtney Work</Author>
		<Date>04/25/18</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.academia.edu/37282747/REPORT-Prey Lang Comanagement- ENG.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>The report is available on academia.edu

The report was originally prepared for the Ministry of the Environment, Kingdom of Cambodia.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Prey Lang: Traditions, Development, and Climate Change in the Context of Collaborative Management</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="17373">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-259115-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Scholar assessment for New Paltz Historic Documents Project. See Supplemental materials for actual report.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Firth H. Fabend, David W. Voorhees</Author>
		<Date>12/28/2018</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Scholar Assessment - New Paltz Historic Documents Project</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="17374">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-259115-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>See supplemental materials for the actual report</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Conservation Center for Art and Historic Artifacts</Author>
		<Date>07/15/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Item-Level Condition Survey</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="17375">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-259115-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>See supplemental materials for actual plan.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Conservation Center for Art and Historic Artifacts</Author>
		<Date>07/15/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Digitization Plan</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="17439">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-259094-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Project Manager Craig Breaden led a pilot project to test methodologies for creating instances of the Radio Haiti Archive on YouTube and the Internet Archive, to further extend the reach of the Archive to people in Haiti and to user groups -- particularly those of the Haitian/Caribbean diaspora -- not optimally served by research library repositories due to differences in digital infrastructure and online cultures.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Breaden, Craig</Author>
		<Date>9/25/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://blogs.library.duke.edu/rubenstein/2019/09/25/radio-haiti-on-youtube-an-archive-in-the-world/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Radio Haiti on YouTube? An Archive in the World</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Voices of Change II: Report on Pilot</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="17444">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-259094-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>In 2019-2020, Duke Libraries' Assessment &amp;amp; Data Visualization Analyst, Angela Zoss, with support from Naomi L. Nelson, Principal Investigator and Project Director, and Craig Breaden, Project Manager, developed a Tableau-based analysis tool for evaluating both the YouTube/Internet Archive pilot project and use of the Radio Haiti Archive at large.  The near-term goal of the "Radio Haiti Dashboard" was to provide detailed views of when and where, and on what platform, users were viewing specific resources in the Archive.  In the longer term, the goal is to gain a more nuanced understanding of how we might effectively bring Library resources to non-academic audiences, by comparing resource use on secondary platforms, like YouTube or the Internet Archive, with resource use via the Duke Digital Repository. See Appendix 2 for a static image of the dashboard.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Developed for internal use.  We hope to share it more broadly in the future.</AccessModel>
		<Author>Breaden, Craig, Zoss, Angela</Author>
		<Date>7/15/2020</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Radio Haiti Pilot Dashboard</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="17527">
		<ApplicationNumber>HAA-266568-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This white paper discusses the challenges inherent in offering access to a legacy online community archive, and discusses possible approaches, including emulation and visualization.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Dragan Espenschied,, Lyndsey Moulds, Michael Connor</Author>
		<Date>8/1/2020</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://thingbbs.rhizome.org/static/NEH%20Early%20Online%20Communities%20in%20Context.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>The white paper for this project is hosted on the project website for Rhizome’s restoration of The Thing BBS.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>The Thing BBS Message Archive: An Early Online Community in Context</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="17567">
		<ApplicationNumber>RZ-230366-15</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The management of lithic raw materials is a significant concern to anthropological archaeologists interested in hunter-gatherer socio-economies. A wide range of studies have implicated quarry distance, work needs, occupational longevity, and consumer population to variation in tactics for reduction, use, and maintenance of chipped stone tools. Fewer studies have examined socio-political factors in the organization of stone tool technology. This study examines the interactive effects of population, occupational longevity, favored prey, and socio-political complexity on the tactics by which lithic raw materials were managed in a long-lived winter pithouse in North America's interior Pacific Northwest. Results of bivariate and multivariate analyses implicate variability in toolstone economies as related to different classes of lithic items. Lithic cores and flake tools were more extensively reduced in contexts of productive subsistence economies, high populations, long winter occupations, and material wealth-based inequality. Bifaces were produced and maintained in relation to needs associated with intensity of deer hunting. The creation and maintenance of slate tools was affected at least in part by the intensity of salmon fishing. Combined, these data suggest that the organization of lithic tool technology responded to multiple factors across the lifespan of the house.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Anna Marie Prentiss, Thomas A. Foor, Ethan Ryan, Ashley Hampton, Matthew J. walsh</Author>
		<Date>8/17/2020</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>file:///C:/Users/lmedici/Downloads/BR%20HP54%20JASR%20Sept%202020.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Journal of Archaeological Science: Reports</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>A multivariate perspective on lithic technological organization at Housepit 54, Bridge River Site (EeRl4), British Columbia</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="17596">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-263471-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This is the final report and analysis of activities conducted as part of Environmental Monitoring of University Archives and Special Collections, a project funded by a Preservation Assistance Grant from the National Endowment of the Humanities (PG-263471-19). This grant was awarded to support the first evercsystematic environmental monitoring of the UASC spaces. This report includes a summary of the collected data, analysis of the data, and potential future activities to be undertaken as a result of the grant activities and the data collected.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Adam Strohm</Author>
		<Date>07/31/2020</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://hdl.handle.net/10560/islandora:1009829</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Link to the metadata record and download links for the report in Illinois Tech's institutional repository.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Environmental Monitoring of University Archives and Special Collections: Final Report and Analysis</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="18016">
		<ApplicationNumber>MT-263824-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Museums have lacked the tools and scales, even a vocabulary, for measuring immersion, presence, and empathy and how and whether those elements contribute to learning outcomes. HG&amp;amp;Co and the Chicago00 team examined how these digital projects advance the Chicago History Museum's goals, and how to measure both cognitive and affective outcomes of these intense emerging experiences in order to develop more substantive and memorable encounters with history through this experimental digital platform.  The team interviewed and surveyed hundreds of participants, and developed a novel Experience Evaluation Rubric (EER) to examine, in depth, how individuals experience immersion and presence within AR and VR environments. VR and AR is at heart a spatial technology, the viewer feels like they are in physical spaces, or in the case of AR, that computer generated content is in real space with them.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Kate Haley Goldman, Leslie Henry Kadish</Author>
		<Date>04/13/2020</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://chicago00.org/Chicago00 OurProcess October 2020.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Evaluative report for the Chicago History Museum's VR experience of the first Ferris Wheel at the World's Columbian Exposition in 1893. Includes an Experience Evaluation Rubric, a tool that can be used by any museum engaged in VR.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Chicago 00 Ferris Wheel Final Evaluation Report and VR/AR Experience Evaluation Rubric</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="18144">
		<ApplicationNumber>AH-275540-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report reviews several regular and AP U.S. History textbooks, analyzes their contributions and errors, and provides a window into the general operations of American history textbooks.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open Access</AccessModel>
		<Author>David Randall, Bruce P. Frohnen, Jason C. Ross, Kevin R.C. Gutzman, William Pettinger</Author>
		<Date>12/1/2020</Date>
		<ISBN>9780965314381</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.nas.org/storage/app/media/New%20Documents/History%20Textbooks.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Online PDF of the report</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>History Instructional Materials and Support</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="18643">
		<ApplicationNumber>AV-265985-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Ka Ho?ea Mai Ana program evaluation</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Stephen Fox</Author>
		<Date>3-31-2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://https://drive.google.com/file/d/1DfIZFZgeh4dFQyAD M4StuQrfUHeBVfr/view?usp=sharing</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL>http://https://drive.google.com/file/d/1txV9BaHwERtLQzvjU3kyw3 S6N2YLsZB/view?usp=sharing</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Preparatory &amp;amp; Program Survey</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Ka Ho?ea Mai Ana program evaluation</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="18703">
		<ApplicationNumber>ZH-258494-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report presents results from a study of Investigating Where We Live (IWWL), conducted by RK&amp;amp;A, Inc. for the National Building Museum (NBM). IWWL is a long-running program that has brought together creative youth from across the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area every summer since 1996 to explore, document, and interpret the local built environment. For this study, RK&amp;amp;A conducted telephone interviews with participants who all have different relationships to the program, both internal and external, to hear a variety of perspectives on the program and its evolution over time. Specifically, RK&amp;amp;A interviewed youth who participated in the program in either summer 2018 or in the previous 3-5 years, NBM staff who have been either directly or indirectly involved in the program, outside stakeholders, and museum peers working in youth programs at other institutions. The purpose of the study is to examine the strengths and challenges related to the program so NBM can use the results to strategically plan for the program's future.   The following summary identifies key findings and presents and discusses trends across participant types. We hope that the information contained herein will help NBM in its decision making regarding the future of the IWWL program.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Internal report</AccessModel>
		<Author>RK&amp;amp;A</Author>
		<Date>12/1/2018</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>This report is attached as an appendix to the National Building Museum's final performance report.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Program Evaluation: Investigating Where We Live</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="18727">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-263619-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The attached document is the progress final report with the need's assessments and recommendation prepared by the contracted 'Archive and Library Educational and Professional Consultant' to incorporate in the institutional Emergency Plan.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>PREPARED BY: DORILYN MORALES COLÓN, BBA MIS | Librarian of the MAPR Research Center, REPORT PREPARED WITH THE NEEDS ASSESSMENT RESULTS FROM:  Karin O. Cardona de Jesús | Archive and Lib</Author>
		<Date>04/30/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Performance Final Report for the development of a long-term preservation plan</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="18854">
		<ApplicationNumber>HAA-269051-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Needs assessment report based on the feedback of FromThePage collection owners.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Joshua Ortiz Baco, Albert A. Palacios, Allyssa Guzman</Author>
		<Date>9/15/20</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://hdl.handle.net/2152/82841</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Report deposited in Texas ScholarWorks, UT Libraries' institutional repository</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>FromThePage Collection Owner User Study Report</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="18882">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-266728-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Travellers Rest Historic House Museum was selected as a grant awardee from the National Endowment for the Humanities in August 2019.  The site was one of 215 awardees from across the country who received grant funds.  The site used these funds specifically for the purpose of monitoring the environmental conditions of the historic house which houses the majority of the collection comprised of Southern and Tennessee artifacts such as furniture, paintings, textiles, decorative homewares, and personal items which belonged to the original owner, Judge John Overton. and his descendants.  Landmark Facilities Group, Inc., of Norwalk, Connecticut, was contracted by the site to complete a preservation assessment of the site's mechanical systems along with installing data loggers to monitor the temperature/humidity levels every 15 minutes.  This project was carried out from November 2019 through early November 2020 in order to document the temperature and humidity levels in the historic house for one full year.  The final preservation assessment was received in January 2021 and provides information to the Board of Directors and staff on best recommendations on how to proceed with proper conservation measures regarding the historic house HVAC system and other related mechanical and environmental measures needed to be undertaken as outlined in the site's 2020-2025 Strategic Plan.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Not applicable</AccessModel>
		<Author>Landmark Facilities Group, Inc.</Author>
		<Date>11/1/2019</Date>
		<ISBN>Not applicable</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>Not applicable</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Not applicable</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>Not applicable</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Not applicable</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Existing Conditions Assessment of Historic Travellers Rest</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19024">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-271637-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Report of a Preservation Needs Assessment - Review of the Town of Concord Archives and recommendations for actions related to preservation and preservation planning.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Becky Geller (NEDCC)</Author>
		<Date>2/8/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Report of a Preservation Needs Assessment</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19075">
		<ApplicationNumber>SO-263616-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The On Wisdom and Vision: Humanities Organizations in Illinois during COVID-19 report tells about 177 humanities organizations from across the state that have kept their doors open through the pandemic and supported their communities through a time of isolation, political upheaval, racial injustice, and economic uncertainty.  This Report looks at the community of organizations supported by $710,000 Illinois Humanities COVID-19 Emergency Relief Grants funded by the federal CARES Act and explores – through data and interviews – the ways in which organizations found ways to keep their doors "open," despite extensive financial and audience loss. In the midst of the pandemic, they conducted work on racial inequity, provided powerful programs and essential support in struggling communities, and demonstrated their resilience.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open Access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Lyon, Gabrielle, Hallett, Mark, Yoo, Jenn</Author>
		<Date>3/10/21</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.ilhumanities.org/app/uploads/2021/03/Illinois-Humanities-COVID-19-CARES-Act-Emergency-Relief-Grants-Report 20210310.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>On Wisdom and Vision: Humanities Organizations in Illinois during COVID-19 PDF</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>On Wisdom and Vision: Humanities Organization in Illinois during COVID-19</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19275">
		<ApplicationNumber>RZ-230579-15</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Preliminary report on the research conducted during the 2019 field season.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>B. D. Wescoat</Author>
		<Date>08/15/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://samothrace.emory.edu/2019-field-season/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>2019 Field Season</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19330">
		<ApplicationNumber>PF-266724-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The collections of the Frank Lloyd Wright Foundation at Taliesin West include fine and decorative art from Europe, Asia, and Central America, textiles and clothing, historic furnishings designed by Wright, books, articles and ephemera by and about Wright, oral histories, and photographs, film, video and audio tapes. Most of the collections are centrally stored in the Archives and Collections Buildings and while safe, are in overcrowded conditions. For lack of space, however, some of the pieces are stored in locations at higher risk than are unsuitable for preservation purposes.  Created by a Preventive Conservation Conservator and an Architect/Engineer in collaboration with FLWF Collections &amp;amp; Preservation staff, the Collections Storage Improvement Plan makes recommendations for organizing and optimizing the space needed for storage; addressing special environmental needs for the collections; and improving interior environments and energy use through building envelope and systems upgrades. In addition the 150-page report provides detailed plans for the relocation and consolidation of media, including high-efficiency floor plans and storage furniture.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Free access to FLWF staff and outside researchers through the FLWF Collections Department. Also available to NEH staff and SCHC applicants through NEH channels.</AccessModel>
		<Author>Michael C. Henry, Wendy Claire Jessup</Author>
		<Date>12/23/2020</Date>
		<ISBN>n/a</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>n/a</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Taliesin West Collections Storage Improvements Plan</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19462">
		<ApplicationNumber>HT-267259-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Per the grant requirement, this is the public facing white paper that describes the institute's origins and goals, project overview and activities, and reflections and possible follow-on actions.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>public access (free to read) via google docs</AccessModel>
		<Author>Rachael Samberg, Timothy Vollmer</Author>
		<Date>07/23/2021</Date>
		<ISBN>N/A</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://docs.google.com/document/d/107Qmu595-7aOc2DPWc4vVDbz7PTULzn 20NOeNfBbWM/edit?usp=sharing</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>google doc</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Building Legal Literacies for Text Data Mining: Institute White Paper</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19547">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-269319-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The main objective of this survey/study is to improve the likelihood that at-risk slide collections of the built environment amassed by members of the Society of Architectural Historians are materially preserved for the benefit of future research and study.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Sonja Sekely-Rowland, Jackie Spafford</Author>
		<Date>11/01/2020</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>NEH/SAH Color Film Emergency Project November 2020 Follow Up Survey</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19548">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-269319-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The NEH-SAH Preservation Consortium Survey is an extension of the Color Film Emergency Project (CFEP) developed in 2013 with the Society of Architectural Historians. The present aims of this project are: (1) identification and evaluation of at-risk 35 mm slide collections, and (2) development of a consortium of institutional partners.  This survey is the first step in developing this consortium.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Sonja Sekely-Rowland, Jackie Spafford</Author>
		<Date>11/01/2020</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>NEH/SAH Preservation Consortium Survey</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19549">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-269319-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This is a collection assessment rubric that will help determine the condition and importance of the collection by collecting the following categories of information: Section A:  Institutional Affiliations:  Potential Consortia Partnershps Section B: Formal Considerations (size, condition, material types) Section C: Processing Considerations (donor restrictions, IP issues) Section D: Physical Risk Assessment Section E: Donor Goals Section F:  Extraordinary Comments/Concerns</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Jackie Spafford, Sonja Sekely-Rowland</Author>
		<Date>10-1-2020</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Society of Architectural Historians 35mm Slide Collection Assessment Rubric</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19558">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-271716-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>An assessment of the current condition of the Academy's archives and recommendations for improvement.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>N/S</AccessModel>
		<Author>Margot Note</Author>
		<Date>12/29/2020</Date>
		<ISBN>None</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Academy of American Poets Archive Evaluation</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19559">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-264041-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The report summarizes the accomplishments of our team as we established foundations for building an open-source, post-custodial, aggregating portal for Mexican American art. The project was supported by a two-year NEH HCRR Foundations-level grant. It also describes the lessons learned and includes a protocol for partnering with small-budget institutions, new culturally-informed vocabularies that will increase discovery of Mexican American art, metadata schema for the forthcoming portal, and resources submitted to the Getty Research Institute.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Cortez, Constance, Davalos, Karen Mary</Author>
		<Date>07-01-2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://hdl.handle.net/11299/223207</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>The University Digital Conservancy of the University of Minnesota  provides free and open access, increases visibility, ensures compliance with public access requirements, as well as provides full-text discoverability and long-term preservation of the records. Each record has a persistent URL.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>https://conservancy.umn.edu/</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>This is the homepage for the University Digital Conservancy, which provides access to the record deposited by Karen Mary Davalos.</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Creating Sustainable Foundations for Rhizomes of Mexican Ameican Art Since 1848</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19643">
		<ApplicationNumber>AKA-270132-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>As part of our work to plan and implement a new Digital Public History minor at the University of Connecticut, we consulted with external experts currently overseeing or developing minors in public history or other minors that were either interdisciplinary or had a significant digital focus. Some of these external experts are involved in programs currently or previously supported by NEH Humanities Connections grants.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Wes Hamrick, Kenia Rodriguez</Author>
		<Date>08/31/21</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://draft.digitalpublichistory.programs.uconn.edu/whitepaper/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Designing and Implementing a Digital Public History Minor at the University of Connecticut</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19695">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-271734-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A Heritage Reinvestment Plan provides the basis for budgeting reserve funds for capital projects needed for preservation of an historic building. A Heritage Reinvestment Plan is an important supplement for other documents that inform stewardship of an historic building, such as a Preservation Plan, an Historic Structures Report, and a Conservation Management Plan. The Heurich House Museum has received funding from the National Trust for Historic Preservation's National Trust Preservation Fund and from the National Endowment for the Humanities (grant number PG-271734-20) for Creating a Heritage Building Reinvestment Model.  The Heritage Building Reinvestment Model provides guidance for preparing a Heritage Reinvestment Plan for the Heurich House Museum which will be done under a separate contract by historic preservation professionals. The Heritage Building Reinvestment Model provides also addresses the special considerations encountered in planning for future capital expenditures for the building including:  -The possible categories of preservation work for the Heurich House Museum; -How to identify and organize the building components, assemblies, and systems for each category of work; -How to establish the service life and remaining service life of the building components of the Heurich House Museum, recognizing that maintaining historic fabric in good condition is the desired outcome; and, - How to approach estimating costs given the special considerations of undertaking projects and professional services for preventive conservation, preservation, and restoration of components of the Heurich House Museum.  The Heritage Building Reinvestment Model does not include cash flow planning or assessment of the property steward's capacity to fund work, as these issues are addressed as part of the Reserve Analysis.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open Access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Michael C. Henry</Author>
		<Date>04/26/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Heritage Reinvestment Model for the Heurich House Museum</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19743">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-253799-17</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The Center for Digital Antiquity at Arizona State University, in collaboration with the Amerind Museum, utilized a 2017 grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities to create a comprehensive digital library of archaeological investigations of the ancient Huhugam (Hohokam). The Digital Archive of Huhugam Archaeology (DAHA) now contains copies of more than 2,000 major archaeological reports, images and data sets. It is curated and made accessible through tDAR (the Digital Archaeological Record), an established online repository that preserves and provides access to archaeological data. The DAHA collection provides scholars with crucial long-term data for comparative studies, indigenous communities with access to a wealth of research on ancestral populations, and the general public with a reliable, vetted resource focused on Huhugam culture (1500 B.C. – 1450 A.D.).  This white paper was submitted as a deliverable to the National Endowment for the Humanities.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Christopher Nicholson, Center for Digital Antiquity, Keith Kintigh</Author>
		<Date>09/08/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://core.tdar.org/document/465750/digital-archive-of-huhugam-archaeology-daha-white-paper</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Digital Archive of Huhugam Archaeology (DAHA): White Paper</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19748">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-271826-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report contains information and recommendations concerning preservation management and other preservation-related topics based on a preservation assessment visit to the Tribal Historic Preservation Office of the 29 Palms Band of Mission Indians in Coachella, CA on June 29-30, 2021. The report contains an overview of current conditions and practices relating to collections care, and recommendations on future options for improvements in preservation.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>No</AccessModel>
		<Author>Rebecca Elder</Author>
		<Date>7/10/2021</Date>
		<ISBN>N/A</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>29 Palms Band of Mission Indians Preservation Assessment</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19750">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-271678-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The Cataloging Librarian, Our Lady of the Lake Sueltenfuss Library, invited LYRASIS Consultant Thomas F. R. Clareson to conduct a virtual assessment of the Library's preservation needs. The Library Director, Cataloging Librarian, and library and archives staff have demonstrated a dedication to the Special Collections and Archives and their preservation, but need to develop further environmental monitoring activities, additional collections care and use policies, and begin considering a new location or facility for the collections as they continue to expand the amount and the use of those collections. This report provides a framework for these efforts.  The report contains information and recommendations concerning preservation management and other preservation-related topics based on Clareson's virtual survey visit on November 17, 2020. The report provides an overview of current conditions and preservation practices in the Special Collections and Archives, and recommendations on future options for preservation management. The special and archival collections of Our Lady of the Lake University are a valuable resource to the University, the State of Texas, and students and scholars across the nation.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Thomas F. R. Clareson</Author>
		<Date>05/25/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Preservation Survey for Our Lady of the Lake University Sueltenfuss Library</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19761">
		<ApplicationNumber>PF-266605-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>In the fall of 2019, the High Point Museum contracted with the Image Permanence Institute (IPI) to support a project funded by the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) to conduct a mechanical system assessment for the air handling units serving the main collection storage space and the gallery spaces. The purpose of this project was to provide short and long-term recommendations for the improvement of the collection environment that the High Point Museum can reasonably implement. The goals of the project were to analyze the preservation quality of current environmental conditions provided by the mechanical systems and provide short and long-term recommendations to improve preservation and energy-efficient operation, while considering the historic nature of the building envelope. The report summarizes an evaluation based on a site visit performed by IPI Sustainable Preservation Specialist, Christopher Cameron, and Executive Director, Jae Gutierrez, as well as documentation review by Preventive Conservation Specialist, Kelly Krish, and discussions and data analysis with High Point Museum staff over an 18 month period. Findings include recommendations to improve dehumidification, implement seasonal set points, and address possible building envelope issues.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Kelly M. Krish, Christopher Cameron</Author>
		<Date>07/31/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Preservation Consulting Report</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19778">
		<ApplicationNumber>MN-268921-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Over the course of the project, there were 14 instances of the project being reported through press releases, TV appearances, and radio broadcasts.  An entire list of the audio/visual reports can be found here: https://may4thxr.kent.edu/publications/index.html</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Mixed access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Project Team</Author>
		<Date>06/30/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://may4thxr.kent.edu/publications/index.html</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>A list of the 14 different citations of the project.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Press Releases</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19791">
		<ApplicationNumber>FEL-262653-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>HICSS-55 Decision Notification for Submission 2944</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Aynne Kokas</Author>
		<Date>10/01/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Grindr and Data Trafficking: Theorizing consent in data localization</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19818">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-271673-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The Laurel Historical Society's Emergency Preparedness and Response Plan provides an integrated emergency and disaster planning system. It also provides guidance, critical information, and processes when an emergency or disaster is occurring or imminent. This Emergency Preparedness and Response Plan (Plan) guides the actions of staff and volunteers in preparing for, responding to, and recovering from an emergency.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Rebecca Kennedy</Author>
		<Date>05/01/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Emergency Preparedness and Response Plan</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19819">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-271673-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Risk Assessment Form customized to the Laurel Historical Society.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Rebecca Kennedy</Author>
		<Date>02/25/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>RISK EVALUATION CHECKLIST</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19821">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-271673-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This Risk Assessment is developed using current information, as available in December 2020. A risk assessment is a guiding document that should be completed annually or after any changes to the institution have been made. The information in this report should be used to identify mitigation and preparedness strategies to limit the impact to the institution during an emergency.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Rebecca Kennedy</Author>
		<Date>01/01/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Risk Assessment Report</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19904">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-269430-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This is the memorandum of agreement between UA libraries and Ana Carvalho regarding the agreement for the preservation of the CESA corpus.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Veronica Reyes Escudero, Ana Carvalho</Author>
		<Date>8/2/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.dropbox.com/s/w8kjevj60co1r20/MOU%2C CESA %26 University of Arizona Library Special Collections.pdf?dl=0</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Memorandum of Understanding with UA Libraries</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19905">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-269430-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This is the User Agreement created for the preservation of the CoBiVa by the UTRGV library.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Justin White, Katherine Christoffersen, Ryan Bessett</Author>
		<Date>8/24/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.dropbox.com/s/659nctr667raf8r/User Agreement%2C CoBiVa %26 UTRGV Libraries Digital Collection.pdf?dl=0</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>User Agreement with UTRGV Libraries</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19906">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-269430-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Here are more details about the preservation policies of UTRGV related to the process for preserving CoBiVa.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>UTRGV Libary</Author>
		<Date>1/1/2018</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/o5lwtkvreb94fxi22rfe3/UNIVER-1.DOC?dl=0&amp;amp;rlkey=l0198dkm0lrh9wco8ww3pde63</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>UTRGV Preservation Policies</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19907">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-269430-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This is the UA Library Digital Preservation Policy which relates to how CESA will be preserved.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>UA Library</Author>
		<Date>6/6/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.dropbox.com/s/e2ncian13wwg36a/UA%20DigitalPreservationPolicy 1-1-7 Final-Public.pdf?dl=0</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>UA Digital Preservation Policy</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19947">
		<ApplicationNumber>ZR-256755-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Vision Maker Media (VMM) held its seventh biennial Vision Maker Film Festival, April 20-26, 2018. The theme of the film festival, "We Are All Related," was a translation from the Lakota language -Mitákuye Oyás'i?- a commonly used expression indicating the Lakota's relationships to each other and in the world. It was especially appropriate as we welcomed our partners from the National MultiCultural Alliance (NMCA) formerly known as the National Minority Consortia (NMC). Partners of this alliance include The Center for Asian American Media (CAAM), Black Public Media (BPM), Latino Public Broadcasting (LPB) and Pacific Islanders in Communications (PIC).   The festival featured 53 films by diverse filmmakers and 15 in person Q&amp;amp;A's. The films featured were a number of shorts, documentary and feature films with some being productions by VMM and members of the National MultiCultural Alliance.  We measured success as follows: • Physical ticket sales for the 2018 film festival (total of 483 were sold) • Physical hard-copy post-screening evaluations for the 2018 film festival (157 evaluations received)  Participant comments: "Excellent film! Thank you!" "Beautifully shot and acted" "So glad to have discovered this- (don't "do" Facebook as am inexperienced so behind on most technical plus so busy with so many environmental and social justice awareness career)" "Not an enjoyably topic but an important one" "The film was better the second time!"</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Vision Maker Media</Author>
		<Date>4/20/2018</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>2018 Vision Maker Film Festival</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19948">
		<ApplicationNumber>ZR-256755-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The National Vision Maker Media Film Tour focuses on bringing Native produced content to communities across the United States. The objective of the tour is to promote Indigenous culture to provide positive impact on our Nation; provide educational opportunities that benefit teachers, students and the general public; and provide an opportunity for the community to interact with positive Indigenous role models.  First film tour stop was June 29, 2018 on the Santee Sioux Reservation in Santee, Nebraska.  Second film tour stop was July 21, 2018 was with Native POP: People of the Plains – A Gathering of Arts and Culture in Rapid City, South Dakota.   The third film tour stop was on March 8, 2019 in Lincoln, Nebraska for Vision Maker Film Festival: Indigenous Women's Films.  The last stop was with Native POP: People of the Plains – A Gathering of Arts and Culture in Rapid City, South Dakota on July 20, 2019.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Vision Maker Media</Author>
		<Date>6/29/2018</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Vision Maker Media Film Tour</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="19949">
		<ApplicationNumber>ZR-256755-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>"commUNITY" was the theme of the Lincoln Arts Councils Award winning eighth biennial Vision Maker Film Festival. This theme was to represent the citywide involvement with VMM to bring the best American Indian, Alaska Native and worldwide Indigenous films to Lincoln, Nebraska. Accompanying the films, the festival was to gather a collective of inspiring filmmakers to engage our community in important and captivating public conversations, creating a space for both healing and learning.  Unfortunately, with COVID-19 affecting the US and the rest of the world, March 2020, we decided to postpone the festival. The conclusion was to have an online festival to keep our audience, community, and staff safe and healthy. With the rapid change from an in-person festival to online, we gained an opportunity to engage a more diverse and widespread audience by offering our films worldwide and open for free streaming. The festival was extended to be a five-week event from August 27-October 5, 2020.  VMM streamed 7 short dramas, 14 documentary shorts, 4 short animations, 2 dramatic features, and 6 documentary feature films. We also held 14 Q&amp;amp;A's and 5 filmmaker panels, coming to a total of 28 filmmakers and those featured in films. We received positive feedback on the themes we had throughout the festival which included women's empowerment, environment &amp;amp; history, activism, LGBTQA+, and youth. Our filmmaker panels were centered around each of these 6 themes.   We measured success of our online audience reach as follows: · Online registrations for the 2020 online film festival (15,000 total registered), · Q&amp;amp;A attendees for the 2020 online film festival (total audience participation 8,000 + via Zoom webinar and Facebook Live event data counts), · Film streams for the 2020 online film festival (164,000+ data clicks to view films), and · Online post-festival evaluations for the 2020 film festival (408 total received).</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Vision Maker Media</Author>
		<Date>8/27/2020</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://visionmakermedia.org/online-filmfest/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Vision Maker Media online film festival webiste.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>2020 Vision Maker Film Festival</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20069">
		<ApplicationNumber>PD-266994-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A reconstruction of Proto-Naduhup prosody.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Simmons, Mark</Author>
		<Date>05/05/2021</Date>
		<ISBN>N/A</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Reconstructing Naduhup Prosody</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20074">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-271633-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>On February 23, 2021, paper-based, audiovisual, and photographic materials housed in the Sherman Room at the Brimfield Public Library (BPL) were assessed for preservation planning purposes by Stephanie Garafolo, Preservation Specialist for the Northeast Document Conservation Center (NEDCC) in Andover, MA. The assessment evaluated the buildings and environments as they relate to the preservation needs of the materials; examined current policies, storage, and handling procedures; and assessed the general condition of materials. Observations and recommendations are based on a pre-site visit questionnaire, an on-site visit, and remote discussions with Rebecca Wells, Library Director, Joanie Robbins, Historian, Michael DeFalco, library trustee and Digitization team volunteer; and Fran Ploof, Digitization team volunteer. Primary reference and archival functions for the BPL are performed by Ms. Wells and Ms. Robbins. They receive close support from Mr. DeFalco and Ms. Ploof in caring for the Local History Collection (LHC) in the Sherman Room.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>The Preservation Needs Assessment: Sherman Room; is a report document created solely for use by the staff of the Brimfield Public Library</AccessModel>
		<Author>Stephanie Garafolo</Author>
		<Date>2/23/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Report of a Preservation Needs Assessment</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20115">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-271743-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>On May 17 and May 20, 2021, paper-based, audiovisual, and photographic materials housed at McAuliffeShepard Discovery Center were assessed for preservation planning purposes by Elena Cordova, Contract Preservation Specialist for the Northeast Document Conservation Center (NEDCC) in Andover, MA. The assessment evaluated the buildings and environments as they relate to the preservation needs of the materials; examined current policies, storage, and handling procedures; and assessed the general condition of materials. Observations and recommendations in this report are based on a pre-site visit questionnaire, a site visit, and discussions with Executive Director, Jeanne Gerulskis and Education Coordinator, Christina "Chee" McGuigan.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Internal only</AccessModel>
		<Author>Elena Cordova</Author>
		<Date>06/30/2021</Date>
		<ISBN>none</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Report of a Preservation Needs Assessment</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20121">
		<ApplicationNumber>ZZ-258560-17</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>First Nations provides this report to share the impact of the Native Language Immersion Initiative (NLII) and to present findings and lessons learned from four years of targeted investments in Native language immersion programs. More importantly, this report serves as an opportunity to elevate the good work being accomplished in Native language revitalization.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Teresa Peterson</Author>
		<Date>11/01/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.firstnations.org/knowledge-center/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>First Nations Development Institute Knowledge Center</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>http://www.firstnations.org</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>First Nations Development Institute</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Ready for a New Decade: Investing in Native Language Immersion</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20122">
		<ApplicationNumber>ZZ-258560-17</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>First Nations provides this report to share the impact of the NLII and to present findings and lessons learned from four years of targeted investments in Native language immersion programs. More importantly, this report serves as an opportunity to elevate the good work being accomplished in Native language revitalization.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Teresa Peterson</Author>
		<Date>11/01/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.firstnations.org/knowledge-center/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>First Nations Development Center Knowledge Center</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>http://www.firstnations.org</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>First Nations Development Institute</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Ready for a New Decade: Investing in Native Language Immersion: A Summary for Native Communities and Language Practitioners</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20123">
		<ApplicationNumber>ZZ-258560-17</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>First Nations provides this summary report to funders and allies to share the impact of the NLII and to present findings and lessons learned from four years of targeted investments in Native language immersion programs. More importantly, this report serves as an opportunity to elevate and continue the good work being accomplished in Native language revitalization.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Teresa Peterson</Author>
		<Date>11/01/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.firstnations.org/knowledge-center/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>First Nations Development Institute Knowledge Center</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>http://www.firstnations.org</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>First Nations Development Institute</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Ready for a New Decade: Investing in Native Language Immersion: A Summary for Funders and Allies.</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20135">
		<ApplicationNumber>ZR-256713-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>In collaboration with the University of South Dakota Center for Disabilities (CFD),Black Hills Works and specifically, Flutter Productions initiated an evaluation plan using the principles of empowerment evaluation. This report contains summaries of activities which Flutter Productions has invested in and executed throughout the great Rapid City and Sioux Falls areas. Attachments to this report include data results gathered for this project.The overarching mission of Flutter Productions and the NEH project offer opportunities for people with disabilities to be fully included in community plays with performers who do not have a disability. These performances include theatre, dance poetry readings, and other contemporary performing arts productions; all of which all of which provide participants with opportunities to exercise their artistic talents.Facilitated conversations are conversations that allowed the facilitator to promote and probe respondents for information about the experiences as participants in Flutter Productions.  The results of these conversations were revealing about the challenges, struggles, accomplishments and connections that all participants experienced.  Conversations were recorded by both Center for Disabilities staff and Ms. Heather Pickering.  The conversations were transcribed and emergent themes were identified by Center for Disabilities evaluation staff.  While the transcribed data included numerous comments from persons with and without disabilities in different roles, we identified seven themes that that facilitated conversation participants frequently We organized them in the following thematic categories1.Finding a Voice 2.Changing Expectations3.Inclusive Cast 4.Friendship &amp;amp; Belonging 5."It's Ok to be Different...and It's Definitely OK to Not Fit In" 6.It's About Community Leaders 7. The Creativity of Adapting to the Performer</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open Access</AccessModel>
		<Author>John R. Johnson, Ph.D Research and Development Director, USD, Heather Pickering, Artistic Director, Flutter Productions, Dr. Jake Cummings, Kristin Berg, Natalia Davila, Dr. Jonathon A MeDrano, Wendy Parent-Johnson, Ph.D, CRC, CESP</Author>
		<Date>04/16/2020</Date>
		<ISBN>000000000000</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://youtu.be/HTJS0rxxHik</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>YouTube is a website that allows professionals, organizations, and amateurs the opportunity to create, upload, and view videos. This link is an Unlisted Link, only those who have the link can view it, and it is not intended for general public viewing. 
This video is just a small sampling of many interviews and facilitated conversations conducted by Flutter Productions with cast members, staff, and audience members from 2017 - 2020.  The clips in this video reflect a portion of the program evaluation conducted from a three year evaluation of the all-ability dance theatre program conducted by the University of South Dakota School of Medicine and Center for Disabilities, and Flutter Productions, funded in part by a major grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities.  The evaluation explores the effects and benefits of all-ability arts with individuals with disabilities as the center of a nexus that includes: community members, audience members, volunteers, and staff.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Evaluation on the Impact of All-Ability Performing Arts on a Community</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20209">
		<ApplicationNumber>FN-230212-15</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>It was initially assumed that there were two related language varieties on Santa Cruz Island in the Solomon Islands. Later, it became clear that there were three related languages, since the ones in the split were not mutually intelligible. That left us with Natügu [ntu], Nalögo [nlz], and Engdewu (formerly Nagu) [ngr]. In recent fieldwork during September through November 2015, Boerger and her team of interns, plus a PhD student from an Australian university, all became convinced that Noipä is a distinct language from the other three, though clearly related. This conclusion was drawn from discussions with speakers of all varieties, with those from other languages telling us that they do not understand Noipä. And Noipä speakers also reported that the others cannot understand them. Noipä is spoken only in the village of Noipä , and the people there have at least a passive, but often an active understanding of either Natügu [ntu] or Nalögo [nlz], which border them on either side. To establish this more concretely, the team led by Boerger collected an oral Swadesh 200 word list with written transcription, the written part of which will be included in the new code request document, along with data from the related languages.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Brenda H. Boerger</Author>
		<Date>10/20/2015</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://iso639-3.sil.org/request/2016-017</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Change request for Noipä to receive a separate ISO code [npx]</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20587">
		<ApplicationNumber>GG-266368-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report reflects data which was collected and collated both by International Storytelling Center (ISC) staff and by the National Humanities Alliance (NHA), a coalition of organizations dedicated to advancing humanities education, research, preservation, and public programs.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>International Storytelling Center</Author>
		<Date>07/31/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.storytellingcenter.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Freedom-Stories-Social-Impact-Report.pdf?x43411</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Freedom Stories Social Impact Report</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20624">
		<ApplicationNumber>PF-266733-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A 194-page planning document that provides Fort Ticonderoga museum staff with professional guidance and recommendations for addressing collections preservation issues within the historic Thompson Pell Research Center building as it is converted into a dedicated Collections and Research Facility. The Plan also includes recommendations concerning the storage needs for a new 3,000-object collection that the museum will be acquiring and moving to the TPRC in 2022.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>In house planning document. Can be redacted and shared with peers upon request. A sample is provided in the White Paper document.</AccessModel>
		<Author>Fort Ticonderoga Association, John G. Waite Associates, Architects, Kohler Ronan Consulting Engineering, Spicer Art Conservation, LLC</Author>
		<Date>12/10/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Fort Ticonderoga Thompson-Pell Research Center Existing Conditions and Feasibility Study</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20643">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-271812-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report presents an overview of the Billie Jane Baguley Library and Archives based on Ms. Teper's observations and background information provided to her as well as her site visit, broken down into three areas: 1) Collections Materials; 2) Facilities; and 3) Administration. Following her observations, Teper provides suggested prioritized recommendations to further the library and archives preservation efforts and impact, as well as possible future funding opportunities for preservation efforts.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Jennifer Hain Teper</Author>
		<Date>06/21/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Collection Preservation Recommendations for the Billie Jane Baguley Library and Archives, Heard Museum</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20716">
		<ApplicationNumber>PF-260745-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A white paper written in fulfillment of a project funded in part by an NEH Sustaining Cultural Heritage Collections Planning Grant.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Beth Parker Miller, Joy Gardiner</Author>
		<Date>12/31/21</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Connecting People with Collections (CPC) or Establishing an economically, socially, and environmentally sustainable plan for accessible storage</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20765">
		<ApplicationNumber>BP-266365-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>In 2019 Museum staff acquired funding through the National Endowment for the Humanities public humanities projects grant program to create a new Comprehensive Interpretive Plan (CIP). Through this planning process, the Museum sought to develop an actionable document that incorporates new scholarship; considers multiple approaches and methods of interpretation; utilizes a fully activated collection and appropriate restoration work; incorporates the organization's strategic goals; highlights the social impact of our cultural programming; brings immediacy to the Museum's interpretation; and takes an inclusive approach to audience engagement.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>n/a</AccessModel>
		<Author>Matt Kirkman, Brooke Steinhauser</Author>
		<Date>05/01/2021</Date>
		<ISBN>n/a</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Comprehensive Interpretive Plan Emily Dickinson Museum</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20845">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-271805-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The link below includes five of the ten on-site collections assessments as as sample of the work that was completed.  I am also attaching a link in the 'secondary URL' for a sample of one of the inventory sheets that was done for Cortland-Bazetta Historical Society, one of the ten participating organizations.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Terri Schindel &amp;amp; Siegfried Rempel</Author>
		<Date>11/1/2020</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://drive.google.com/file/d/1A8Qcvz7uSauwBjeavu895DYSAJ4Kld6l/view?usp=sharing</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL>https://drive.google.com/file/d/1jOqUBT0AwhYelj2qG bVnWdcxPaVPccq/view?usp=sharing</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Sample of the on-site assessments</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20878">
		<ApplicationNumber>FS-261503-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A report on the resurgence of interest among Anglo-American Analytic philosophers in G. W. F. Hegel with special reference to the work of Robert Brandom.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open access on web</AccessModel>
		<Author>Willem A. deVries</Author>
		<Date>10/26/2021</Date>
		<ISBN>--</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://aeon.co/essays/how-the-anglophone-world-is-rediscovering-hegels-philosophy</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Hegel Today</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20887">
		<ApplicationNumber>FS-261503-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Book Review</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Online</AccessModel>
		<Author>J Wretzel</Author>
		<Date>1/1/2022</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://ndpr.nd.edu/reviews/hegels-theory-of-normativity-the-systematic-foundations-of-the-philosophical-science-of-right/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Review of Hegel's Theory of Normativity by Kevin S. Thompson.</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="20996">
		<ApplicationNumber>SO-263453-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The grant project involves the restoration of our open-ocean voyaging vessel the Fanhigayan Guahan by our master carvers, along with workshops and training conducted by our master navigator, which will contribute to perpetuating the transference of sacred voyaging skills and traditions.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Google Drive link</AccessModel>
		<Author>TASA</Author>
		<Date>6/7/21</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://drive.google.com/file/d/1SIptHRSTO7G5CNLbD6orQnX0r0xFjI18/view?usp=sharing</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Video/slide show documentation of grant project activities associated with the restoration of the outrigger open-ocean voyaging canoe, (sakman) Fanhigayan Guåhan.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Traditions Affirming our Seafaring Ancestry, Inc. (TASA): Fanhigayan Guåhan Sakman</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="21044">
		<ApplicationNumber>AH-269621-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>In recent decades, we as a nation have failed to prepare young Americans for self-government, leaving the world's oldest constitutional democracy in grave danger, afflicted by both cynicism and nostalgia, as it approaches its 250th anniversary. The time has come to recommit to the education of our young people for informed, authentic, and engaged citizenship.  Educating for American Democracy (EAD) is an unprecedented effort that convened a diverse and cross-ideological group of scholars and educators to create a Roadmap to Educating for American Democracy— guidance and an inquiry framework that states, local school districts, and educators can use to transform teaching of history and civics to meet the needs of a diverse 21st century K–12 student body.  EAD is a call to action to invest in strengthening history and civic learning, and to ensure that civic learning opportunities are delivered equitably throughout the country.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Both the EAD Report and Roadmap are freely available on the site</AccessModel>
		<Author>Danielle Allen, Paul Carrese, Louise Dubé, Michelle Herczog, Emma Humphries, Jane Kamensky, Kei Kawashima-Ginsberg, Peter Levine, Adam Seagrave, Tammy Waller</Author>
		<Date>10/1/2019</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.educatingforamericandemocracy.org/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Educating for American Democracy - Report &amp;amp; Roadmap</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="21160">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-271645-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report includes a complete assessment of the materials located in the Local History Collection of the Jefferson County Public Library in Madison, Indiana.  It also includes an Addendum which is titled a Digital Preservation Addendum.  The Assessment includes paper-based, audiovisual and photographic materials housed in this collection.  The assessment evaluated the buildings and environments as they related to the preservation needs of the materials; examined current policies, storage and handling procedures and assessed the general condition of materials. Observations are based on a pre-site visit questionnaire, a full-day site visit and discussions with Camille Fife (Local History Coordinator), Alicia Zavala (Library Assistant-Local History Collection) Judi Terpening (Library Director), Ron Marshall (Maintenance), and Kelly Joyce (Library Trustee).</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Alison Fulmer, Preservation Specialist, NEDCC,Andover, MA 01810</Author>
		<Date>10/04/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Report of a Preservation Needs Assessment</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="21240">
		<ApplicationNumber>AH-274329-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>NA</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Robert Elliott, Joana Jansen, Janne Underriner, Brittany Parham</Author>
		<Date>9/30/2020</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>Internal University of Oregon Brief on Online Language Revitalization Learning Series, June 2020</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Internal University of Oregon Brief on Online Language Revitalization Learning Series, June 2020</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>LRLS Brief 2020</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="21365">
		<ApplicationNumber>BP-264708-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The report describes the interpretive plan for new exhibits that bring to life the Native American history of the East Bay and the continued presence today of the Ohlone people.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Holly Alonso</Author>
		<Date>12/31/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Indigenous Voices Interpretive Plan for Peralta Hacienda Historical Park</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="21411">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-280605-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Between January 3, 2022 and January 13, 2022 , paper-based, audiovisual, and photographic materials housed in Special Collections at the James P. Adams Library at Rhode Island College were assessed for preservation planning purposes by Elena Cordova, Contract Preservation Specialist for the Northeast Document Conservation Center (NEDCC) in Andover, MA. The assessment, which was funded by a National Endowment for the Humanities Preservation Assistance Grant, evaluated the buildings and environments as they relate to the preservation needs of the materials; examined current policies, storage, and handling procedures; and assessed the general condition of materials. Observations and recommendations are based on a pre-site visit questionnaire, a site visit, and discussions with Digital Archivist and Special Collections Librarian, Molly Bruce Patterson; Digital Initiatives Coordinator, Andrew Davis; and Carissa DeLizio, Library Director.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>n/a - unpublished report for internal use</AccessModel>
		<Author>Elena Cordova, Northeast Document Conservation Center</Author>
		<Date>03/11/2022</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Report of a Preservation Needs Assessment: Special Collections at the James P. Adams Library, Rhode Island College, Providence, RI.</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="21479">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-277585-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This white paper documents the work of the American Congress Digital Archives Portal project to aggregate congressional archives into a single, online platform and make them more broadly available. Congressional archives document the democratic process; the development of public policy; and multiple narratives related to the country's social, cultural, and political development. Work of the project included developing standards and best practices; creating governance structures for the one-year project and future phases; developing a web portal that meets user needs and adding archival content; determining digitization priorities via a research survey; conducting usability testing; and communicating and publicizing the project. The project was made possible by funding from the National Endowment for the Humanities.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open Access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Danielle Emerling</Author>
		<Date>04/15/2022</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://researchrepository.wvu.edu/faculty publications/3090/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>The American Congress Digital Archives Portal Project White Paper</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="21537">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-280839-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Summary and individual condition reports of conservation survey of paintings at Black Mountain College Museum + Arts Center.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Crawford, Craig, Yoshikawa, Maho</Author>
		<Date>12/1/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Condition report from Crawford Conservation</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="21778">
		<ApplicationNumber>PE-277136-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>During his tenure at the National Gallery, Derek Lintala composed a meeting summary for the Washington Conservation Guild "Emerging Professionals Talks" series on a lecture delivered by Conservation Center alumnus Hae Min Park ‘18, Andrew W. Mellon Fellow in Paintings Conservation at the Walters Art Museum.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Derek Lintala</Author>
		<Date>05/02/2022</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://washingtonconservationguild.org/2022/05/02/wcg-meeting-summary-investigating-portrait-girolamo-mercuriale-lavinia-fontana-walters-art-museum/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>WCG Meeting Summary: “Investigating Portrait of Girolamo Mercuriale by Lavinia Fontana at the Walters Art Museum”</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="21830">
		<ApplicationNumber>HC-50007-10</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report culminates two years of work by CLIR staff involving extensive interviews and site visits with scholars engaged in international research collaborations involving computational analysis of large data corpora. These scholars were the first recipients of grants through the Digging into Data program, led by the NEH, who partnered with JISC in the UK, SSHRC in Canada, and the NSF to fund the first eight initiatives. The report introduces the eight projects and discusses the importance of these cases as models for the future of research in the academy.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open</AccessModel>
		<Author>Williford, Christa, Henry, Charles</Author>
		<Date>6/1/2012</Date>
		<ISBN>978-1-932326-4</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.clir.org/pubs/reports/pub151/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>One Culture. Computationally Intensive Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="21831">
		<ApplicationNumber>HC-50004-08</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>As part of its ongoing programs in digital scholarship and the cyberinfrastructure to support teaching, learning and research, the Council on Library and Information Resources (CLIR) in cooperation with the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) held a symposium on September 15, 2008 in which a group of some 30 leading scholars was invited to  articulate the research challenges that will use the new media to advance the analysis and interpretations of text, images and other sources of interest to the humanities and social sciences and in so doing, pose interesting problems for ongoing computational research. White papers were commissioned to help frame the issues. This report contains the final versions of those papers, as well as an account of the day's discussion and a summary of a report by Diane Zorich on digital humanities centers.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Friedlander, Amy, Babeu, Alison, Bamman, David, Cerrato, Lisa, Crane, Gregory, Huberman, Bernardo, Levander, Caroline, Murray, Stephen, Oard, Douglas, Singhal, Rasmi, Stone, Maureen, Zorich, Diane</Author>
		<Date>3/1/2009</Date>
		<ISBN>978-1-932326-3</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.clir.org/pubs/reports/pub145/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Working Together or Apart: Promoting the Next Generation of Digital Scholarship</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="21870">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-266647-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report is the outcome of a general preservation assessment of the Cultural &amp;amp; Natural History Collections (CNHC) University of La Verne, which was made possible by funding from an NEH Preservation Assistance Grant for Smaller Institutions, awarded to the museum in fall 2019. The information gathered and summarized in the Observations sections of the report is based on conversations with Director Beardsley and Curator Collier, visual observations of the condition of the facilities and collections, and a review of CNHC's current practices and policies. Interpretation of the facts gathered during site visits form the basis for the Discussion sections under each heading, and further analysis of the present situation in light of the museum's mission leads to the Recommendations for specific actions that can be taken to improve the state of the collection as a whole. Focusing on preservation issues, practical strategies are offered for making systematic improvements to collection storage. These are summarized at the conclusion of the report and divided into necessary and immediate goals and actions possible in the short-term, and medium to long-range goals that will require more time and resources to achieve. The museum's objectives for the assessment were to examine current storage practices and environmental conditions, and to provide guidance on best practices for care and long-term preservation of the collections, including training on how to recognize potential problems and strategies for improvements. The grant was intended to focus on the humanities collections, though by necessity--since they share the same storage space--the natural history collections also were included in the assessment.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Report provided upon request.</AccessModel>
		<Author>Irena Calinescu, Fine Arts Conservation LLC, Kellie Boss, Boss Conservation LLC, Stefani Cavazos, Fine Arts Conservation LLC</Author>
		<Date>4/23/2021</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Conservation Assessment Report for the Cultural and Natural History Collections, University of La Verne</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="22126">
		<ApplicationNumber>AV-279607-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A pre-discussion survey for workshop participants.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Ayesha Chetty and Eric Hodges</Author>
		<Date>5/24/22</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeYkfp0s7VCvg2GdQsnERWphRG4rZJ8hlR41BoD2bqOecD Dw/viewform</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Pre-discussion survey</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="22127">
		<ApplicationNumber>AV-279607-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Post-discussion survey for participants.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Ayesha Chetty and Eric Hodges</Author>
		<Date>5/24/22</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSchPdOCraacgjZykAVEj3bSKw7QShmBDllOrowFvYSs7AZ-bA/viewform</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Post-discussion survey</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="22303">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-280850-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>On December 3, 2021, paper-based, photographic, and audiovisual materials housed in the Legacy Center at the Japanese American Service Committee (JASC) were assessed for preservation planning purposes by Eli Boyne, Preservation Specialist for the Northeast Document Conservation Center (NEDCC) in Andover, MA. The assessment evaluated the buildings and environments as they relate to the preservation needs of the materials; examined current policies, storage, and handling procedures; and assessed the general condition of materials. Observations and recommendations are based on a pre-site visit questionnaire and a full-day site visit that included discussions with Emma Saito Lincoln, Legacy Center Director; Ken Oba, Volunteer; Michael Takada, Executive Director/CEO; and Bryan Robson, Controller.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Boyne, Eli</Author>
		<Date>2/3/2022</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Report of a Preservation Needs Assessment</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="22479">
		<ApplicationNumber>FEL-273171-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This is a technical report describing ethnographic fieldwork completed in 2021. Filed with the Sela company.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Allison Mickel</Author>
		<Date>2022/07/07</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Outline and Report on Ethnographic Fieldwork Completed, Summer 2021</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="22755">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-280966-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report examines the preservation needs and recommends priorities for the preservation of the Aquinnah Cultural Center's freestanding historic and artistic works located at the Vanderhoop House on Martha's Vineyard, Massachusetts. The purpose of this report is to provide a foundation upon which to base a master plan for the long-term care and preservation of these important cultural resources.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>available on request from ACC</AccessModel>
		<Author>Valarie Kincade</Author>
		<Date>04/10/2022</Date>
		<ISBN>NA</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Aquinnah Cultural Center General Preservation Needs Assessment</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="22859">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-280636-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Executive Summary  The Huna Heritage Foundation (HHF) Library and Archives participated in a virtual preservation assessment in November 30 – December 1, 2021. Consultant Annie Peterson of LYRASIS led the assessment, which included a video tour of the archives storage space, discussions about staffing, planning, storage, and other facets of preservation and access to HHF's archival collections.   The goals of the preservation assessment were:  •Discuss and document HHF's existing strengths, what staff are already doing well, and areas for potential improvement related to collections care and access  •Gather information to create this report documenting the current state of collections, site visit findings, and recommendations for improved preservation practices •Use this report to advocate for resources (externally and/or internally) to move forward with providing access and use of the archival materials  The assessment focused on preservation of physical collections. A digital collection assessment was conducted in 2018. Preservation entails providing sustained, long-term access to collections. Near-term access to collections was also discussed, as preservation and access are closely intertwined.   HHF staff have made excellent progress on describing and arranging their archival collections and are well-prepared to take next steps to make collections accessible and preserve them for access in the future. The digital projects that HHF has already worked on, the relationships that HHF staff have built, and the commitment to HHF's shared vision is a remarkable foundation that HHF will build on to maintain enduring access to its collections.   The recommendations in this report are intended to guide HHF's next steps. Summarized recommendations, from the perspective of the consultant, are listed below, with more detailed recommendations in the body of the report. HHF staff will add their expertise and deeper understanding of organization to turn these recommendations</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Internal Use</AccessModel>
		<Author>Annie Peterson</Author>
		<Date>1/10/2022</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Preservation Assessment Report: Huna Heritage Foundation</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="22947">
		<ApplicationNumber>RZ-266160-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Excavations during 2022 continued in Palenque's residential sectors. The goal of this work is to systematically recover and document traces of daily activities in the homes of Palenque's diverse population. We seek to understand the ways that repeated practices formed Palenque's way of life during its apogee, from AD 450 – 850. Through the excavation of areas typical for daily activities, including plaza spaces outside of the structures as well as the interior surfaces of the structures, we seek to test for the range of economic, ritual, and food related activities that may be unique to individual households as well as those activities that are shared across a possible neighborhood. This report summarizes findings from the first field season, during which we conducted excavations in the Structure JO33 Compound. We found evidence of daily life in the form of chipped stone tools, grinding stones, and ceramics used for food preparation and serving, but also evidence of disposal of, and possibly working of, white stone into ornaments, and household-based ritual including the use of figurines, incense burning, and the possible use of a ceramic drum.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Project report</AccessModel>
		<Author>Lisa M. Johnson, Lucas R.M. Johnson, Maureen Carpenter</Author>
		<Date>12/31/2022</Date>
		<ISBN>NA</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>NA</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Arqueología doméstica en un barrio de Palenque: Excavaciones en conjunto JO33</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="22974">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-277369-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Report derived from surveys with potential users to determine preferences such as which features will be most useful for BMCM+AC's digital collections portal.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Internal to BMCM+AC staff, board, and project team.</AccessModel>
		<Author>Taylor Barrett</Author>
		<Date>09/30/2022</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>BMCM+AC User Needs Survey Report</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="22975">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-277369-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Guidelines for staff use of CollectiveAccess; importing/exporting data; standards for manual additions, quality assurance, edits, and deletions by staff; and digital preservation policies.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Internal to BMCM+AC staff, board, and project team.</AccessModel>
		<Author>Taylor Barrett, Black Mountain College Museum + Arts Center</Author>
		<Date>09/30/2022</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>BMCM+AC Digital Collections Workflow</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="22976">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-277369-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>High-level guidance on priorities and long-term use of BMCM+AC's digital collections platform as identified by consultant through user needs assessments and discussions.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Internal to BMCM+AC staff, board, and project team.</AccessModel>
		<Author>Taylor Barrett</Author>
		<Date>09/30/2022</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>BMCM+AC Digital Collections Strategic Plan</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="23030">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-280728-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Internal document to ensure the safety of Genesee Country Village &amp;amp; Museum's John L. Wehle Gallery collections, staff, building, and visitors. Used to assess and minimize risk to the collections the Museum is tasked with preserving and interpreting for the public, particularly in the case of an emergency or disaster incident, as well as to recover from such an incident.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Internal document</AccessModel>
		<Author>Genesee Country Village &amp;amp; Museum Curatorial Staff</Author>
		<Date>9/1/22</Date>
		<ISBN>N/A</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>N/A</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>N/A</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>N/A</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>N/A</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Genesee Country Village &amp;amp; Museum - Emergency Plan</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="23753">
		<ApplicationNumber>PF-280799-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The Collection Storage Master Plan (CSMP) project is a pre-planning exercise supporting comprehensive long-range Research Libraries collection storage planning, emphasizing special collection storage and climate resilience. The collaborative project team included NYPL staff from Collection Management, Preservation, Collection Development, Facilities, Security, and Energy and Sustainability, supported by consultants in preservation environment, sustainability, and architecture. Project activities included a documentation review; curatorial, facilities, and security staff interviews; and onsite visits to NYPL's 50+ storage areas at its research centers. The 97-page report includes foundational recommendations, targeted considerations for collection storage planning, and recommended action items to improve preservation.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>In-house planning document. Free access to NYPL senior leaders, preservation staff, and staff involved in collection storage planning.  Also available to NEH staff upon request.</AccessModel>
		<Author>William Stingone, Rebecca Fifield</Author>
		<Date>2/1/2023</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>NYPL Collection Storage Master Plan</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="23812">
		<ApplicationNumber>CHA-268873-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The original goals of the proposal were to implement permanent solutions to four major problems—roof, paver, and window leaks, as well as excessive ultraviolet light—that continue to threaten the integrity of the library structure and pose an imminent risk to collections stewardship, humanities scholarship, and overall institutional health. The trustees of IAS selected the firm Kimmel Borgette to scope this important project. After an assessment of the alternatives and deep consideration of the library's long-term needs, we have decided to move forward by bridging the existing building with a steel truss system. A usable third floor will be added to the building without removing the existing original vaulted roof, thereby preserving the uniqueness of the original design. Please see the attached documents for renderings ("Library Design"). Within the attached designs, you'll see an abundance of office spaces to meet existing need and create capacity for new personnel to support interdisciplinary projects, open spaces for collaboration, seminar rooms, as well as multi-purpose spaces. In keeping with the paramount importance of preserving the building's revered architectural design, the proposed improvements are planned for minimal visibility. In addition, the planned renovations will make vital updates to the library to achieve much higher levels of energy efficiency; to bring the facility up to code; and to improve maintenance and accessibility. The project conforms closely to the institution's long-range strategic plan, in which a central focus is renewal and restoration of major campus infrastructure. The budget for this plan is now estimated at $11 - $15 million, dependent upon the prices of raw materials, inflation, labor costs and finishes. We've identified additional donors who have committed to fund this proposal, building on those funds already certified and reported as part of our match.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>N/A</AccessModel>
		<Author>N/A</Author>
		<Date>04/06/2023</Date>
		<ISBN>N/A</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>N/A</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>N/A</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Final design plans for the renovation of the Institute’s Historical Studies – Social Science Library</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="23820">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-287457-22</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Report of a preservation needs assessment conducted at the New Orleans Pharmacy Museum. This report contains best practice recommendations on collection management and preservation planning, the building environment, collections storage and handling, and conservation and exhibition.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Eli Boyne, Preservation Specialist</Author>
		<Date>02/07/2023</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Report of a Preservation Needs Assessment</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="23853">
		<ApplicationNumber>RZ-260752-18</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A 509 page report, in Spanish, reporting on the 2021 field season. A report, also in Spanish, is not yet expected but is under preparation for the 2022 field season.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Elizabeth Marroquin, Thomas Garrison, Stephen Houston</Author>
		<Date>02/01/2021</Date>
		<ISBN>NA</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.mesoweb.com/zotz/El-Zotz-2021.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>A public access report on the Mesoweb.com website.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>PROYECTO ARQUEOLÓGICO EL ZOTZ 15va TEMPORADA DE CAMPO INFORME FINAL ENTREGADO A LA DIRECCION GENERAL DEL PATRIMONIO CULTURAL Y NATURAL</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="23963">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-287782-22</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This report provides the preservation assessment conducted by Conservator Lisa Duncan to evaluate the Rare Books Room at The Evergreen State College Library. The assessment report recommends powder-coated steel shelving, higher shelves to properly store materials, and additional monitoring of temperature and relative humidity.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Lisa Duncan</Author>
		<Date>12/27/2022</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1RO YQ42-zz0VEW7rDNSax7yjCYZe4oAa</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Preservation Assessment of the Rare Books Room at The Evergreen State College Library</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="24201">
		<ApplicationNumber>MD-277096-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This requirements specification document presents user personas and functional and non-functional requirements for an app that aims to enhance the visitor experience at Vermilionville Village, a living history museum in Lafayette, Louisiana. The user personas developed in this study include a school student, a community member, a visitor from outside the community, and a ULL history professor. Each persona is based on demographic information, background, personality traits, goals and motivations, and potential challenges that they may encounter during their visit.  The functional requirements identified for the app include interactive maps, historical and cultural information, the ability to purchase tickets and make reservations, and compatibility with different devices and operating systems. Non-functional requirements include user-friendliness, accessibility, security, and privacy.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Beenish Moalla Chaudhry</Author>
		<Date>6/1/2022</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Requirements Specification Doucment</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="24262">
		<ApplicationNumber>HAA-269062-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This project set out to think through different considerations that need to be made before building a data repository for prosopographic data through a series of workshops. The primary focus of the discussions was on how to build infrastructure that will actually be usable and used by its constituencies. The workshop generated a lot of discussion about the people who use data humanities infrastructure and how we can center them as we build new data sharing and preservation apparatuses.  The primary outputs of this project were the User Personas, which can eventually be transformed into a User Requirements document for a future repository developer. The "Specific Goals" column for each user outlines in detail the necessary functionality for this repository.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open Access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Stanley, Sarah</Author>
		<Date>04/02/2022</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://prosopreponeh.github.io/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Repository for Prosopographic Data</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="24433">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-280811-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>On December 14, 2021, the digital collections at the CCTV Center for Media &amp;amp; Democracy (CCTV) were assessed for planning purposes by Stephanie Garafolo, Associate Preservation Specialist of NEDCC. The goals of the assessment were to document the state of digital preservation at CCTV, identify challenges and opportunities for improvement, and make recommendations for preserving the Center's unique digital collections.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Upon Request</AccessModel>
		<Author>Stephanie Garofano, NEDCC</Author>
		<Date>2/16/22</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>NA</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>NA</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>NA</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>NA</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Digital Preservation Assessment for CCTV</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="24448">
		<ApplicationNumber>PW-269407-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The Green-Wood Cemetery, one of America's oldest rural cemeteries, was established in 1838 on 478 acres and is the resting place for 570,000 permanent residents, including Leonard Bernstein, Boss Tweed, Charles Ebbets,Jean-Michel Basquiat, Louis Comfort Tiffany, Horace Greeley, Civil War generals, baseball legends, politicians, artists, entertainers, and inventors. In 1999, it established The Green-Wood Historic Fund, a 501c3 organization whose mission is to preserve and maintain the cemetery, including its monuments of historical and cultural significance; to advance the public knowledge of Green-Wood; to conduct, sponsor, and host education programs in the community; and to safeguard the natural habitat and parklands of one of New York City's first green spaces. In recent years, the Fund came to appreciate the importance of its vast collection of institutional records, which contains the documentation for every interment since the cemetery's first burial in 1840. With engagement from an advisory board, the Fund sought to identify high priorities to focus its energies upon in order to advance its mission. Among all of the archival documents at Green-Wood — 3,000 cubic feet in total — the advisory board zeroed in on 60 handwritten, cloth-bound volumes, which recorded all interments at Green-Wood in its first century, known as the Burial &amp;amp; Vital Records. A 2019 implementation grant funded by the National Endowment for the Humanities, "Providing Access to the Unexpectedly Rich Records of Brooklyn's Green-Wood Cemetery" allowed the cemetery to transcribe the ledgers, build a database and search engine, upload the records to the database, and build a web page to make the information accessible. The following pages, define, describe, and disseminate the project's details so that other cemeteries may replicate the program, others may harvest the data, and the public may search for the many residents in Green-Wood Cemetery.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Open access</AccessModel>
		<Author>Julie I. May, Lisa Alpert, Stacy Locke, Bill McKinney, Colin McDonald</Author>
		<Date>2022-11-28</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.green-wood.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Green-Wood-White-Paper 2022-11-28.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>We invite you to learn more about how this database was developed in the white paper from our project director, Julie I. May.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>The Green-Wood Historic Fund 2019 Implementation Proposal to the National Endowment for the Humanities Humanities Collections and Reference Resources Providing Access to the Unexpectedly Rich Records of Brooklyn’s Green-Wood Cemetery</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="24465">
		<ApplicationNumber>BP-278283-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Final report compiled by design firm to provide a summary of project findings as well as a series of interpretive options, recommendations, and a proposed series of steps to implement those recommendations.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Report format for staff and stakeholder use.</AccessModel>
		<Author>Howard + Revis Design</Author>
		<Date>03/15/2023</Date>
		<ISBN>n/a</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Final Visioning Document</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="24477">
		<ApplicationNumber>PG-287820-22</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Executive Summary On March 14, 2023, paper-based, photographic, and audiovisual materials housed at the Albemarle Charlottesville Historical Society were assessed for preservation planning purposes by Alison Fulmer, Preservation Specialist for the Northeast Document Conservation Center (NEDCC) in Andover, MA. The assessment evaluated the buildings and environments as they relate to the preservation needs of the materials; examined current policies, storage, and handling procedures; and assessed the general condition of materials. Observations and recommendations are based on a pre-site visit questionnaire, a full-day site visit, and discussions staff members.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel/>
		<Author>Alison Fulmer</Author>
		<Date>4/28/2023</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Report of a Preservation Needs Assessment</Title>
	</Report>
	<Report ID="24491">
		<ApplicationNumber>GE-280520-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The We Are Texas: Origin Stories Interpretive Plan provides an overview of the exhibition including major themes, sample emblematic stories and artifacts, and interpretive strategies for the permanent exhibition.</Abstract>
		<AccessModel>Internal</AccessModel>
		<Author>Witte Museum, Gallagher and Associates</Author>
		<Date>6/30/2023</Date>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>We Are Texas: Origin Stories Interpretive Plan</Title>
	</Report>
</Reports>
