<Centers xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="NEH_Centers.xsd">
	<Center ID="3456">
		<ApplicationNumber>CH-51170-14</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A key feature of Illinois College's Preserve+Share+Produce Humanities Initiative is the creation of the Khalaf Al Habtoor Archives within Illinois College's Schewe Library. The College's new archival facility more than triples the previously available archival storage capacity, and adds a spacious, dedicated archival processing area and a research area that allows scholars and researchers to access archival materials. It also provides space for faculty to work on projects with entire classes.</Abstract>
		<Address>1101 West College Avenue&amp;#x0D;
Jacksonville, Illinois 62650</Address>
		<Director>Elizabeth H. Tobin, Provost and Dean of the College, Jan Figa, Library Director</Director>
		<Name>Khalaf Al Habtoor Archives at Illinois College</Name>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.ic.edu/RelId/633055/ISvars/default/Khalaf al Habtoor Archives at Illinois College.htm</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Year>2014</Year>
	</Center>
	<Center ID="3468">
		<ApplicationNumber>CH-50406-07</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The Henry D. Green Center for the Study of the Decorative Arts is part of the Georgia Museum of Art Study Centers in the Humanities, a state-of-the-art facility funded by an NEH Challenge Grant and opened to the public in January 2011.  The Green Center was established at the Georgia Museum of Art (GMOA) in 2000 to address a burgeoning interest in the decorative arts of Georgia and to promote scholarship in this heretofore little-studied area of Georgia's history. The center honors Mr. Green (1909-2003), the acknowledged pioneer in the study and collection of Georgia's decorative arts, furniture in particular. The Green Center conducts original research, which it makes public through exhibitions, publications, symposia, colloquia and workshops; and assists scholars and laypersons who study and investigate the decorative arts. It has established links with colleagues and scholars, including those in other units at the University of Georgia, in the fine arts, historic preservation, sciences, and humanities, as well as with museums, scholars, collectors, and enthusiasts all over the state and beyond.</Abstract>
		<Address>Henry D. Green Center for the Study of the Decorative Arts
Georgia Museum of Art
University of Georgia 
90 Carlton Street
Athens, GA 30602-6719
</Address>
		<Director>William U. Eiland</Director>
		<Name>Henry D. Green Center for the Study of the Decorative Arts</Name>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.georgiamuseum.org</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Website of the Georgia Museum of Art</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>http://georgiamuseum.org/art/collections/green-center</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Description of the Green Center and its collections</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Year>2011</Year>
	</Center>
	<Center ID="3469">
		<ApplicationNumber>CH-50406-07</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Established at the Georgia Museum of Art in 2002 as a gift from Martha Randolph Daura in honor of her father, the Pierre Daura Center contains a collection of paintings, prints, drawings and sculptures by the Catalan-American artist Pierre Daura (1896–1976), who co-founded the important artists' group Cercle et Carré. The gift included the artist's archive, with important material relevant to modern art from the 1920s through the 1960s, and an endowment to support both the center and a Pierre Daura Curator of European Art. This gift facilitates and broadens the presentation and study of European art at the museum.&amp;#x0D; &amp;#x0D; The Daura Center is part of the Georgia Museum of Art Study Centers in the Humanities, with a facility funded by an NEH Challenge Grant that opened in January 2011.&amp;#x0D; </Abstract>
		<Address>Pierre Daura Center&amp;#x0D;
Georgia Museum of Art&amp;#x0D;
University of Georgia&amp;#x0D;
90 Carlton Street&amp;#x0D;
Athens, GA 30602-6719</Address>
		<Director>William U. Eiland, Lynn Edward Boland</Director>
		<Name>Pierre Daura Center</Name>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.georgiamuseum.org</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>The website of the Georgia Museum of Art&amp;#x0D;
</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>http://hmfa.libs.uga.edu/hmfa/view?docId=ead/gmoa001-ead.xml;query=;brand=default</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Link to the finding aid for the Daura Center produced by the Hargrett Rare Book and Manuscript Library, UGA Special Collections&amp;#x0D;
&amp;#x0D;
Also, the museum's web page on the Pierre Daura Center:&amp;#x0D;
&amp;#x0D;
http://georgiamuseum.org/art/collections/daura-center</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Year>2011</Year>
	</Center>
	<Center ID="3470">
		<ApplicationNumber>CH-50406-07</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The Study Centers in the Humanities include the archives of British-American painter and printmaker Gerald Leslie Brockhurst (1890-1978), through an arrangement with the Jacob Burns Foundation.  In 2002, the foundation made a major gift of works by Brockhurst and funding in support of Phase II for the establishment of the Burns Foundation Center for the study of Brockhurst and his contemporaries, including Burns himself.  Jacob Burns (1902-1993), a Russian-born philanthropist, was the lawyer of Gerald Brockhurst, as well as his friend and student.</Abstract>
		<Address>Jacob Burns Foundation Center&amp;#x0D;
Georgia Museum of Art&amp;#x0D;
University of Georgia&amp;#x0D;
90 Carlton Street&amp;#x0D;
Athens, GA 30602</Address>
		<Director>William U. Eiland, Sarah Kate Gillespie, curator of American art</Director>
		<Name>Jacob Burns Foundation Center</Name>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.georgiamuseum.org</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Website of the Georgia Museum of Art</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>http://georgiamuseum.org/art/collections/burns-foundation-collection</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Link to web page on Burns Foundation Center</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Year>2011</Year>
	</Center>
	<Center ID="3789">
		<ApplicationNumber>AC-50002-06</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A center has been created that includes in addition to regular course instruction HSK testing, an annual speech contest, an intensive language summer abroad program, ongoing meetings of the regional Chinese Language Teachers Association, and more.</Abstract>
		<Address/>
		<Director>Li Ma</Director>
		<Name>The Miami-China Connection</Name>
		<PrimaryURL>http://dll.fiu.edu/languages/chinese/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Year>2008</Year>
	</Center>
	<Center ID="14048">
		<ApplicationNumber>CH-51171-14</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>In 2013, the National Endowment for the Humanities awarded the University of California, Berkeley Art Museum and Pacific Film Archive (BAMPFA) a prestigious Challenge Grant in the amount of $2 million. The grant—which required us to raise a 3:1 match—allowed BAMPFA to successfully:  1) furnish and equip the education and study facilities in its new building in downtown Berkeley, which opened in 2016. These spaces include the Helzel Works on Paper Study Center (HWoPSC), Leiber Conceptual Art Study Center (LCASC), Cahill Asian Art Study Center (CAASC), Film Library &amp;amp; Study Center, and a small screening room with a projection booth.  2) endow a new position, Collections Engagement Associate, that plays in important role in increasing awareness and availability of works held in the study centers.   These project outcomes, all of which benefit the UC Berkeley campus, researchers, scholars, and the general public, enhance access to the institution's distinct art and film collections and help advance the important role of the humanities in academic and everyday life.</Abstract>
		<Address>UC Berkeley Art Museum and Pacific Film Archive
2120 Oxford Street #2250
Berkeley, CA 94720-2250</Address>
		<Director>Lawrence Rinder</Director>
		<Name>BAMPFA Study and Education Centers</Name>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Year>2016</Year>
	</Center>
	<Center ID="18112">
		<ApplicationNumber>CZ-50049-04</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This annual report announces the accreditation of the Oberlin Heritage Center/O.H.I.O. by the American Association of Museums.</Abstract>
		<Address/>
		<Director>Patricia Murphy</Director>
		<Name>Oberlin Heritage Center Annual Report for 2005</Name>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.oberlinheritagecenter.org/platform/cms/files/Annual%20Reports/OHC%202005%20ARr.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Link to annual report</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Year>2006</Year>
	</Center>
	<Center ID="18383">
		<ApplicationNumber>CZ-50318-13</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Announcement of a permanent endowment to fund GRCC's Humanities Cultural Center</Abstract>
		<Address/>
		<Director/>
		<Name>Endowment for the Humanities Cultural Center at GRCC</Name>
		<PrimaryURL>http://Green River Community College Report to the Community 2012</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Electronic copy of Green River Community College Report to the Community 2012 promoting that the Jeff Clausen Humanities Fund was being used to fund a permanent endowment for the Humanities Cultural Center at GRCC (p. 10)</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Year>2012</Year>
	</Center>
	<Center ID="18685">
		<ApplicationNumber>CZ-50349-14</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The MWCC Humanities Project was established in 2013 through an NEH Challenge grant as part of a special initiative for two-year colleges.</Abstract>
		<Address/>
		<Director>Michelle Valois</Director>
		<Name>Mount Wachusett Community College Humanities Project</Name>
		<PrimaryURL>https://mwcc.edu/campus-life/humanities-project/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>The homepage for the Humanities Project</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Year>2013</Year>
	</Center>
	<Center ID="18699">
		<ApplicationNumber>CH-51268-15</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This grant supported the creation of an endowment for Mercer University's Center for Southern Studies which would incorporate various pre-existing programs, including the Lamar Lecture series and The Journal of Southern Religion, into a humanities center with dedicated funding.</Abstract>
		<Address/>
		<Director>Dr. Sarah Gardner</Director>
		<Name>Spencer B. King, Jr. Center for Southern Studies Endowment</Name>
		<PrimaryURL>https://kingcenter.mercer.edu/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Website for the Spencer B. King, Jr. Center for Southern Studies highlighting their current programs and staff.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Year>2014</Year>
	</Center>
	<Center ID="19035">
		<ApplicationNumber>CH-233791-16</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This grant helped establish an endowment to support the Free Library of Philadelphia's collaborative community-based projects, now called the Miriam Spector Endowment for the Humanities. It is administered under the library's Division of Cultural and Civic Engagement led by Andrew Nurkin (also the project director for this grant). Although it is not a stand-alone center, it operates similarly by funding these collaborative projects through an endowment.</Abstract>
		<Address/>
		<Director>Andrew Nurkin</Director>
		<Name>Miriam Spector Endowment for the Humanities</Name>
		<PrimaryURL>https://libwww.freelibrary.org/assets/pdf/support/flp-foundation-fy20-development-report.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>This links to the Free Library of Philadelphia's FY2020 Annual Report. Pages 12 &amp;amp; 13 of the report offer information on the Miriam Spector Endowment for the Humanities which was partially funded through this grant.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Year>2017</Year>
	</Center>
	<Center ID="19492">
		<ApplicationNumber>CHA-264431-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>As both a campus showpiece and an active workspace, the new Center for Public Arts and Humanities celebrates our inspiring work in the arts and humanities and cements the campus's international reputation as a leader in the arts and humanities. In both planning and management, it responds to the incredible successes and new programs established by the arts and humanities community over the past five years and meets critical needs that were identified in an all-campus survey and study undertaken by the Arts Administration in 2017. The new center is a place to focus and develop new teaching, research, and creative activity on campus that is multi-disciplinary, public-facing, and socially responsive, dynamic work that is in desperate need of space, visibility, and access, and without a proper home would weaken in significance and impact. By bringing all of our current investments into one space, the center not only signifies our commitment to the arts and humanities at their most socially urgent, but serves as a model for other schools and programs across the world.    Specifically, the new campus center serves as a much-needed home and co-located workspace (with over 40 offices) for three of the campus's most public-facing arts and humanities centers: the Arts and Humanities Council, which is responsible for the First Thursdays Festival, the Global Remixed Festival, and many other successful programs that attract tens of thousands of students each year; the College Arts and Humanities Institute, which supports contemporary research and creative activity as well as oversees dozens of centers and working groups in these areas; and the Center for Rural Engagement, which mobilizes IU's vast resources to aid in the development of rural communities in southern Indiana, particularly through Quality of Place, which focuses on the arts and culture infrastructure of small towns throughout the region. Bringing these dynamic offices together in one place ensures their continued c</Abstract>
		<Address/>
		<Director>Edward P. Dallis-Comentale</Director>
		<Name>Gayle Karch Cook Center for Public Arts and Humanities</Name>
		<PrimaryURL>https://artsandhumanities.indiana.edu/cook-center/index.html</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>A website that provides information about the center, its purpose, partners, and programs.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</Center>
	<Center ID="20315">
		<ApplicationNumber>PY-234444-16</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The NEH Common Heritage grant award helped provide start-up equipment and the time and training for the Clearwater Public Library System to determine the best tools and formats to offer to the public in the Heritage Studio of Community Memory.   Patrons may now utilize the Heritage Studio to digitize their own items, or they may employ the "Memvelope" service to have a limited number of their items digitized by library staff. Patrons must supply their own digital media for conservation.  The Heritage Studio offers stations where patrons can reserve time to digitize a number of formats, including popular home-video formats VHS and Betamax, as well as camcorder formats hi8, MiniDV, and compact VHS-C. Patrons may reserve the Photo Station to batch-scan photographs, or use a special transparency scanner to scan negatives and slides. The Audio Station offers a reel-to-reel audio tape player, as well as vinyl, audio cassette, and microcassette players, all with digitizing capability. Users can make use of three Projector Stations to convert 16 mm, 8 mm, and Super8 films. The Large Format Scanner will scan documents up to 33.5 inches wide and 23 inches tall in order to capture big books, rare newspapers, magazines, large advertising materials, and artwork.  The Heritage Studio of Community Memory is located on the 4th floor of the Clearwater Main Library at 100 North Osceola Avenue in Clearwater, Florida, and is open during library hours and by appointment. The Heritage Studio is open to the public and no library card is needed in order to use the Studio. Library staff are available to get users started and to help solve any technical problems.</Abstract>
		<Address>100 N Osceola Ave
Clearwater, FL 33755</Address>
		<Director>Currently vacant</Director>
		<Name>The Heritage Studio of Community Memory</Name>
		<PrimaryURL>https://myclearwaterlibrary.librarymarket.com/reserve-room/room?room type%5B445%5D=445&amp;amp;op=Apply&amp;amp;form build id=form-VR6sfuMJ7zWPDeVwfGHwsfUKyClPy5UgX36Ut61TPhs&amp;amp;form id=lc reserve by time</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>This is the web page where patrons may get information about the Heritage Studio and what it offers. They can also make reservations to use the equipment from this page.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.myclearwaterlibrary.com/Services/Use-the-Memvelope-Service</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>This is the web page where patrons may get information about the Memvelope service. They can also download the policies and forms required to have items digitized by library staff.</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Year>2017</Year>
	</Center>
	<Center ID="21448">
		<ApplicationNumber>AE-269208-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>During Year #2 of the grant period, a SF Center for Applied Ethics and Humanities was established.  Although a Director has not yet been appointed, Project Director, Ann Thebaut, serves as its Coordinator.  Dr. Thebaut, along with Project Co-Director, Bill Stephenson, presented to SF administration the CAEH Executive Summary and Proposal for Organizational Structure.  Additionally, a CAEH website was created.  See attached document links, which provide an overview of the CAEH mission, as well as a pointer to its website.</Abstract>
		<Address>Santa Fe College
3000 NW 83rd St., B-032B
Gainesville, FL  32606</Address>
		<Director>no Director yet named--Project Director, Ann Thebaut, serves as Coordinator</Director>
		<Name>Santa Fe College Center for Applied Ethics and Humanities</Name>
		<PrimaryURL>https://drive.google.com/file/d/1CBMH7qoVJDVw1LU1Uv8-ugnR17hREja4/view?usp=sharing</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>link to the website for the SF Center for Applied Ethics and Humanities:
https://www.sfcollege.edu/ethics/</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</Center>
	<Center ID="23414">
		<ApplicationNumber>AK-255269-17</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This interdisciplary program was the goal of the grant, It now serves undergraduates at Univ of TX Austin, is robust, very popular, is changing interdisciplinary perspectives involving healthcare, medical humanities and ethics at the university and beyond. It has national influence.</Abstract>
		<Address>The University of Texas at Austin
2501 Whitis Avenue, Carothers Dormitory (CRD) 31
Campus Mail Stop F5025
Austin, TX 78701</Address>
		<Director>Stephen M. Sonnenberg, M.D.</Director>
		<Name>Bridging Disciplines Program Patients, Practitioners, and Cultures of Care</Name>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription/>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Year>2020</Year>
	</Center>
</Centers>
