<OpenAccessItems xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="NEH_OpenAccessItems.xsd">
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22400">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-278091-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Xuanhe Catalogue of Paintings is the first complete translation of the well-known document produced at the court of Emperor Huizong (r. 1100–1125). Dated to 1120, the Catalogue is divided into ten categories of subject matter. Under Daoist and Buddhist Subjects, Figural Subjects, Architecture, Barbarian Tribes, Dragons and Fish, Landscape, Domestic and Wild Animals, Flowers and Birds, Ink Bamboo, and Vegetables and Fruit are biographies of 231 painters, ranging from famous early masters, such as Wu Daozi (ca. 685-758) and Li Cheng (919-967), to otherwise unknown artists of the Song-dynasty court, including fourteen eunuch officials and sixteen male and female members of the royal family. Titles of their pictures held in the palace collection are listed for each artist. These 6,396 paintings testify to the visual culture experienced by viewers of the twelfth century. The author's Introduction analyzes the Catalogue as a source of evidence about the formation of the Song-dynasty palace collection and argues that the majority of its pictures were already in the collection before Huizong's reign, as a result of conquest, confiscation, tribute, gift culture, collecting by earlier emperors, and the production of academy artists and regular officials at the Song court. Under Huizong's reign, around a thousand other pictures were added to the Catalogue through acquisition and reattribution.</Abstract>
		<Author>Amy McNair</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9781501766732</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.cornellpress.cornell.edu/book/9781501766732/xuanhe-catalogue-of-paintings/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Book's page on the Cornell University Press website.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>Cornell University Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Xuanhe Catalogue of Painting</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type/>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2022</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22401">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-278093-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Thomas Mann, winner of the 1929 Nobel Prize in literature and author of such world-renowned novels as Buddenbrooks and The Magic Mountain, began his self-imposed exile in the United States in 1938, having fled his native Germany in the wake of Nazi persecution and public burnings of his books. Mann embraced his role as a public intellectual, deftly using his literary reputation and his connections in an increasingly global publishing industry to refute Nazi propaganda. As Boes shows, Mann undertook successful lecture tours of the country and penned widely-read articles that alerted US audiences and readers to the dangers of complacency in the face of Nazism's existential threat. Spanning four decades, from the eve of World War I, when Mann was first translated into English, to 1952, the year in which he left an America increasingly disfigured by McCarthyism, Boes establishes Mann as a significant figure in the wartime global republic of letters.</Abstract>
		<Author>Tobias Boes</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9781501745010</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.cornellpress.cornell.edu/book/9781501745010/thomas-manns-war/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Book's page on the Cornell University Press website.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>Cornell University Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Thomas Mann's War: Literature, Politics, and the World Republic of Letters</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22402">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-278092-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>In More Than Medals, Dennis J. Frost answers this question and addresses the histories of individuals, institutions, and events—the 1964 Paralympics, the FESPIC Games, the Oita International Wheelchair Marathon, the Nagano Winter Paralympics, and the 2021 Tokyo Summer Games that played important roles in the development of disability sports in Japan. Sporting events in the postwar era, Frost shows, have repeatedly served as forums for addressing the concerns of individuals with disabilities. More Than Medals provides new insights on the cultural and historical nature of disability and demonstrates how sporting events have challenged some stigmas associated with disability, while reinforcing or generating others. Frost analyzes institutional materials and uses close readings of media, biographical sources, and interviews with Japanese athletes to highlight the profound—though often ambiguous—ways in which sports have shaped how postwar Japan has perceived and addressed disability. His novel approach highlights the importance of the Paralympics and the impact that disability sports have had on Japanese society.</Abstract>
		<Author>Dennis J. Frost</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9781501753091</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.cornellpress.cornell.edu/book/9781501753091/more-than-medals/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Book's page on the Cornell University Press</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>Cornell University Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>More than Medals: A History of the Paralympics and Disability Sports in Postwar Japan</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type/>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2022</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22406">
		<ApplicationNumber>AC-264295-19</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Edited collection of best practices in oral history.</Abstract>
		<Author>Kirsten E. Gardner and Valerie Martinez</Author>
		<Editor>Kirsten E. Gardner and Valerie Martinez</Editor>
		<ISBN>none</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>http://rrpress.utsa.edu/handle/20.500.12588/1087</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>https://rrpress.utsa.edu/handle/20.500.12588/1087

Essays, Podcasts, and Video tips on oral history.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>Roadrunner Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Women's Voices of Military City, USA</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type/>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2022</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22487">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-278009-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>When American forces arrived in Vietnam, they found themselves embedded in historic village and frontier spaces already shaped by many past conflicts. American bases and bombing targets followed spatial and political logics influenced by the footprints of past wars in central Vietnam. The militarized landscapes here, like many in the world's historic conflict zones, continue to shape post-war land-use politics.  Footprints of War traces the long history of conflict-produced spaces in Vietnam, beginning with early modern wars and the French colonial invasion in 1885 and continuing through the collapse of the Saigon government in 1975. The result is a richly textured history of militarized landscapes that reveals the spatial logic of key battles such as the Tet Offensive.  Drawing on extensive archival work and years of interviews and fieldwork in the hills and villages around the city of Hue to illuminate war's footprints, David Biggs also integrates historical Geographic Information Systems (GIS) data, using aerial, high-altitude, and satellite imagery to render otherwise placeless sites into living, multidimensional spaces. This personal and multilayered approach yields an innovative history of the lasting traces of war in Vietnam and a model for understanding other militarized landscapes.</Abstract>
		<Author>David Biggs</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9780295743875</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://uw.manifoldapp.org/projects/footprints-of-war</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Open Access eBook of Footprints of War</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University of Washington Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctvcwnk0c</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Footprints of War on JSTOR</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Footprints of War: Militarized Landscapes in Vietnam</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type/>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2022</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22504">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-272401-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>In 1933, John A. Lomax and his son Alan set out as emissaries for the Library of Congress to record the folksong of the "American Negro" in several southern African American prisons. Listening to the Lomax Archive: The Sonic Rhetorics of African American Folksong in the 1930s asks how the Lomaxes' field recordings—including their prison recordings and a long-form oral history of jazz musician Jelly Roll Morton—contributed to a new mythology of Americana for a nation in the midst of financial, social, and identity crises. Stone argues that folksongs communicate complex historical experiences in a seemingly simple package, and can thus be a key element—a sonic rhetoric—for interpreting the ebb and flow of cultural ideals within contemporary historical moments. He contends that the Lomaxes, aware of the power of folk music, used the folksongs they collected to increase national understanding of and agency for the subjects of their recordings even as they used the recordings to advance their own careers. Listening to the Lomax Archive gives readers the opportunity to listen in on these seemingly contradictory dualities, demonstrating that they are crucial to the ways that we remember and write about the subjects of the Lomaxes' archive and other repositories of historicized sound.</Abstract>
		<Author>Jonathan W. Stone</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9780472902446</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.fulcrum.org/concern/monographs/v405sc60h</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Open Access eBook of Listening to the Lomax Archive</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University of Michigan Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://library.oapen.org/handle/20.500.12657/51246</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Listening to the Lomax Archive in OAOpen</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Listening to the Lomax Archive: The Sonic Rhetorics of American Folksong in the 1930s</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22505">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-280110-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Children and Drug Safety traces the development, use, and marketing of drugs for children in the twentieth century, a history that sits at the interface of the state, business, health care providers, parents, and children. This book illuminates the historical dimension of a clinical and policy issue with great contemporary significance—many of the drugs administered to children today have never been tested for safety and efficacy in the pediatric population.   Each chapter of Children and Drug Safety engages with major turning points in pediatric drug development; themes of children's risk, rights, protection and the evolving context of childhood; child-rearing; and family life in ways freighted with nuances of race, class, and gender. Cynthia A. Connolly charts the numerous attempts by Congress, the Food and Drug Administration, the American Academy of Pediatrics, and leading pediatric pharmacologists, scientists, clinicians, and parents to address a situation that all found untenable.</Abstract>
		<Author>Cynthia A. Connolly</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9780813563893</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.rutgersuniversitypress.org/children-and-drug-safety/9780813563893</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Redirect to Rutgers University Press dedicated landed page for Chiildren and Drug Safety, by Cynthia A. Connolly</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>Rutgers University Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Children and Drug Safety: Balancing Risk and Protection in Twentieth-Century America</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2018</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22506">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-280113-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>About This Book Embracing Age: How Catholic Nuns Became Models of Aging Well examines a community of individuals whose aging trajectories contrast mainstream American experiences. In mainstream American society, aging is presented as a "problem," a state to be avoided as long as possible, a state that threatens one's ability to maintain independence, autonomy, control over one's surroundings. Aging "well" (or avoiding aging) has become a twenty-first century American preoccupation. Embracing Age provides a window into the everyday lives of American Catholic nuns who experience longevity and remarkable health and well-being at the end of life. Catholic nuns aren't only healthier in older age, they are healthier because they practice a culture of acceptance and grace around aging. Embracing Age demonstrates how aging in the convent becomes understood by the nuns to be a natural part of the life course, not one to be feared or avoided. Anna I. Corwin shows readers how Catholic nuns create a cultural community that provides a model for how to grow old, decline, and die that is both embedded in American culture and quite distinct from other American models.</Abstract>
		<Author>Anna I. Corwin</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9781978822313</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.rutgersuniversitypress.org/embracing-age/9781978822276</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>URL that links to the book page on the Rutgers University Press site, where the ebook can be downloaded gratis.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>Rutgers University Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Embracing Age: How Catholic Nuns Became Models of Aging Well</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22507">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-272623-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Female seminaries in the nineteenth-century United States offered middle-class women the rare privilege of training in music and the liberal arts. A music background in particular provided the foundation for a teaching career, one of the few paths open to women. Jewel A. Smith opens the doors of four female seminaries, revealing a milieu where rigorous training focused on music as an artistic pursuit rather than a social skill. Drawing on previously untapped archives, Smith charts women's musical experiences and training as well as the curricula and instruction available to them, the repertoire they mastered, and the philosophies undergirding their education. She also examines the complex tensions between the ideals of a young democracy and a deeply gendered system of education and professional advancement.  An in-depth study of female seminaries as major institutions of learning, Transforming Women's Education illuminates how musical training added to women's lives and how their artistic acumen contributed to American society.</Abstract>
		<Author>Jewel Smith</Author>
		<Editor>none</Editor>
		<ISBN>978-0-252-0532</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.5406/j.ctv26xfvq4</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Open access edition on JSTOR</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University of Illinois Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://muse.jhu.edu/book/63938</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Open access edition on Project MUSE</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Transforming Women’s Education: Liberal Arts and Music in Female Seminaries</Title>
		<Translator>none</Translator>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2022</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22534">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-278085-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Countess Sofia Panina lived a remarkable life. Born into an aristocratic family in imperial Russia, she found her true calling in improving the lives of urban workers. Her passion for social service and reputation as the "Red Countess" led her to political prominence after the fall of the Romanovs. She became the first woman to hold a cabinet position and the first political prisoner tried by the Bolsheviks. The upheavals of the 1917 Revolution forced her to flee her beloved country, but instead of living a quiet life in exile she devoted the rest of her long life to humanitarian efforts on behalf of fellow refugees.  Based on Adele Lindenmeyr's detailed research in dozens of archival collections, 'Citizen Countess' establishes Sofia Panina as an astute eyewitness to and passionate participant in the historical events that shaped her life. Her experiences shed light on the evolution of the European nobility, women's emancipation and political influence of the time, and the fate of Russian liberalism.</Abstract>
		<Author>Adele Lindenmeyr</Author>
		<Editor>Nathan MacBrien</Editor>
		<ISBN>9780299325381</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://worldcat.org/title/1090280620</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>WorldCat</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University of Wisconsin Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://uwpress.wisc.edu/books/5844.htm</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>UW Press main book page
[[[DENNIS: NO OA LINK AVAILABLE YET]]</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Citizen Countess: Sofia Panina and the Fate of Revolutionary Russia</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2022</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22508">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-280049-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The Other/Argentina looks at literature, film, and the visual arts to examine the threads of Jewishness that create patterns of meaning within the fabric of Argentine self-representation. A multiethnic yet deeply Roman Catholic country, Argentina has worked mightily to fashion itself as a modern nation. In so doing, it has grappled with the paradox of Jewishness, emblematic both of modernity and of the lingering traces of the premodern. By the same token, Jewishness is woven into, but also other to, Argentineity. Consequently, books, movies, and art that reflect on Jewishness play a significant role in shaping Argentina's cultural landscape. In the process they necessarily inscribe, and sometimes confound, norms of gender and sexuality. Just as Jewishness seeps into Argentina, Argentina's history, politics, and culture mark Jewishness and alter its meaning. The feminized body of the Jewish male, for example, is deeply rooted in Western tradition; but the stigmatized body of the Jewish prostitute and the lacerated body of the Jewish torture victim acquire particular significance in Argentina. Furthermore, Argentina's iconic Jewish figures include not only the peddler and the scholar, but also the Jewish gaucho and the urban mobster, troubling conventional readings of Jewish masculinity. As it searches for threads of Jewishness, richly imbued with the complexities of gender and sexuality, The Other/Argentina explores the patterns those threads weave, however overtly or subtly, into the fabric of Argentine national meaning, especially at such critical moments in Argentine history as the period of massive state-sponsored immigration, the rise of labor and anarchist movements, the Perón era, and the 1976–83 dictatorship. In arguing that Jewishness is an essential element of Argentina's self-fashioning as a modern nation, the book shifts the focus in Latin American Jewish studies from Jewish identity to the meaning of Jewishness for the nation.</Abstract>
		<Author>Amy K. Kaminsky</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9781438483290</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>http://hdl.handle.net/20.500.12648/1711</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>This is the Open Access repository site for the State University of New York</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>SUNY Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://sunypress.edu/Books/T/The-Other-Argentina2</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>SUNY Press website</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>The Other/Argentina: Jews, Gender, and Sexuality in the Making of a Modern Nation</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22509">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-278094-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>An examination of successful environmental advocacy strategies in East Asia that shows how advocacy can be effective under difficult conditions.</Abstract>
		<Author>Mary Alice Haddad</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9780262363426</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://direct.mit.edu/books/book/5090/Effective-AdvocacyLessons-from-East-Asia-s</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Landing page at MIT Press website</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>MIT Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://doi.org/10.7551/mitpress/13475.001.0001</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Redirects to MIT Press website</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Effective Advocacy: Lessons from East Asia's Environmentalists</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22510">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-280048-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Death Rights presents an antiracist critique of British romanticism by deconstructing one of its organizing tropes—the suicidal creative "genius." Putting texts by Olaudah Equiano, Mary Shelley, John Keats, and others into critical conversation with African American literature, black studies, and feminist theory, Deanna P. Koretsky argues that romanticism is part and parcel of the legal and philosophical discourses underwriting liberal modernity's antiblack foundations. Read in this context, the trope of romantic suicide serves a distinct political function, indexing the limits of liberal subjectivity and (re)inscribing the rights and freedoms promised by liberalism as the exclusive province of white men. The first book-length study of suicide in British romanticism, Death Rights also points to the enduring legacy of romantic ideals in the academy and contemporary culture more broadly. Koretsky challenges scholars working in historically Eurocentric fields to rethink their identification with epistemes rooted in antiblackness. And, through discussions of recent cultural touchstones such as Kurt Cobain's resurgence in hip-hop and Victor LaValle's comic book sequel to Frankenstein, Koretsky provides all readers with a trenchant analysis of how eighteenth-century ideas about suicide continue to routinize antiblackness in the modern world. Print versions available for purchase at https://sunypress.edu/Books/D/Death-Rights</Abstract>
		<Author>Deanna P. Koretsky</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9781438482897</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://soar.suny.edu/handle/20.500.12648/1712</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>SUNY content repository</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>SUNY Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://sunypress.edu/Books/D/Death-Rights</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>SUNY Press website</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Death Rights: Romantic Suicide, Race, and the Bounds of Liberalism</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22511">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-272616-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>In Cut/Copy/Paste, Whitney Trettien journeys to the fringes of the London print trade to uncover makerspaces and collaboratories where paper media were cut up and reassembled into radical, bespoke publications. Bringing these long-forgotten objects back to life through hand-curated digital resources, Trettien shows how early experimental book hacks speak to the contemporary conditions of digital scholarship and publishing. As a mixed-media artifact itself, Cut/Copy/Paste enacts for readers what Trettien argues: that digital forms have the potential to decenter patriarchal histories of print.  From the religious household of Little Gidding—whose biblical concordances and manuscripts exemplify protofeminist media innovation—to the queer poetic assemblages of Edward Benlowes and the fragment albums of former shoemaker John Bagford, Cut/Copy/Paste demonstrates history's relevance to our understanding of current media. Tracing the lives and afterlives of amateur "bookwork," Trettien creates a method for identifying and comprehending hybrid objects that resist familiar bibliographic and literary categories. In the process, she bears witness to the deep history of radical publishing with fragments and found materials.  With many of Cut/Copy/Paste's digital resources left thrillingly open for additions and revisions, this book reimagines our ideas of publication while fostering a spirit of generosity and inclusivity. An open invitation to cut, copy, and paste different histories, it is an inspiration for students of publishing or the digital humanities, as well as anyone interested in the past, present, and future of creativity.</Abstract>
		<Author>Whitney Trettien</Author>
		<Editor>Douglas Armato</Editor>
		<ISBN>9781517904098</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.upress.umn.edu/book-division/books/cut-copy-paste</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Link to the book on the University of Minnesota Press website</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University of Minnesota Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>http://https://manifold.umn.edu/projects/cut-copy-paste</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Link to the book on the Manifold website.</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Cut/Copy/Paste: Fragments from the History of Bookwork</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2022</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22512">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-272610-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>If you were an independent, adventurous, liberated American woman in the 1920s or 1930s where might you have sought escape from the constraints and compromises of bourgeois living? Paris and the Left Bank quickly come to mind. But would you have ever thought of Russia and the wilds of Siberia? This choice was not as unusual as it seems now. As Julia L. Mickenberg uncovers in American Girls in Red Russia, there is a forgotten counterpoint to the story of the Lost Generation: beginning in the late nineteenth century, Russian revolutionary ideology attracted many women, including suffragists, reformers, educators, journalists, and artists, as well as curious travelers. Some were famous, like Isadora Duncan or Lillian Hellman; some were committed radicals, though more were just intrigued by the "Soviet experiment." But all came to Russia in search of social arrangements that would be more equitable, just, and satisfying. And most in the end were disillusioned, some by the mundane realities, others by horrifying truths.  Mickenberg reveals the complex motives that drew American women to Russia as they sought models for a revolutionary new era in which women would be not merely independent of men, but also equal builders of a new society. Soviet women, after all, earned the right to vote in 1917, and they also had abortion rights, property rights, the right to divorce, maternity benefits, and state-supported childcare. Even women from Soviet national minorities—many recently unveiled—became public figures, as African American and Jewish women noted. Yet as Mickenberg's collective biography shows, Russia turned out to be as much a grim commune as a utopia of freedom, replete with economic, social, and sexual inequities.</Abstract>
		<Author>Julia L. Mickenberg</Author>
		<Editor>Timothy Mennel</Editor>
		<ISBN>9780226256269</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>http://bibliopen.org/p/bopen/9780226256269</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Open-access landing page</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>The University of Chicago Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>http://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/A/bo20098421.html</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>University of Chicago Press product page</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>American Girls in Red Russia: Chasing the Soviet Dream [Open-access ebook edition]</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2022</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22513">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-272611-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Drive the streets of Nairobi, and you are sure to see many matatus—colorful minibuses that transport huge numbers of people around the city. Once ramshackle affairs held together with duct tape and wire, matatus today are name-brand vehicles maxed out with aftermarket detailing. They can be stately black or extravagantly colored, sporting names, slogans, or entire tableaus, with airbrushed portraits of everyone from Kanye West to Barack Obama. In this richly interdisciplinary book, Kenda Mutongi explores the history of the matatu from the 1960s to the present.             As Mutongi shows, matatus offer a window onto the socioeconomic and political conditions of late-twentieth-century Africa. In their diversity of idiosyncratic designs, they reflect multiple and divergent aspects of Kenyan life—including, for example, rapid urbanization, organized crime, entrepreneurship, social insecurity, the transition to democracy, and popular culture—at once embodying Kenya's staggering social problems as well as the bright promises of its future. Offering a shining model of interdisciplinary analysis, Mutongi mixes historical, ethnographic, literary, linguistic, and economic approaches to tell the story of the matatu and explore the entrepreneurial aesthetics of the postcolonial world.</Abstract>
		<Author>Kenda Mutongi</Author>
		<Editor>David Brent, David Brent/Priya S. Nelson</Editor>
		<ISBN>9780226471426</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>http://bibliopen.org/p/bopen/9780226471426</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Open-access edition landing page</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>The University of Chicago Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>http://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/M/bo17847525.html</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>University of Chicago Press product page</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Matatu: A History of Popular Transportation in Nairobi [Open-access ebook edition]</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2022</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22514">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-272612-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Weather control. Juxtaposing those two words is enough to raise eyebrows in a world where even the best weather models still fail to nail every forecast, and when the effects of climate change on sea level height, seasonal averages of weather phenomena, and biological behavior are being watched with interest by all, regardless of political or scientific persuasion. But between the late nineteenth century—when the United States first funded an attempt to "shock" rain out of clouds—and the late 1940s, rainmaking (as it had been known) became weather control. And then things got out of control.  In Make It Rain, Kristine C. Harper tells the long and somewhat ludicrous history of state-funded attempts to manage, manipulate, and deploy the weather in America. Harper shows that governments from the federal to the local became helplessly captivated by the idea that weather control could promote agriculture, health, industrial output, and economic growth at home, or even be used as a military weapon and diplomatic tool abroad. Clear fog for landing aircraft? There's a project for that. Gentle rain for strawberries? Let's do it! Enhanced snowpacks for hydroelectric utilities? Check. The heyday of these weather control programs came during the Cold War, as the atmosphere came to be seen as something to be defended, weaponized, and manipulated. Yet Harper demonstrates that today there are clear implications for our attempts to solve the problems of climate change.</Abstract>
		<Author>Kristine C. Harper</Author>
		<Editor>Timothy Mennel</Editor>
		<ISBN>9780226437378</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>http://bibliopen.org/p/bopen/9780226437378</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Open access landing page</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>The University of Chicago Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/M/bo25338705.htmlhttp://</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>University of Chicago product page</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Make It Rain: State Control of the Atmosphere in Twentieth-Century America [Open-access ebook edition]</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2022</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22515">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-278065-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Lincoln's somber portraits. Lyndon Johnson's swearing in. George W. Bush's reaction to learning about the 9/11 attacks. Photography plays an indelible role in how we remember and define American presidents. Throughout history, presidents have actively participated in all aspects of photography, not only by sitting for photos but by taking and consuming them. Cara A. Finnegan ventures from a newly-discovered daguerreotype of John Quincy Adams to Barack Obama's selfies to tell the stories of how presidents have participated in the medium's transformative moments. As she shows, technological developments not only changed photography, but introduced new visual values that influence how we judge an image. At the same time, presidential photographs—as representations of leaders who symbolized the nation—sparked public debate on these values and their implications. An original journey through political history, Photographic Presidents reveals the intertwined evolution of an American institution and a medium that continues to define it.</Abstract>
		<Author>Cara A. Finnegan</Author>
		<Editor>N/A</Editor>
		<ISBN>e ISNB 9780252</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.jstor.org/stable/10.5406/j.ctv1k03sbn</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Open access edition on the JSTOR platform.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University of Illinois Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://muse.jhu.edu/book/83119</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Open access in addition on the Project MUSE platform.</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Photographic Presidents: Making History from Dageurreotype to Digital</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22516">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-272593-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Imagined Homelands chronicles the emerging cultures of nineteenth-century British settler colonialism, focusing on poetry as a genre especially equipped to reflect colonial experience. Jason Rudy argues that the poetry of Victorian-era Australia, New Zealand, South Africa, and Canada—often disparaged as derivative and uncouth—should instead be seen as vitally engaged in the social and political work of settlement. The book illuminates cultural pressures that accompanied the unprecedented growth of British emigration across the nineteenth century. It also explores the role of poetry as a mediator between familiar British ideals and new colonial paradigms within emerging literary markets from Sydney and Melbourne to Cape Town and Halifax.   Rudy focuses on the work of poets both canonical—including Tennyson, Browning, Longfellow, and Hemans—and relatively obscure, from Adam Lindsay Gordon, Susanna Moodie, and Thomas Pringle to Henry Kendall and Alexander McLachlan. He examines in particular the nostalgic relations between home and abroad, core and periphery, whereby British emigrants used both original compositions and canonical British works to imagine connections between their colonial experiences and the lives they left behind in Europe.  Drawing on archival work from four continents, Imagined Homelands insists on a wider geographic frame for nineteenth-century British literature. From lyrics printed in newspapers aboard emigrant ships heading to Australia and South Africa, to ballads circulating in New Zealand and Canadian colonial journals, poetry was a vibrant component of emigrant life. In tracing the histories of these poems and the poets who wrote them, this book provides an alternate account of nineteenth-century British poetry and, more broadly, of settler colonial culture.</Abstract>
		<Author>Jason R. Rudy</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9781421441252</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://muse.jhu.edu/book/56466</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Project MUSE</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>Johns Hopkins University Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.press.jhu.edu/books/title/11058/imagined-homelands</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Hopkins Press</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Imagined Homelands: British Poetry in the Colonies</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22517">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-272592-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Richard C. Sha argues that scientific understandings of the imagination indelibly shaped literary Romanticism. Challenging the idea that the imagination found a home only on the side of the literary, as a mental vehicle for transcending the worldly materials of the sciences, Sha shows how imagination helped to operationalize both scientific and literary discovery. Essentially, the imagination forced writers to consider the difference between what was possible and impossible while thinking about how that difference could be known.   Sha examines how the imagination functioned within physics and chemistry in Percy Bysshe Shelley's Prometheus Unbound, neurology in Blake's Vala, or The Four Zoas, physiology in Coleridge's Biographia Literaria, and obstetrics and embryology in Mary Shelley's Frankenstein. He also demonstrates how the imagination was called upon to do aesthetic and scientific work using primary examples taken from the work of scientists and philosophers Davy, Dalton, Faraday, Priestley, Kant, Mary Somerville, Oersted, Marcet, Smellie, Swedenborg, Blumenbach, Buffon, Erasmus Darwin, and Von Baer, among others.   Sha concludes that both fields benefited from thinking about how imagination could cooperate with reason—but that this partnership was impossible unless imagination's penchant for fantasy could be contained.</Abstract>
		<Author>Richard C. Sha</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9781421441245</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://muse.jhu.edu/book/59664</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Project MUSE</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>Johns Hopkins University Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.press.jhu.edu/books/title/11451/imagination-and-science-romanticism</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Hopkins Press</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Imagination and Science in Romanticism</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22518">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-280005-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>What drove U.S. Catholics in their arduous quest, full of twists and turns over more than a century, to win an American saint? The absence of American names in the canon of the saints had left many of the faithful feeling spiritually unmoored. But while canonization may be fundamentally about holiness, it is never only about holiness, reveals Kathleen Sprows Cummings in this panoramic, passionate chronicle of American sanctity. Catholics had another reason for petitioning the Vatican to acknowledge an American holy hero. A home-grown saint would serve as a mediator between heaven and earth, yes, but also between Catholicism and American culture. Throughout much of U.S. history, the making of a saint was also about the ways in which the members of a minority religious group defined, defended, and celebrated their identities as Americans. Their fascinatingly diverse causes for canonization—from Kateri Tekakwitha and Elizabeth Ann Seton to many others that are failed, forgotten, or still under way—represented evolving national values as Catholics made themselves at home. Cummings's vision of American sanctity shows just how much Catholics had at stake in cultivating devotion to men and women perched at the nexus of holiness and American history—until they finally felt little need to prove that they belonged.</Abstract>
		<Author>Kathleen Sprows Cummings</Author>
		<Editor>Elaine Maisner</Editor>
		<ISBN>978-1-4696-494</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://uncpress.org/book/9781469665535/a-saint-of-our-own/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>UNC Press Description Page</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University of North Carolina Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.amazon.com/Saint-Our-Own-Catholics-American-ebook/dp/B07H51658M/ref=sr 1 1?keywords=9781469649481&amp;amp;qid=1551300115&amp;amp;s=digital-text&amp;amp;sr=1-1</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Amazon Kindle Edition</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>A Saint of Our Own: How the Quest for a Holy Hero Helped Catholics Become American</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3>https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/a-saint-of-our-own-kathleen-sprows-cummings/1129483505?ean=9781469649481#/</URL3>
		<URL3Description>Barnes &amp;amp; Noble Nook Edition</URL3Description>
		<URL4>https://muse.jhu.edu/book/63996</URL4>
		<URL4Description>Project Muse Edition</URL4Description>
		<URL5>https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.5149/9781469649498 cummings</URL5>
		<URL5Description>JSTOR Edition</URL5Description>
		<Year>2019</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22522">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-280007-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>More than 150 years after its end, we still struggle to understand the full extent of the human toll of the Civil War and the psychological crisis it created. In Aberration of Mind, Diane Miller Sommerville offers the first book-length treatment of suicide in the South during the Civil War era, giving us insight into both white and black communities, Confederate soldiers and their families, as well as the enslaved and newly freed. With a thorough examination of the dynamics of both racial and gendered dimensions of psychological distress, Sommerville reveals how the suffering experienced by Southerners living in a war zone generated trauma that, in extreme cases, led some Southerners to contemplate or act on suicidal thoughts. Sommerville recovers previously hidden stories of individuals exhibiting suicidal activity or aberrant psychological behavior she links to the war and its aftermath. This work adds crucial nuance to our understanding of how personal suffering shaped the way southerners viewed themselves in the Civil War era and underscores the full human costs of war.</Abstract>
		<Author>Diane Miller Sommerville</Author>
		<Editor>Chuck Grench</Editor>
		<ISBN>978-1-4696-435</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://uncpress.org/book/9781469643304/aberration-of-mind/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>UNC Press Description Page</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University of North Carolina Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.amazon.com/Aberration-Mind-Suicide-Suffering-War-Era-ebook/dp/B07BB5W66G/ref=sr 1 1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1537989381&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=9781469643571</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Amazon Kindle Edition</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Aberration of Mind: Suicide and Suffering in the Civil War–Era South</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3>https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/aberration-of-mind-diane-miller-sommerville/1128220028?ean=9781469643571</URL3>
		<URL3Description>Barnes &amp;amp; Noble Nook Edition</URL3Description>
		<URL4>https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.5149/9781469643588 sommerville?item view=book info</URL4>
		<URL4Description>JSTOR Edition</URL4Description>
		<URL5>https://muse.jhu.edu/book/61411</URL5>
		<URL5Description>Project Muse Edition</URL5Description>
		<Year>2018</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22526">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-280008-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>White working-class conservatives have played a decisive role in American history, particularly in their opposition to social justice movements, radical critiques of capitalism, and government help for the poor and sick. While this pattern is largely seen as a post-1960s development, Poor Man's Fortune tells a different story, excavating the long history of white working-class conservatism in the century from the Civil War to World War II. With a close study of metal miners in the Tri-State district of Kansas, Missouri, and Oklahoma, Jarod Roll reveals why successive generations of white, native-born men willingly and repeatedly opposed labor unions and government-led health and safety reforms, even during the New Deal. With painstaking research, Roll shows how the miners' choices reflected a deep-seated, durable belief that hard-working American white men could prosper under capitalism, and exposes the grim costs of this view for these men and their communities, for organized labor, and for political movements seeking a more just and secure society. Roll's story shows how American inequalities are in part the result of a white working-class conservative tradition driven by grassroots assertions of racial, gendered, and national privilege.</Abstract>
		<Author>Jarod Roll</Author>
		<Editor>Brandon Proia</Editor>
		<ISBN>978-1-4696-563</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://uncpress.org/book/9781469656298/poor-mans-fortune/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>UNC Press Description Page</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University of North Carolina Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.amazon.com/Poor-Mans-Fortune-Working-Class-Conservatism-ebook/dp/B07XDDJJH9/ref=sr 1 1?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=9781469656304&amp;amp;qid=1586808925&amp;amp;s=digital-text&amp;amp;sr=1-1</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Amazon Kindle Edition</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Poor Man's Fortune: White Working-Class Conservatism in American Metal Mining, 1850–1950</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3>https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/poor-mans-fortune-jarod-roll/1133382774?ean=9781469656304</URL3>
		<URL3Description>Nook Edition</URL3Description>
		<URL4>https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.5149/9781469656311 roll</URL4>
		<URL4Description>JSTOR edition</URL4Description>
		<URL5>https://muse.jhu.edu/book/74161</URL5>
		<URL5Description>Project Muse edition</URL5Description>
		<Year>2020</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22530">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-284952-22</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A vexed figure inhabits U.S. literature and culture: the visibly racialized immigrant who disavows minority identity and embraces the American dream. Such figures are potent and controversial, for they promise to expiate racial violence and perpetuate an exceptionalist ideal of America. Swati Rana grapples with these figures, building on studies of literary character and racial form. Rana offers a new way to view characterization through racialization that creates a fuller social reading of race. Situated in a nascent period of ethnic identification from 1900 to 1960, this book focuses on immigrant writers who do not fit neatly into a resistance-based model of ethnic literature. Writings by Paule Marshall, Ameen Rihani, Dalip Singh Saund, José Garcia Villa, and José Antonio Villarreal symbolize different aspects of the American dream, from individualism to imperialism, assimilation to upward mobility. The dynamics of characterization are also those of contestation, Rana argues. Analyzing the interrelation of persona and personhood, Race Characters presents an original method of comparison, revealing how the protagonist of the American dream is socially constrained and structurally driven.</Abstract>
		<Author>Swati Rana</Author>
		<Editor>Lucas Church</Editor>
		<ISBN>978-1-4696-594</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://uncpress.org/book/9781469659473/race-characters/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>UNC Press Description Page</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University of North Carolina Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.amazon.com/Race-Characters-Ethnic-Literature-American-ebook/dp/B086GJY975/ref=sr 1 1?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=9781469659480&amp;amp;qid=1602008967&amp;amp;s=digital-text&amp;amp;sr=1-1</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Amazon Kindle Edition</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Race Characters: Ethnic Literature and the Figure of the American Dream</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3>https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/race-characters-swati-rana/1136746126?ean=9781469659480</URL3>
		<URL3Description>Barnes &amp;amp; Noble Nook Edition</URL3Description>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2020</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22532">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-279980-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Pauulu's Diaspora is a sweeping story of black internationalism across the Atlantic, Indian, and Pacific Ocean worlds, told through the life and work of twentieth-century environmental activist Pauulu Kamarakafego. Challenging U.S.-centered views of Black Power, Quito Swan offers a radically broader perspective, showing how Kamarakafego helped connect liberation efforts of the African diaspora throughout the Global South.    ?Born in Bermuda and with formative experiences in Cuba, Kamarakafego was aware at an early age of the effects of colonialism and the international scope of racism and segregation. After pursuing graduate studies in ecological engineering, he traveled to Africa, where he was inspired by the continent's independence struggles and contributed to various sustainable development movements. Swan explores Kamarakafego's remarkable fusion of political agitation and scientific expertise and traces his emergence as a central coordinator of major black internationalist conferences. Despite government surveillance, Kamarakafego built a network of black organizers that reached from Kenya to the islands of Oceania and included such figures as C. L. R. James, Queen Mother Audley Moore, Kwame Nkrumah, Sonia Sanchez, Sylvia Hill, Malcolm X, Vanessa Griffen, and Stokely Carmichael.  In a riveting narrative that runs through Caribbean sugarcane fields, Liberian rubber plantations, and Papua New Guinean rainforests, Pauulu's Diaspora recognizes a global leader who has largely been absent from scholarship. In doing so, it brings to light little-known relationships among Black Power, pan-Africanism, and environmental justice.</Abstract>
		<Author>Quito J. Swan</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9780813070032</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://upf.com/book.asp?id=9780813066417</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>This is the book's page on the publisher website, containing bibliographic data, blurbs, awards, and an abstract. It also links to directly to the Open Access edition on the University of Florida Digital Repository.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University Press of Florida</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://dloc.com/AA00082286/00001/pdf/0</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>This is a direct link to the Open Access edition posted on the University of Florida Digital Repository.</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Pauulu's Diaspora: Black Internationalism and Environmental Justice</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22533">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-279990-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Hardworking actor, playwright, and stage manager Harry Watkins (1825–94) was also a prolific diarist. For fifteen years Watkins regularly recorded the plays he saw, the roles he performed, the books he read, and his impressions of current events. Performing across the U.S., Watkins collaborated with preeminent performers and producers, recording his successes and failures as well as his encounters with celebrities such as P. T. Barnum, Junius Brutus Booth, Edwin Forrest, Anna Cora Mowatt, and Lucy Stone. His is the only known diary of substantial length and scope written by a U.S. actor before the Civil War—making Watkins, essentially, the antebellum equivalent of Samuel Pepys. Theater historians Amy E. Hughes and Naomi J. Stubbs have selected, edited, and annotated excerpts from the diary in an edition that offers a vivid glimpse of how ordinary people like Watkins lived, loved, struggled, and triumphed during one of the most tumultuous periods in U.S. history.</Abstract>
		<Author>Harry Watkins</Author>
		<Editor>Edited by Amy L. Hughes and Naomi J. Stubbs</Editor>
		<ISBN>9780472902613</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://worldcat.org/search?q=A+Player+and+a+Gentleman</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Worldcat.org listing for A Player and a Gentleman</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University of Michigan Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.press.umich.edu/9290953/player and a gentleman</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Publisher webpage for A Player and a Gentleman</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>A Player and a Gentleman: The Diary of Harry Watkins, Nineteenth - Century U.S. American Actor</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Scholarly Edition</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22549">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-272597-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Covering the period from 1915 to the present, The Rise of Euroskepticism examines the role that artists and intellectuals have played in projects of European integration. Using Spain as a case study, Martín-Estudillo explores the ways in which countries on the Continent understand themselves as European or not and how that perception changes over time.</Abstract>
		<Author>Luis Martín-Estudillo</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.vanderbilt.edu/university-press/the-rise-of-euroskepticism-open-access.pdf</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Open Access PDF</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>Vanderbilt University Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctv1675bt7</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>The open-access edition published on JSTOR</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>The Rise of Euroskepticism: Europe and Its Critics in Spanish Culture</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3>https://muse.jhu.edu/book/58300</URL3>
		<URL3Description>The open-access edition hosted on Project MUSE</URL3Description>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2020</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22550">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-272609-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>"See yourself in the movies!" Prior to the advent of the home movie camera and the ubiquitousness of the camera phone, there was the local film. This cultural phenomenon, produced across the country from the 1890s to the 1950s, gave ordinary people a chance to be on the silver screen without leaving their hometowns. Through these movies, residents could see themselves in the same theaters where they saw major Hollywood motion pictures. Traveling filmmakers plied their trade in small towns and cities, where these films were received by locals as being part of the larger cinema experience. With access to the rare film clips under discussion, Main Street Movies documents the diversity and longevity of local film production and examines how itinerant filmmakers responded to industry changes to keep sponsors and audiences satisfied. From town pride films in the 1910s to Hollywood knockoffs in the 1930s, local films captured not just images of local people and places but also ideas about the function and meaning of cinema that continue to resonate today.</Abstract>
		<Author>Martin L. Johnson</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://publish.iupress.indiana.edu/projects/main-street-movies</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Main Street Movies Open Access</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>Indiana University Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Main Street Movies: The History of Local Film in the United States</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22551">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-272615-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>In Thought Crime Max M. Ward explores the Japanese state's efforts to suppress political radicalism in the 1920s and 1930s. Ward traces the evolution of an antiradical law called the Peace Preservation Law, from its initial application to suppress communism and anticolonial nationalism—what authorities deemed thought crime—to its expansion into an elaborate system to reform and ideologically convert thousands of thought criminals throughout the Japanese Empire. To enforce the law, the government enlisted a number of nonstate actors, who included monks, family members, and community leaders. Throughout, Ward illuminates the complex processes through which the law articulated imperial ideology and how this ideology was transformed and disseminated through the law's application over its twenty-year history. In so doing, he shows how the Peace Preservation Law provides a window into understanding how modern states develop ideological apparatuses to subject their respective populations.</Abstract>
		<Author>Max M. Ward</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.dukeupress.edu/thought-crime</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Thought Crime at Duke University Press</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>Duke University Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Thought Crime: Ideology and State Power</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2022</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22552">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-272617-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>In Listening for Africa David F. Garcia explores how a diverse group of musicians, dancers, academics, and activists engaged with the idea of black music and dance's African origins between the 1930s and 1950s. Garcia examines the work of figures ranging from Melville J. Herskovits, Katherine Dunham, and Asadata Dafora to Duke Ellington, Dámaso Pérez Prado, and others who believed that linking black music and dance with Africa and nature would help realize modernity's promises of freedom in the face of fascism and racism in Europe and the Americas, colonialism in Africa, and the nuclear threat at the start of the Cold War. In analyzing their work, Garcia traces how such attempts to link black music and dance to Africa unintentionally reinforced the binary relationships between the West and Africa, white and black, the modern and the primitive, science and magic, and rural and urban. It was, Garcia demonstrates, modernity's determinations of unraced, heteronormative, and productive bodies, and of scientific truth that helped defer the realization of individual and political freedom in the world.</Abstract>
		<Author>David F. Garcia</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>http://www.dukeupress.edu/listening-for-africa</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>OA e-book at the Duke University Press website.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>Duke University Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Listening for Africa: Freedom, Modernity, and the Logic of Black Music's African Origins</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2022</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22553">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-281329-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>One of the great transformations presently sweeping the Muslim world involves not just political and economic change but the reshaping of young Muslims' styles of romance, courtship, and marriage. Nancy J. Smith-Hefner takes up the personal lives and sexual attitudes of educated Muslim Javanese youth in the city of Yogyakarta to explore the dramatic social and ethical changes taking place in Indonesian society. Drawing on more than 250 interviews over a fifteen-year period, her vivid, well-crafted ethnography is full of insights into the real-life struggles of young Muslims and framed by a deep understanding of Indonesia's wider debates on gender and youth culture. The changes among Muslim youth reflect an ongoing if at times unsteady attempt to balance varied ideals, ethical concerns, and aspirations. On the one hand, growing numbers of young people show a deep and pervasive desire for a more active role in their Islamic faith. On the other, even as they seek a more self-conscious and scripture-based profession of faith, many educated youth aspire to personal relationships similar to those seen among youth elsewhere—a greater measure of informality, openness, and intimacy than was typical for their parents' and grandparents' generations. Young women in particular seek freedom for self-expression, employment, and social fulfillment outside of the home. Smith-Hefner pays particular attention to their shifting roles and perspectives because it is young women who have been most dramatically affected by the upheavals transforming this Muslim-majority country. Although deeply personal, the changing aspirations of young Muslims have immense implications for social and public life throughout Indonesia.</Abstract>
		<Author>Nancy J. Smith-Hefner</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://doi.org/10.2307/j.ctv7r43bt</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>JSTOR BOOKS - OPEN ACCESS</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University of Hawai'i Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.amazon.com/Islamizing-Intimacies-Sexuality-Contemporary-Indonesia-ebook/dp/B07HXPWGX1/ref=tmm kin swatch 0?</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Amazon Kindle - Free Access</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Islamizing Intimacies: Youth, Sexuality, and Gender in Contemporary Indonesia</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22801">
		<ApplicationNumber>RQ-271199-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>All nine published volumes of the Papers of Thomas A. Edison are now available as open-access content and downloadable as PDFs and EPUBs on Project Muse.</Abstract>
		<Author/>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://edison.rutgers.edu/research/book-edition</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>This page provides links to each volume of the Papers of Thomas A. Edison on Project Muse.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Open Access Collection</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>Johns Hopkins University Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://muse.jhu.edu/</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>This is the digital platform on which Johns Hopkins University Press has made available as open-access content the Papers of Thomas A. Edison.</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Thomas A. Edison Papers Digital Book Edition</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Edited Volume</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22923">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-285227-22</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Creating the Qur'an presents the first systematic historical-critical study of the Qur'an's origins, drawing on methods and perspectives commonly used to study other scriptural traditions. Demonstrating in detail that the Islamic tradition relates not a single attested account of the holy text's formation, Stephen J. Shoemaker shows how the Qur'an preserves a surprisingly diverse array of memories regarding the text's early history and its canonization. To this he adds perspectives from radiocarbon dating of manuscripts, the linguistic history of Arabic, the social and cultural history of late ancient Arabia, and the limitations of human memory and oral transmission, as well as various peculiarities of the Qur'anic text itself. Considering all the relevant data to present the most comprehensive and convincing examination of the origin and evolution of the Qur'an available, Shoemaker concludes that the canonical text of the Qur'an was most likely produced only around the turn of the eighth century.</Abstract>
		<Author>Stephen Shoemaker</Author>
		<Editor>Eric Schmidt</Editor>
		<ISBN>9780520389038</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://luminosoa.org/site/books/m/10.1525/luminos.128/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Link to the University of California Press’s Luminos website.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University of California Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctv2tbwqhq</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Link to JSTOR platform.</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Creating the Qur'an: A Historical-Critical Study</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3>https://www.degruyter.com/document/doi/10.1515/9780520389045/html?lang=en</URL3>
		<URL3Description>Link to De Gruyter platform.</URL3Description>
		<URL4>https://www.amazon.com/Creating-Quran-Historical-Critical-Stephen-Shoemaker-ebook/dp/B0B13YBB27/ref=tmm kin swatch 0? encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=&amp;amp;sr=</URL4>
		<URL4Description>Link to Amazon Kindle.</URL4Description>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2022</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="22967">
		<ApplicationNumber>FEL-282998-22</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Previous archeological excavations at Vulci (Etruscan then Roman city) focused heavily on aristocratic tombs, funerary art, and ritual monuments that have shown the power of elite classes and their capacity to trade with the Attic region (in Greece). By contrast, less than 5% of the ancient urban area has been excavated and no stratigraphic documentation of Vulci has been published in the last decades. The decision of the Duke University team to dig in the Southern region of the tufa (limestone) plateau (2014-2022) near the intersection between cardo and decumanus, or perpendicularly laid out thoroughfares) was determined by a preliminary GPR (ground penetrating radar) survey in the area which showed very deep deposits (over 2.5 m.) and the overlapping of several monumental structures. In particular, the last two years of excavations unveiled the presence of a large network of Etruscan and Roman water systems: wells, cisterns, channels, tunnels, pipes, pools, fountains. Additional archaeological finds, such as a large monumental complex with several rooms and key objects like Etruscan inscriptions, ritual bowls and lamps, sculptures, and raw coral, seem to corroborate the idea of pre-existing water cults in the Etruscan and Roman times. This monumental complex was built in the Imperial Roman age (1st cent.CE) but on top of Etruscan buildings. The presence of Etruscan votive objects seems to demonstrate the pre-existence of an Etruscan sanctuary dedicated to water cults because of the presence of raw coral (documented in other sanctuaries and temples along the Mediterranean). Water is an outstanding research topic in pre-Roman and Roman archaeology; in fact, the Etruscans considered water an essential factor for everyday life making it paramount in their religion. Etruscan water systems were reused and imitated by the Romans and characterized urban settings and sacred placed for the entire first millennium BCE. Duke excavations in Vulci show complex water systems, or</Abstract>
		<Author>G.Morelli, E.Biancifiori, F.Fiocchi, N.Danelon, A.Conti, E.Sartini, L.Sagripanti, A.Vivona, D.Rogers, A.LoPiano, F.Celico, R.Pinardi, A.Mercuri, A.Curci, F.Fiori</Author>
		<Editor>Maurizio Forte</Editor>
		<ISBN>n/a</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL/>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Water is an outstanding research topic in pre-Roman and Roman archaeology; in fact, the Etruscans considered water an essential factor for everyday life making it paramount in their religion. Etruscan water systems were reused and imitated by the Romans and characterized urban settings and sacred placed for the entire first millennium BCE. Duke excavations in Vulci show complex water systems, originally Etruscan, then upgraded in Roman times. The Duke research team documented for the first time in Southern Etruria a very large (about 40 cubic meters) intact cistern (stratigraphically excavated) in 3D, including all the correlated tunnels, occluded shafts, well curbstone, and feeding conduits.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>BAR-University of Michigan</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>The Vulci Waterscape (in preparation)</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Multi-author monograph, Edited Volume</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2023</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="23455">
		<ApplicationNumber>HC-279973-21</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>The name of Léonard Foujita (AKA Tsuguharu Foujita) has lost much of its luster today. However, in his heyday in Paris in the 1920s, Foujita was not only the most celebrated Japanese artist in the world, but (along with Hollywood star Sessué Hayakawa) arguably the most famous living person of Japanese ancestry.</Abstract>
		<Author>Seth Jacobowitz, Greg Robinson</Author>
		<Editor>Greg Robinson</Editor>
		<ISBN/>
		<PrimaryURL>https://discovernikkei.org/en/journal/2021/1/7/leonard-foujita-1/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Discover Nikkei is a community website about Nikkei identity, culture, and history. The goal of this project is to provide an inviting space for the community to share, explore, and connect with each other through diverse Nikkei stories, experiences, and perspectives.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Open Access Collection</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>Discovery Nikkei</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Foujita Discovers the Americas: An Artist's Tour</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Other</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="23814">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-285176-22</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>From the 1950s to the 1970s, the idea of independence inspired radical changes across the French-speaking world. In The Quebec Connection, Julie-Françoise Tolliver examines the links and parallels that writers from Quebec, the Caribbean, and Africa imagined to unite that world, illuminating the tropes they used to articulate solidarities across the race and class differences that marked their experience. Tolliver argues that the French tongue both enabled and delimited connections between these writers, restricting their potential with the language's own imperial history. The literary map that emerges demonstrates the plurality of French-language literatures, going beyond the concept of a single, unitary francophone literature to appreciate the profuse range of imaginaries connected by solidary texts that hoped for transformative independence.   Importantly, the book expands the "francophone" framework by connecting African and Caribbean literatures to Québécois literature, attending to their interactions while recognizing their particularities. The Quebec Connection's analysis of transnational francophone solidarities radically alters the field of francophone studies by redressing the racial logic that isolates the northern province from what has come to be called the postcolonial world.</Abstract>
		<Author>Julie Francoise-Tolliver</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>978-0-8139-490</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>http://https://open.upress.virginia.edu/projects/the-quebec-connection</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>University of Virginia - Virginia Open Website</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Open Access Collection</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University of Virginia Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>The Quebec Connection</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2020</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="24155">
		<ApplicationNumber>MT-284693-22</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Teaching Shakespeare through performance has a long history, and active methods of teaching and learning are a logical complement to the teaching of performance. Virtual reality ought to be the logical extension of such active learning, providing an unrivalled immersive experience of performance that overcomes historical and geographical boundaries. But what are the key advantages and disadvantages of virtual reality, especially as it pertains to Shakespeare? And more interestingly, what can Shakespeare do for VR (rather than vice versa)? This Element, the first on its topic, explores the ways that virtual reality can be used in the classroom and the ways that it might radically change how students experience and think about Shakespeare in performance.</Abstract>
		<Author>David McInnis (ed.), Stephen Wittek (ed.)</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9781009007061</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://www.cambridge.org/core/elements/abs/shakespeare-and-virtual-reality/0AB7528A5DDF43B9A700646B93BD1AE1</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Cambridge University Press website</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Open Access Collection</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>Cambridge University Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Shakespeare and Virtual Reality</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Edited Volume</Type>
		<URL3>https://www.google.com/books/edition/Shakespeare and Virtual Reality/14lZEAAAQBAJ?hl=en</URL3>
		<URL3Description>Google books</URL3Description>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="24230">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-284952-22</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A vexed figure inhabits U.S. literature and culture: the visibly racialized immigrant who disavows minority identity and embraces the American dream. Such figures are potent and controversial, for they promise to expiate racial violence and perpetuate an exceptionalist ideal of America. Swati Rana grapples with these figures, building on studies of literary character and racial form. Rana offers a new way to view characterization through racialization that creates a fuller social reading of race. Situated in a nascent period of ethnic identification from 1900 to 1960, this book focuses on immigrant writers who do not fit neatly into a resistance-based model of ethnic literature. Writings by Paule Marshall, Ameen Rihani, Dalip Singh Saund, José Garcia Villa, and José Antonio Villarreal symbolize different aspects of the American dream, from individualism to imperialism, assimilation to upward mobility. The dynamics of characterization are also those of contestation, Rana argues. Analyzing the interrelation of persona and personhood, Race Characters presents an original method of comparison, revealing how the protagonist of the American dream is socially constrained and structurally driven.</Abstract>
		<Author>Swati Rana</Author>
		<Editor>Lucas Church</Editor>
		<ISBN>9781469659480</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://uncpress.org/book/9781469659473/race-characters/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>UNC Press bookpage for Rana's Race Characters.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>The University of North Carolina Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://flexpub.com/preview/race-characters</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>OA of UNC Press's Race Characters by Swati Rana.</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Race Characters: Ethnic Literature and the Figure of the American Dream</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3>https://d1xwerhqtnbyw0.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/08141554/RANA RACE 9781469659497 web.pdf</URL3>
		<URL3Description>An OA PDF of UNC Press's Race Characters by Swati Rana.</URL3Description>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2020</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="24237">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-286803-22</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Matt Cohen's book is inspired by a disquieting moment in the freed African Olaudah Equiano's 1792 "Narrative" when on a voyage to secure labor for an English plantation he seeks to convert an Amerindian shipmate, Prince George of the Misquito, to Christanity. Finding no common ground, and in particular disputing the existence of a Christian Hell, the Prince falls silent and withdraws from the conversation -- the opportunity for cross-cultural understanding a victim of the African Equiano's zealous European piety.   "The Silence of the Miskito Prince" argues that misunderstandings and slippery definitions of cultural reciprocity and patience along with violent forms of cosmopolitanism and piety shaped cross-cultural relations in the seventeenth and early eighteenth centuries. Closely interrogating five concepts --  cosmopolitanism, piety, patience, reciprocity, and understanding -- Cohen argues that these terms haunt the very conceptual apparatus that scholars, in the last forty years of cultural historical work, have hoped would promote intercultural dialogue.   Confronting the disturbing dimensions of the common conceptual vocabulary for North American colonial studies through a series of archival explorations, "The Silence of the Miskito Prince" argues for new ways of framing scholarly conversations that take the past as a site for thinking about intercultural relations today. By investigating the colonial histories of these terms, and their use today in scholarship that wants to bring us a world beyond colonialism, Cohen offers both a reflection on how we got here and a model of scholarly humility for rethinking many other words, just as crucial as these, that hold us to our better or worse pasts.</Abstract>
		<Author>Matt Cohen</Author>
		<Editor>Douglas Armato</Editor>
		<ISBN>9781517913953</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://manifold.umn.edu/projects/the-silence-of-the-miskito-prince</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Primary site for open access to Matt Cohen's "Silence of the Miskito Prince" hosted on the University of Minnesota Press's Manifold installation.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University of Minnesota Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://muse.jhu.edu/pub/23/monograph/book/100001</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Link to Matt Cohen's "Silence of the Miskito Prince" on Project MUSE. 

We will remind Project MUSE and JSTOR to make this book open access on their platforms.</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>The Silence of the Miskito Prince: How Cultural Dialogue Was Colonized</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2022</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="24297">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-287980-22</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A decade before the American Civil War, James Churchwill Vaughan (1828–1893) set out to fulfill his formerly enslaved father's dying wish that he should leave America to start a new life in Africa. Over the next forty years, Vaughan was taken captive, fought in African wars, built and rebuilt a livelihood, and led a revolt against white racism, finally becoming a successful merchant and the founder of a wealthy, educated, and politically active family. Tracing Vaughan's journey from South Carolina to Liberia to several parts of Yorubaland (present-day southwestern Nigeria), Lisa Lindsay documents this "free" man's struggle to find economic and political autonomy in an era when freedom was not clear and unhindered anywhere for people of African descent. In a tour de force of historical investigation on two continents, Lindsay tells a story of Vaughan's survival, prosperity, and activism against a seemingly endless series of obstacles. By following Vaughan's transatlantic journeys and comparing his experiences to those of his parents, contemporaries, and descendants in Nigeria and South Carolina, Lindsay reveals the expansive reach of slavery, the ambiguities of freedom, and the surprising ways that Africa, rather than America, offered new opportunities for people of African descent.</Abstract>
		<Author>Lisa A. Lindsay</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>978-1-4696-311</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://uncpress.org/book/9781469652153/atlantic-bonds/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Bookpage for Atlantic Bonds on the UNC Press website.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>The University of North Carolina Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>OA Version of Atlantic Bonds: A Nineteenth-Century Odyssey from America to Africa</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3>https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.5149/9781469631134 lindsay</URL3>
		<URL3Description>OA version of Atlantic Bonds on JSTOR</URL3Description>
		<URL4>https://www.amazon.com/Atlantic-Bonds-Nineteenth-Century-Odyssey-America-ebook/dp/B01N7KXX4V/ref=sr 1 1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1483453815&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=atlantic+bonds</URL4>
		<URL4Description>OA version of Atlantic Bonds on Amazon Kindle</URL4Description>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2017</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="24298">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-287981-22</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Jamestown, the Lost Colony of Roanoke, and Plymouth Rock are central to America's mythic origin stories. Then, we are told, the main characters--the "friendly" Native Americans who met the settlers--disappeared. But the history of the Lumbee Tribe of North Carolina demands that we tell a different story. As the largest tribe east of the Mississippi and one of the largest in the country, the Lumbees have survived in their original homelands, maintaining a distinct identity as Indians in a biracial South. In this passionately written, sweeping work of history, Malinda Maynor Lowery narrates the Lumbees' extraordinary story as never before. The Lumbees' journey as a people sheds new light on America's defining moments, from the first encounters with Europeans to the present day. How and why did the Lumbees both fight to establish the United States and resist the encroachments of its government? How have they not just survived, but thrived, through Civil War, Jim Crow, the civil rights movement, and the war on drugs, to ultimately establish their own constitutional government in the twenty-first century? Their fight for full federal acknowledgment continues to this day, while the Lumbee people's struggle for justice and self-determination continues to transform our view of the American experience. Readers of this book will never see Native American history the same way.</Abstract>
		<Author>Malinda Maynor Lowery</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>978-1-4696-463</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://worldcat.org/title/1120116102</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Lumbee Indians on worldcat.org website</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>The University of North Carolina Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.5149/9781469646398 lowery</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>Lumbee Indians on JSTOR</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>The Lumbee Indians: An American Struggle</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3>https://www.amazon.com/Lumbee-Indians-American-Struggle-ebook/dp/B07BB5GWWF/ref=sr 1 2?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1533214918&amp;amp;sr=1-2&amp;amp;keywords=malinda+s+lowery</URL3>
		<URL3Description>Lumbee Indians on Amazon Kindle</URL3Description>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="24299">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-287982-22</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>During the Great Depression, the American South was not merely "the nation's number one economic problem," as President Franklin Roosevelt declared. It was also a battlefield on which forces for and against social change were starting to form. For a white southern liberal like Jonathan Daniels, editor of the Raleigh News and Observer, it was a fascinating moment to explore. Attuned to culture as well as politics, Daniels knew the true South lay somewhere between Erskine Caldwell's Tobacco Road and Margaret Mitchell's Gone with the Wind. On May 5, 1937, he set out to find it, driving thousands of miles in his trusty Plymouth and ultimately interviewing even Mitchell herself. In Discovering the South historian Jennifer Ritterhouse pieces together Daniels's unpublished notes from his tour along with his published writings and a wealth of archival evidence to put this one man's journey through a South in transition into a larger context. Daniels's well chosen itinerary brought him face to face with the full range of political and cultural possibilities in the South of the 1930s, from New Deal liberalism and social planning in the Tennessee Valley Authority, to Communist agitation in the Scottsboro case, to planters' and industrialists' reactionary worldview and repressive violence. The result is a lively narrative of black and white southerners fighting for and against democratic social change at the start of the nation's long civil rights era.</Abstract>
		<Author>Jennifer Ritterhouse</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>978-1-4696-309</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://worldcat.org/title/1175636533</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Discovering the South on the worldcat.org website.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>The University of North Carolina Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.5149/9781469630953 ritterhouse</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>OA Version of Discovering the South on JSTOR</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Discovering the South: One Man's Travels through a Changing America in the 1930s</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3>https://www.amazon.com/Discovering-South-Travels-through-Changing-ebook/dp/B01MZIYSP0/ref=sr 1 1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1487086073&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=discovering+the+south</URL3>
		<URL3Description>OA version of Discovering the South on Amazon Kindle</URL3Description>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2017</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="24300">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-287983-22</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>When Latino migration to the U.S. South became increasingly visible in the 1990s, observers and advocates grasped for ways to analyze "new" racial dramas in the absence of historical reference points. However, as this book is the first to comprehensively document, Mexicans and Mexican Americans have a long history of migration to the U.S. South. Corazón de Dixie recounts the untold histories of Mexicanos' migrations to New Orleans, Mississippi, Arkansas, Georgia, and North Carolina as far back as 1910. It follows Mexicanos into the heart of Dixie, where they navigated the Jim Crow system, cultivated community in the cotton fields, purposefully appealed for help to the Mexican government, shaped the southern conservative imagination in the wake of the civil rights movement, and embraced their own version of suburban living at the turn of the twenty-first century. Rooted in U.S. and Mexican archival research, oral history interviews, and family photographs, Corazón de Dixie unearths not just the facts of Mexicanos' long-standing presence in the U.S. South but also their own expectations, strategies, and dreams.</Abstract>
		<Author>Julie M. Weise</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>978-1-4696-249</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://worldcat.org/title/1086535411</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Corazón de Dixie on worldcat.org website.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>The University of North Carolina Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.5149/9781469624976 weise</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>OA version of Corazón de Dixie on JSTOR</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Corazón de Dixie: Mexicanos in the U.S. South since 1910</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3>https://www.amazon.com/Coraz%C3%B3n-Dixie-Mexicanos-Borderlands-History-ebook/dp/B00W1VH8Q0/ref=sr 1 1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1443723371&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=corazon+de+dixie</URL3>
		<URL3Description>OA version of Corazón de Dixie on Amazon Kindle</URL3Description>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2015</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="24301">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-290430-23</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Nellie Y. McKay (1930–2006) was a pivotal figure in contemporary American letters. The author of several books, McKay is best known for coediting the canon-making Norton Anthology of African American Literature with Henry Louis Gates Jr., which helped secure a place for the scholarly study of Black writing that had been ignored by white academia. However, there is more to McKay's life and legacy than her literary scholarship. After her passing, new details about McKay's life emerged, surprising everyone who knew her. Why did McKay choose to hide so many details of her past? Shanna Greene Benjamin examines McKay's path through the professoriate to learn about the strategies, sacrifices, and successes of contemporary Black women in the American academy. Benjamin shows that McKay's secrecy was a necessary tactic that a Black, working-class woman had to employ to succeed in the white-dominated space of the American English department. Using extensive archives and personal correspondence, Benjamin brings together McKay's private life and public work to expand how we think about Black literary history and the place of Black women in American culture.</Abstract>
		<Author>Shanna Greene Benjamin</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9781469661896</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://worldcat.org/title/1242875653</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Half in Shadow on worldcat.org website.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>The University of North Carolina Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://d1xwerhqtnbyw0.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/06193351/Benjamin Half 9781469661896 web.pdf</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>OA version of Half in Shadow as PDF</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Half in Shadow: The Life and Legacy of Nellie Y. McKay</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3>https://www.amazon.com/Half-Shadow-Legacy-Nellie-McKay-ebook/dp/B08HGJ6CH9/ref=sr 1 1?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=9781469661896&amp;amp;qid=1617738431&amp;amp;s=digital-text&amp;amp;sr=1-1</URL3>
		<URL3Description>OA version of Half in Shadow on Amazon Kindle</URL3Description>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="24302">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-290431-23</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Eve E. Buckley's study of twentieth-century Brazil examines the nation's hard social realities through the history of science, focusing on the use of technology and engineering as vexed instruments of reform and economic development. Nowhere was the tension between technocratic optimism and entrenched inequality more evident than in the drought-ridden Northeast sertão, plagued by chronic poverty, recurrent famine, and mass migrations. Buckley reveals how the physicians, engineers, agronomists, and mid-level technocrats working for federal agencies to combat drought were pressured by politicians to seek out a technological magic bullet that would both end poverty and obviate the need for land redistribution to redress long-standing injustices. Scientists planned and oversaw huge projects including dam construction, irrigation for small farmers, and public health initiatives. They were, Buckley shows, sincerely determined to solve the drought crisis and improve the lot of poor people in the sertão. Over time, however, they came to the frustrating realization that, despite technology's tantalizing promise of an apolitical means to end poverty, political collisions among competing stakeholders were inevitable. Buckley's revelations about technocratic hubris, the unexpected consequences of environmental engineering, and constraints on scientists as agents of social change resonate with today's hopes that science and technology can solve society's most pressing dilemmas, including climate change.</Abstract>
		<Author>Eve E. Buckley</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9781469634319</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://worldcat.org/title/1032363615</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Technocrats and the Politics of Drought and Development in Twentieth-Century Brazil on the worldcat.org website.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>The University of North Carolina Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.5149/9781469634319 buckley</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>OA version of Technocrats and the Politics of Drought and Development in Twentieth-Century Brazil on JSTOR</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Technocrats and the Politics of Drought and Development in Twentieth-Century Brazil</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3>https://www.amazon.com/Technocrats-Politics-Drought-Development-Twentieth-Century-ebook/dp/B06Y3TMGCP/ref=sr 1 1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1501614531&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=technocrats</URL3>
		<URL3Description>OA version of Technocrats and the Politics of Drought and Development in Twentieth-Century Brazil on Amazon Kindle</URL3Description>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2017</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="24303">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-290429-23</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This groundbreaking history of African Americans and golf explores the role of race, class, and public space in golf course development, the stories of individual black golfers during the age of segregation, the legal battle to integrate public golf courses, and the little-known history of the United Golfers Association (UGA)--a black golf tour that operated from 1925 to 1975. Lane Demas charts how African Americans nationwide organized social campaigns, filed lawsuits, and went to jail in order to desegregate courses; he also provides dramatic stories of golfers who boldly confronted wider segregation more broadly in their local communities. As national civil rights organizations debated golf's symbolism and whether or not to pursue the game's integration, black players and caddies took matters into their own hands and helped shape its subculture, while UGA participants forged one of the most durable black sporting organizations in American history as they fought to join the white Professional Golfers' Association (PGA). From George F. Grant's invention of the golf tee in 1899 to the dominance of superstar Tiger Woods in the 1990s, this revelatory and comprehensive work challenges stereotypes and indeed the fundamental story of race and golf in American culture.</Abstract>
		<Author>Lane Demas</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9781469634234</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://worldcat.org/title/1032362788</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Game of Privilege: An African American History of Golf on worldcat.org website.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>The University of North Carolina Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.5149/9781469634234 demas</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>OA version of Game of Privilege: An African American History of Golf on JSTOR</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Game of Privilege: An African American History of Golf</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3>https://www.amazon.com/Game-Privilege-African-American-Franklin-ebook/dp/B06Y3PTXGN/ref=sr 1 1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1502382294&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=game+of+privilege</URL3>
		<URL3Description>OA version of Game of Privilege: An African American History of Golf on Amazon Kindle</URL3Description>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2017</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="24304">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-290432-23</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>This social and cultural history of Civil War medicine and science sheds important light on the question of why and how anti-Black racism survived the destruction of slavery. During the war, white Northerners promoted ideas about Black inferiority under the guise of medical and scientific authority. In particular, the Sanitary Commission and Army medical personnel conducted wartime research aimed at proving Black medical and biological inferiority. They not only subjected Black soldiers and refugees from slavery to substandard health care but also scrutinized them as objects of study. This mistreatment of Black soldiers and civilians extended after life to include dissection, dismemberment, and disposal of the Black war dead in unmarked or mass graves and medical waste pits. Simultaneously, white medical and scientific investigators enhanced their professional standing by establishing their authority on the science of racial difference and hierarchy.    Drawing on archives of the U.S. Sanitary Commission, recollections of Civil War soldiers and medical workers, and testimonies from Black Americans, Leslie A. Schwalm exposes the racist ideas and practices that shaped wartime medicine and science. Painstakingly researched and accessibly written, this book helps readers understand the persistence of anti-Black racism and health disparities during and after the war.</Abstract>
		<Author>Leslie A. Schwalm</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>9781469672700</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://worldcat.org/title/1370495075</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Medicine, Science, and Making Race in Civil War America on worldcat.org website.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>The University of North Carolina Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.5149/9781469672717 schwalm</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>OA version of Medicine, Science, and Making Race in Civil War America on JSTOR</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>Medicine, Science, and Making Race in Civil War America</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3>https://www.amazon.com/Medicine-Science-Making-Civil-America-ebook/dp/B0BFGDBSPL/ref=sr 1 1?crid=T5TIJ48L43ML&amp;amp;keywords=9781469672700&amp;amp;qid=1676477243&amp;amp;s=digital-text&amp;amp;sprefix=9781469672700%2Cdigital-text%2C72&amp;amp;sr=1-1</URL3>
		<URL3Description>OA version of Medicine, Science, and Making Race in Civil War America on Amazon Kindle</URL3Description>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2023</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="24464">
		<ApplicationNumber>DR-286799-22</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>Provincializing Empire explores the global history of Japanese expansion through a regional lens. It rethinks the nation-centered geography and chronology of empire by uncovering the pivotal role of expeditionary merchants from Omi (present-day Shiga Prefecture) and their modern successors. Tracing their lives from the early modern era, and writing them into the global histories of empire, diaspora, and capitalism, Jun Uchida offers an innovative analysis of expansion through a story previously untold: how the nation's provincials built on their traditions to create a transpacific diaspora that stretched from Seoul to Vancouver, while helping shape the modern world of transoceanic exchange.</Abstract>
		<Author>Jun Uchida</Author>
		<Editor/>
		<ISBN>978-0-520-3901</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>https://luminosoa.org/site/books/m/10.1525/luminos.144/</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>This URL is the University of California Press Luminos Open Access website listing for Provincializing Empire by Jun Uchida.</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Single Publication</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>University of California Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL/>
		<SecondaryURLDescription/>
		<Title>Provincializing Empire</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Single author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2023</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
	<OpenAccessItem ID="24471">
		<ApplicationNumber>SP-271395-20</ApplicationNumber>
		<Abstract>A simplified analysis and contextualization of the Revised Organic Act of 1954 as amended. The 1954 Revised Organic Act (amended) serves as the effective constitution of the United States Virgin Islands (U.S.V.I.). Despite its importance in the political life of the Territory, it has not previously been available in a format that integrates the original document with the important changes (amendments) made to it. This version is written in plain English which enables the average person to understand it and provides an overview of the historical and political context which explains why the islands are organized by a law passed by the U.S. Congress rather than a locally drafted and approved framework of government. This document expands public awareness of the Revised Organic Act and its importance, and provides access to the territory's schools, libraries, civic organizations and/or institutions.</Abstract>
		<Author>Paul Leary, Ph.D., Malík Sékou, Ph.D.</Author>
		<Editor>Linda Smith, Ph.D.</Editor>
		<ISBN>978-1-7376533-</ISBN>
		<PrimaryURL>http://sway.office.com/7Ac6pr7E4Fy9Mki3?ref=Link</PrimaryURL>
		<PrimaryURLDescription>Electronic book</PrimaryURLDescription>
		<PublicationType>Open Access Collection</PublicationType>
		<Publisher>The Caribbean Writer Press</Publisher>
		<SecondaryURL>http://www.uvi.edu/academics/lib-arts-and-sciences/research-and-outreach/osdcd.html</SecondaryURL>
		<SecondaryURLDescription>University of the Virgin Islands Office of Self Determination and Constitutional Development</SecondaryURLDescription>
		<Title>(Simplified) Revised Organic Act of the Virgin Islands 1954</Title>
		<Translator/>
		<Type>Multi-author monograph</Type>
		<URL3/>
		<URL3Description/>
		<URL4/>
		<URL4Description/>
		<URL5/>
		<URL5Description/>
		<Year>2021</Year>
	</OpenAccessItem>
</OpenAccessItems>
